(audience chattering)
- Let's get started.
Every day, people are on the move,
whether jet sitting across the continents,
or raising through the ranks,
or savoring their
unforgettable experiences,
but out of all this,
every financial institutions
have one common mission.
That is to ensure that
your funds flow in the right directions,
slowly, safely and smoothly,
and ensure that every single
transaction checks out,
stays compliant and
keeps us all protected.
Because the world moves so fast
that the right flow of fund
and the airtight compliance is crucial.
This lets us run without a glitch.
This is Bhuvaneswari Subramani here,
Chief Evangelist at Intuitive.ai,
AWS Hero and AWS Ambassador
joining hands with two amazing
machine learning heroes,
Ayyanar Jeyakrishnan and Vivek Raja PS
from AWS India community,
joining here to talk
about AWS Strands power.
That is we are gonna
talk about the use case,
anti-money laundering,
multi-agent orchestration
with AWS Strands and this will prepare you
to help the financial institutions
maintain compliance with confidence.
That's what we are gonna see today.
So we'll be focusing on the global impact
of anti-money laundering
and the evolving compliance.
We are gonna see how
the Agentic AI workflow
implemented using AWS Strands
is going to solve this problem
against the financial crime.
And we will also take you
through the demo in detail
with a real life solution.
So, financial crime is a global crisis.
Around 3.1 trillion illicit
funds (audience applauds)
flowed in 2023 and the
similar pattern got repeated
in 2024 as well.
Where are these funds coming from?
Majority of these things,
majority of the causes
are from drug trafficking,
human trafficking,
terrorism, and fraud.
So all of these things constitutes
towards millions of dollars loss.
It's a huge financial impact, right?
So much of these things goes undetected.
That's why we say that
anti-money laundering
is very, very crucial.
So financial organizations like FinCEN
have started working on
regulations for a quite long time
and no one can solve this alone.
That's why we are here to talk about
how Agentic AI solutions
powered by Strands SDK
is gonna help fight against this.
And when we are talking about this,
if we go on little bit of history,
I'm not a much of a
history person, but still,
let's take a quick step back and see
how the AML standards have evolved.
It started with the
Bank Secrecy Act in 1970
followed by creation of FATF
which had 40 specific
standards as a recommendations
that the institutions have to follow.
And 1992 was the year
where Suspicious Activity
Report came into existence.
That is, if there is any deviation
in the financial transaction,
the financial organization has to
file the Suspicious Activity Report.
It could be a real legitimate risk
or it could be a potential risk,
but it's the duty of the
financial institution
to file the Suspicious Activity Report
and also it continue to evolve.
In 2020 is what we had this
anti-money laundering act
that came into picture.
So this is the history of
how these things evolved
and each milestone have only increased
the responsibility and vigilance
for the financial institutions,
how we can fight against
this financial crime.
So why are we talking about
all these things, right?
So we have to deal with
diverse set of data
when we are talking about
anti-money laundering.
So in today's enterprise world,
we operate a mix of legacy applications
combined with modern technologies.
So justice, goods and capitals flow freely
across the borders.
It is the responsibility of
the financial institutions
to ensure that the money
flows the right way
without a glitch.
That is very, very essential, right?
So here the organizations,
the financial institutions
deal with diverse data.
It could be your financial
transactions, customer profiles
or it could be the KYC
data, even newsfeeds, right?
There could be some newsfeeds,
there was some issue they raised
or standards that got published.
So they love to keep track
of all of these diverse data
and you have the high volume
data, high velocity of data
coming from different data sets,
all of these things have to
be taken through our system.
That system is like a legacy
traditional rule-based system.
This rule-based system
actually had too many false alarms.
These are a false positive up to 95%.
For example, if there is an enterprise
which has the business sending alerts
about the legitimate transactions,
maybe report anything about 10,000 USD,
if it's going to report about 10,000 USD,
there could be hundreds
of legitimate transactions
happening in that month.
If it ends up prompting
and reporting for all that
and later the compliance personnel,
the human was to sit and review this,
it takes a lot of time, lot of energy,
waste of resources costing
all of that, right?
So, this slows down the
real threat detection.
So what do we need?
We need real context aware methods
which can cut down the false
alarms, increase the focus,
and then helps us to detect
the real risk quickly
at a lower cost.
That is what we need.
Before we get into the actual solution
and agentic AI implementation,
I wanna talk a little
bit about the technology
that is powering the implementation.
So let me say something.
All of us might have used
talking to either Siri
or your Alexa, a bank chatbot,
something or the other,
even in the middle of night.
Many times we would've felt
that it is far more better
and easier to talk to these
bots than your close friend
or even your spouse for the matter, right?
So I see a lot of smiles.
So this is a fact.
So when you have a bot which
is so powerful in responding,
let's see, what is the
tech powering the bots?
Imagine you have an agent
which is so powerful implemented for this.
So what is this agent basically built out?
We also had lot of things
that Dr. Swami covered
as part of our morning Agentic
AI keynote about the agents
and the latest launches.
So when you talk about an agent in simple,
you have a prompt which
is sent to the agent,
that is the question
that you wanted to ask.
Maybe you have diverse
set of data coming in,
you're defining an agent which
is going to take your data,
process it.
So when the prompt is sent to the agent,
the agent is capable of invoking any tool.
It could be the code interpreter
or it could talk to
your database, anything.
It could invoke your tool.
The tool will process the information
and return the data through the agent.
And the agent is also
capable of invoking the LLMs,
it could be Ollama, GPT, anything.
So this again fetches the
results back to the agent.
So both the results are
available in the agent
and the agent is going to
process that and create
or curate a human readable content
and it's gonna pass it on to the user
or the application from where
this agent is being invoked.
So that's the agent in nutshell.
So when we say agent, what
is the difference between
agentic AI and agentic AI workflow?
Because the solution that
we are going to implement
for this is agentic AI workflow, right?
So the agentic AI, it's
basically autonomous entity
which makes decisions and
act upon those additions
to accomplish a goal with
minimal human intervention.
And when you talk about
agentic AI workflow,
it's the coordinated sequence
where the multiple
agents are orchestrating
to accomplish a complex goal
to solve the biggest
problem that you have.
So this is what we talk about agentic AI
and agentic AI workflow.
And when do we use agentic AI workflow?
Just because everywhere
we talk about agents,
not necessary that we have
to use only agentic AI
to every damn problem that we see.
There are advantages in using traditional
as well as agentic AI.
So that's what I wanted
to talk about in this.
So when you take about agentic AI,
when you wanna deal
with complex workflows,
when you have a diverse data set
or when you wanted to have a
memory that is to be retained
after the conversations that
is happening from start to end,
so in all these cases you will
go for Agentic AI workflow.
When we talk about the
tools that is powering this,
you will understand
and relate this better.
But for now, so for all these scenarios,
we'll go for Agentic AI workflow.
And for the traditional,
when you have the mission
critical applications
where the results has to
be 100% deterministic,
we would go for this traditional workflow.
And when you have a system
which needs ultra low latency,
you need this.
And if it is a fixed rule-based system
which can actually derive
better results with that
than traditional solution is better.
Okay, so now when we
talk about these things,
what are the technology that
is powering these solutions?
So we are gonna talk about AWS Strands SDK
and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore
which has powered these things.
So when you say Strands SDK,
it's the open source framework
from Amazon with which
without worrying too much
about the infrastructure
or writing thousands and
thousands of lines of code
with just few lines,
anybody should be able to create an agent.
If you had watched the keynote today,
so Swami gave an amazing number,
there are already over 5 million downloads
for this Strands SDK.
People are really using
like day in and day out.
Anybody talking about agents
are building agents with Strands SDK.
It's becoming so, so powerful.
So that's what we have used
as well to create our agents.
It can actually natively integrate
with any of the AWS services
and it can connect to native
tools, any MCP servers,
whether you have created or it's external.
iI works seamlessly, it
can work with any model.
That is the power of Strands SDK.
And so when you have one agent,
you create it for one task,
it's all good, right?
Imagine you have a stream
of agent interconnected
to actually think, act
and remember all at once
at a massive scale.
That's when we need service
like Bedrock AgentCore
to take care all of this completely.
So you build agent with Strands SDK
or you can build agents with
any framework for the matter.
It could be from Llama,
LlamaIndex, LangChain, LangGraph
CrewAI or Google.
So you build with anything.
You can use Amazon Bedrock
AgentCore to deploy,
that is so, so powerful.
It is not just a single service.
It's a composite suite of services
which helps you address
whole lot of logistics
that is involved in deploying an agent
at a production scale.
You imagine an agent when
you wanted to deploy,
you don't have to deal
with infrastructure,
that's where runtime comes into picture.
And when you're deploying it,
you have to ensure that the conversation
between the agents are secured, seamless
and nothing gets leaked beyond
the conversation context.
So in this case, the identity
management comes into picture.
So when your agent wanted to interact with
other tools and other stuff,
Bedrock AgentCore gateway is there.
And when you wanted to
audit, debug and report,
that's where AgentCore
observability is there.
And so when you want these information
across the conversations and
chats has to be remembered,
refer for insights,
that's when AgentCore
memory comes into picture.
All of these components
holistically work together
to help you deploy agent
run at a production scale.
But otherwise, if you see,
I have a friend who was actually saying
when you do a lot of POCs,
agentic AI solutions,
most of the POCs end by like death by POC.
That's a term, it was
used by one of my friend.
So everybody starts
with agentic AI, right?
Where it suffers, where it struggles is,
but for taking it to
production has been struggles.
That's where AgentCore is
here to rescue and take care.
Let's drill down and look
into three major components.
We can talk about AgentCore
for hours together,
but I want to drill down
and talk about three
important components here
which we are gonna extensively use
for the workflow that we have designed.
So you take AgentCore runtime,
it is the completely
managed serverless service
but it's not like a
traditional serverless service.
We are just invoking a function,
returning a result and going to use it.
This AgentCore runtime is a micro VM.
Whenever you are hosting an
agent, deploying an agent,
this micro VM is started and
this micro VM is available
and runs for the maximum up to eight hours
to serve the functionality of the agent
to the invoked application.
So that is how the micro VM is available,
which is unlike the traditional system.
And using this you can actually
deploy the agents created
from any framework as I mentioned earlier.
It could be from your
LangChain, LangGraph,
LlamaIndex, or CrewAI.
Irrespective of that
you'll be able to build,
all that you needed is
when you invoke this AgentCore runtime,
it creates the docker composed file
and it deploys it to the ECS repository.
Once it is, the image is made available
in the ECR repository, it can be invoked
and deployed into the runtime.
Once it is deployed, you have
an endpoint made available
which can be used to
integrate with the application
to serve your customer request.
So that's how this AgentCore
runtime works in a nutshell.
And when we talk about
the AgentCore gateway,
so you are creating one agent.
This agent cannot work alone.
It need to interact with
multiple agent, right?
So when you wanted this agent to interact
with multiple agent, for an example,
we spoke about diverse data.
When the diverse data
coming in, we have an agent
which is going to read the data
and see whether some data is
actually false positive or not.
So you need an agent.
So this agent should also
go and check the KYC data
or the last seven days data
to see was there any risk.
So when it has to do all of these things,
it has to interact with different tools.
One agent cannot do everything, right?
It needs to have multiple
agents or multiple tools.
So, you can use AgentCore gateway
to connect to the API gateway
and the API gateway in turn
connect to different tools
within AWS services, it can invoke
and it processes and returns
the information that is needed.
We can also make this AgentCore gateway
connect to your lambda function,
which is gonna again
process a set of tools
and return the results.
It can talk to another set of MCP tools.
So the inbound authentication stops
at this AgentCore gateway
and the AgentCore gateway
takes care of the rest of the
interactions with the tools,
MCP tools or the AWS services
like API endpoint or Lambda
and the return results.
So that's how AgentCore gateway works.
And the next one important thing is,
okay, you have a runtime you have hosted,
you have a gateway which
can help you interact,
all is fine but we need memory.
Whatever conversation that happens,
whatever the processing that happens,
all that has to be recorded, stored,
for using it now, at least
during the process or later.
So for that the AgentCore
memory has an amazing feature.
Let's talk about two things.
Short term memory and
long-term memory, how it works.
So when you take an agent, there
is an agent implementation.
When the agent is implemented,
there will be a sequence
of event happenings.
When the sequence of events are happening,
there are messages which gets exchanged
and the state that needs to be stored.
So these messages and states
will be stored in a memory
called short-term memory.
And this short term memory
can be made available
or stored maximum up to 365 days.
Don't ask why 365 days, it's a number,
it's nice to say one year, right?
So it is configurable,
you can say whether I
need it for like one month
or 365 days, but the maximum is 365 days
for short term memory.
And in case of long term memory,
you have a module called
automatic memory extraction module
which processes these data
which gets stored in short-term
memory asynchronously
and extracts insights, summary information
or the semantic data,
all of that and stores
in the long term memory.
On the other hand, the agentic
implementation that has,
whenever it needs any
of these information,
could be user preferences
or the insights that
you wanted to process,
you can actually go ahead
and invoke this information
and then use it asynchronously.
So that's how short term
and long-term memory
is super beneficial
for the agentic AI
workflow implementation.
So we saw what is the global
impact of anti-money laundering
and we went through the diverse
set of data that we have,
how the false alarms gets raised,
how the compliance have been evolving
and we also spoke about the tech
that is powering this agentic AI solution.
And our agentic AI workflow is implemented
using strands SDK and
Amazon Agent Bedrock Core.
So with this insights I
would call upon my co-speaker
Ayyanar Jeyakrishnan, AJ
to continue from here.
Thank you so much.
- Thanks Bhuvana. Okay.
So we all love Strands
which is really flexible
and we also allow the
AgentCore is very modular
and we can deploy at a scale.
And let's dive into the solution,
how are we solving the
anti-money laundering
leveraging the agentic workflow.
So these are the agents we lined up
act as an individual persona,
each one has a different role
to play in this workflow.
Let's start with the first
agent, Perception Agent.
This naming convention speaks for it.
When the transaction
comes, it'll understand
what is this transaction, add
additional perception to it,
then it'll connect to the
different data source.
Based on your requirement,
based on your enterprise,
it'll connect to the different data source
and add to the context agent
and the data source can be varied
but the context you need
to have a streamline,
the information before sending
to any kind of reasoning agent.
So the context, whatever we are telling,
it's all between the enterprise, okay?
But when come to the enterprise,
the real time data matters a lot.
That's where we are going
to add the news agent
into the mixture
which will connect to
the real time data source
and add to the reasoning agent.
This is where the real powerful comes.
The reasoning agent will leverage
both the unstructured data
as well as it user existing context
retrieved from your enterprise
and make a reasoning and
forward to the risk agent.
The risk agent make a decision,
it can connect to your enterprise
existing risk AML models
as well as based on all the context
we have retrieved from you this workflow,
it also give a context and make a risk.
Then, Action Agent comes.
So all good currently whatever
the actions we are making,
it's all highly manual.
This action agent take out
those major chunk of this action
and automate it,
like it can do the
straight through processing
if it all goes good.
And after that all the workflows are fine.
When come to any financial institution
or any enterprise we are building it,
application we are building it,
the audit play a pivotal role.
And when come to the audit,
all the agent make a decision
and we want to make sure every
information will be triaged
and logged.
So, if anybody want to
go and make a decision
why the risk score was different,
we have all the information
from multiple agent went
through, we have an audit.
Then learning agent, this is
one of the my favorite agent.
We need to keep the system more autonomous
because we want to, whatever we observe,
we want to add to the
system as a feedback loop.
So it'll be evolved
over the period of time,
then we need to create a final report.
So if you find it suspicious,
you need to create the
Suspicious Activity Report.
We will create a report leveraging LLM.
This is a high level, we
orchestrated the workflow,
it's completely modular.
We can fix, we can plug
into our enterprise need
with a different agent.
I want a little bit zoomed
down on the risk agent,
which is very important.
Okay.
Based on the risk agent, the
action agent will be invoked.
Okay, if the score is less
than 30, okay, perfect,
we can do the straight through processing.
The agent can do their
straight through processing.
Then if there is the score
is on 30 or between 50,
this will vary.
We can make sure we
are notifying it, okay,
and if it find it's a repeated pattern,
we need to mandatorily file the report.
The report will be created
using LLM and we also make sure
this transaction is monitored and flagged.
But if we feel the score is high,
currently whatever the
action we are making,
sometimes most of the time
we do the false positive
but with this kind of
approach we will be able to
take a freeze that and make a next action.
This is how the overall
system we have orchestrated.
Let me come into the
technical deep dive off
how we lined up this agent,
how we use the Strands
and made it (indistinct)
We made it as a layered
approach based on the use case.
We all started with a major
chunk of use case in the AML,
the transaction monitoring
and post created this workflow
end-to-end and made it work.
We made plugged into the additional layer
which we added a more context
by adding the real time
information like news, OFAC,
all those information.
Now we have created a context,
we have created a end-to-end workflow.
We want to make it more autonomous.
That's where the third layer comes.
We have made it, added the learning agent
and we added a more audit
into the picture, okay.
So this is how step by step
we have built the agents.
Let me dive into the
transaction monitoring
and spend some time on it.
The real time data we are
processing using a Kinesis.
Once we have our real time data,
based on that transaction information,
we will connect to the
existing data source.
It can be your CRM or think
like we have our everything
in our RDS or our relational database.
It'll go connect to it to get those KYC
and the perception agent based on that
it'll create a triage of how
this transaction looks like.
We are using Bedrock
for different kind of model for
different different purpose.
Now let me come to the next
one, the context agent.
With all the information we collected,
we created the context agent.
But the context agent
had a very critical thing
about the historical data.
The historical data
currently we are keeping all
the information at DynamoDB
for the faster retrieval and
we build a flurry of tools.
Take a last in transaction,
the so and so data and
transaction is recently flagged.
We created multiple tools
using a Lambda function
and we kept AgentCore
gateway as a front end
and we connect from the context agent
to those lambda function to
retrieve the data via gateway.
So we no need to change the architecture.
If you have an additional requirement
to connect to the data, all you need to do
is build an additional tool
and it'll be more flexible.
Based on your requirement, we can add it.
Now we have created a context agent
and connect it to the historical data
with the real time data, good.
Now we are adding to the reasoning agent.
All the contacts will be
sent to the reasoning agent.
It used the reasoning model
to make a complete understanding.
It created a risk score by itself
based on the how we
prompted and orchestrated
with all the context, we
got it from perception agent
as well as the context agent.
Once we have the complete
details from the context agent
and the reasoning agent we are
taking into the action agent.
We created a tools here also.
We can build the multiple tools
based on your requirement.
At least for the transaction monitoring,
the notification is very important.
We created a tool for a notification
and also we want to make
sure if it is high risk,
we want to flag the transaction.
So we have created the tool
based on the information,
we got it from the context,
we got it from the reasoning agent.
We will be able to make action.
And if we find it,
yes, this is a transaction
which we want to create
the Suspicious Action Report.
Currently in industry everything
need to be done manually
and whatever the
transaction they have seen,
they have to create a manual report.
With the proper prompt template structure,
we will be able to pre-fill this one
and store it into the S3.
As I mentioned clearly, auditing
is a very important task
if you want to make a decision.
That's where the audit agent
will come into the picture.
All the context we've
taken from the perception
to all the layers and
whatever the action we take,
we audit everything and
keep it in elastic search.
So think like it.
If they found there is a
suspicious in the transaction,
it automatically created a report.
If the human in the loop,
they can check the report
at the same time how we made a decision,
everything will be in elastic search.
So that is how we orchestrated this flow
for the transaction monitoring.
The next layer what we build
is the adverse media monitoring
where we want to add the
real time information
of the news, okay?
We added a news, we created a new agent
which is a News Herald agent.
So that is how we model...
We make it very flexible
so we can keep adding our
agent based on our use case,
with the power of Strands and AgentCore.
We added the News Herald agent
and whatever the information it is getting
it added to the memory.
Why memory?
Imagine if there is a
new transaction coming
and the same person is doing it.
We want to make a quick action.
So yesterday there is a news
comes and we may be flagged
and if there is a change in news,
it'll have both the context
that is a negative news,
there is a positive news,
this is a recent information,
we can make a decision accordingly.
Currently whatever we are doing
is we are doing it manually
but with the AgentCore memory,
this will add a context in a real time
what we are fetching from the
news agent to make a decision.
All this will be fed
into the context agent.
If you look at before,
this will add your batch,
your previous internal
information to the context
in a transaction monitoring.
Here we are adding a real time
information to the context.
So news is one factor
but when we come to the
anti-money laundering,
it's very vast.
Country to country, it'll be vary.
The data source which the each country
or the whatever the act
they have will keep vary.
Take an example of OFAC, Office
of Foreign Asset Control,
which publish the report very frequently.
It has all the information if
any political exposed person,
something of the sanctions are happening.
Every information will be here.
This, I'm taking an example.
So based on your requirement
we can add to that particular data source.
We use the Lambda which will
periodically retrieve the data
and of course we are using a
Bedrock to do the embedding
and write it to our knowledge base.
Why knowledge base?
The News Herald agent,
whichever we built it,
it have both the context of
the real-time information
which we fetch from the news
as well as according
to your country or act,
it'll have this information
in a Bedrock knowledge base.
Both information will be
fed into the context agent.
Okay.
So post to the second...
This is the final layer we have built.
It's all more about instant
risk interdiction, okay?
The reason why we want
to do this banner is
currently mostly we are
doing in a reactive fashion.
Now as I'm saying it's
not a hundred percentage
we will be able to proactively do it
but we can make a quick correction
and avoid more false
positive in this approach.
Here we added two more agent.
One is on the risk assessor agent.
What this risk assessor
agent will do, right?
So it'll integrate to your class,
internally currently whatever
the way we are doing, right?
We may be using a classic model,
it can be your classification model
or it can be your clustering model
like classic ML model you have.
That is how we are flagging
whether it is a risk or not.
What we are doing is we are adding that
as an additional context
to the action agent.
So whatever the information we got it,
we are adding a new agent which
will connect us to the API
and get what is the risk score
for this kind of transaction
and add this information
to the action agent.
And finally we are adding
the learning agent.
Whatever information the risk was done,
it'll be taken into the account...
Using the learning agent,
it'll take all the context information
and write it back to the DynamoDB,
then it act as a feedback loop
for our transaction monitoring.
This is how we have structured the agent.
So it is highly modular,
every use case will differ
and every requirement may be
differ based on your use case.
You can think this as a known reference
and you can build on top of it.
What we have done on this workflow,
what we learned on this workflow, right?
We identified the classic
ML way we are doing
is really, really working well.
But that is a challenge.
We are not able to do
proactive action, okay?
Because lot of decision we are making,
it's all in unstructured manner.
This agentic workflow, we
added the classic ML feature
into our agent workflow pipeline
and we leveraged the gen AI
to process the unstructured data.
And using a bedrock, we applied
all the guardrails needed
to make sure that it is not hallucinating
or it aligned to the enterprise need.
What we have achieved via
this anti-money laundering agentic system
we built using Strands
and AgentCore, right?
I love the future of observability,
AgentCore observability.
All the information we have
called what tool we have called
and how much time the
tool spend that time,
how we made all the information.
I no need to build anything.
I take care of my audit trial
and what done at the transaction level,
everything was observed
by the observability.
Then real time injection,
we have used a kinesis
or we can use a Kafka
according to our requirement.
And session installation, we are adding,
the context is what the
center of the piece, right?
We are using a Bedrock knowledge base.
We are using a AgentCore memory
to manage that complete session
and semantic reasoning for it.
And security and compliance,
we want to store all the data into the S3
and it is encrypted and
we are using a Bedrock.
Connecting to the bedrock
model as well as AgentCore
using a VPC endpoint, then all
the transaction information,
the lineage, everything, we
are using a elastic search
serverless which is highly
scalable for our requirement.
Then, our favorite, we
are using different model
for different requirement.
We are using a...
For the reasoning, we are
using a bedrock cloud model,
sorry, under the bedrock
we are using a cloud model,
for a different purpose, we
are using a (indistinct) model.
So this is how we structured it.
What is our expectation result?
Yes, we reduce the manual review.
As I mentioned how this report
was generated, it's manual.
We are able to accelerate using our LLM
to create those report and
reducing the false positive
and try to track it in a earlier manner.
And audit trial, whatever
the agentic workflow done,
all the context, all
the lineage information,
we are able to track it down.
That is the expected results from us.
That's all from me. And that's me AJ.
I tried to hand over this
the demo, realtime demo
which will be done by
Vivek, my fellow AI Hero.
- Thank you.
So it's time for the demo.
We have understood how things work
and what we have achieved to do.
So I'm gonna concentrate on one
of the most important agents
in this whole workflow,
which is the reasoning agent.
So the reasoning agent is built
using the Strands Agents SDK.
And as you can see the
agent class is instantiated,
which is from the Strands Agents
and the name of that is reasoning agent.
And the system prompt
actually defines the behavior
of the whole agent, which
includes figuring out
what the transaction does
by creating hypothesis,
indicators, explanation, confidence
and recommending what step
needs to be taken next
for this particular
transaction that comes through.
With that being said,
it also understands that
the reasoning agent depends
on the output and the context
that comes from the previous
agents that is in the workflow.
That is help using our AgentCore memory.
This helps the reasoning agent
to make very informed
decision about how to navigate
to make a informed decision
about a particular transaction
before marking that as a
fraudulent transaction or not.
So this AgentCore memory helps
you to maintain the context
across the whole session of the workflow
by saving the outputs of
each and every single agents
that works in this particular workflow.
And as you can see here, we
are trying to keep the context
from perception context
and all the other agents
and all these outputs
have been put under here.
With that being said, this
helps you to actually understand
how we need to actually
take a transaction,
stream it through Kinesis,
take it from Lambda
and also work through the
entire AgentCore system
and figure out how this
transaction comes through.
So this is a simple UI that we have built
and this is preloaded
with a couple of scenarios
that you can see on the left side.
The scenarios are of
different transactions
of different types of categories,
which includes low risk
transaction, medium risk
and high risk transactions.
And you can notice at the below that...
You can notice how in the
below that how this looks like
and we have both a PEP
donation into microstate NGO.
That is what we are going to pick
as one of the first scenario
that we wanted to run it through.
And there are multiple orchestrations
that we have already seen.
We are gonna pick the first one
which is your behavioral signal triage.
And that has a five agent
system which is your perception,
context, reasoning, action and audit.
We are going to run the system to see
how this transaction is being dealt
with this agentic workflow.
So all these agents are
being executed at the moment
and once the whole execution is done,
we also know how it really
works under the hood
by interacting with the gateway
and interacting with the AgentCore memory
and all the other stuff.
And the verdict that this
agentic workflow gives
for the scenario is that you
need to file an SAR report
and freeze this transaction.
But we are really interested
to understand that
how this decision is
really made by the agent
because we want to uncover this black box.
So the perception agent
tries to understand the users
which is a receiver and the sender
about what amount is being sent,
what is the currency that is being there
and where is it being sent and so on.
And one of the most important
jobs of the perception agent
is to understand the
KYC of both the sender
and the receiver here.
So it picks up the KYC details
of the sender and the
receiver and as you can see
the sender is also marked
as a high risk entity
and the receiver KFC also have been marked
as one of the high risk entity
that we have in the system.
So these are some of
the important features
that the perception agent
picks up and not just that,
the perception agent also calculates
a couple of other features such as
what's the device is being used
and what's the deviation of
our amount that takes place
in the transaction and so on.
And with all this information
that is being stored in AgentCore memory
and that is passed down
to your next agent,
which is your context agent.
The context agent picks up
the details of the sender
and the receiver of the 60 day transaction
that it takes place.
So it calculates a lot
of behavioral features
from out of it, like what's
a rolling average and so on.
And now comes one of the most important
and the core agent of the whole workflow,
which is your reasoning agent.
So the reasoning agent comes
with three different things,
which is, it creates a hypothesis
first like to understand
what to really make out
of this transaction.
So the hypothesis that it
really makes out is that
the transaction may be suspicious
but involvement of a PEP
and an excluder provider
and it creates an indicator
how it really marks that
why it makes this transaction
a little bit risky
and it gives a detailed explanation
what really it understands
from the transaction.
And the decision made is
around 0.85 of confidence
and it recommends the steps as well.
And that is passed down
to your action agent,
which recommends that this
needs to be filed SAR report
and you need to freeze this transaction.
And a lot of other actions have
been executed along the same
which is like you have to
freeze the transaction,
notify the operations team
and you have to also store the SAR report.
But depending on your organization,
you can also execute a lot of other tools
and workflows underneath.
And the audit trail is one
of the important trial agent
in the system which
understands and picks up
all the necessary outputs and details
that has been generated by each
and every single agent in the system,
which basically keeps your
audit clean and ready.
And with that being
said, the output is too,
we have to file an SAR.
And this is SAR report,
it has we generated
and the audit trail actually
gives a detail information
about each and every single
agent that is being executed
and what information has collected
and what information
that's produced and so on
so that a human in this particular loop
can identify and figure out
how it's being really
the decision is made.
Now let's try to run the same scenario
using our next use case, which
is a reputation pulse scan.
And you can notice that
we are going to include
a new agent in this workflow,
which is your news agent.
Let's run this orchestration
and see how that works out.
And it goes through each and every agent
and it tries to understand
how the transaction works.
And with that being said, once
the transaction is completed
you get to see the entire results
of how this agent has taken
this particular verdict.
So we already know how
the other agents works.
Let's jump into how this news
agent is really working out
in this new use case.
So, it tries to understand
what is a sender country,
receiver country and so on.
And one of the notes it has
really maintained is that
the receiver is a sanctioned person.
So let's go into audit
to really figure out
how the news agent really came up
with this particular results.
So you can see here that in the news
it has mentioned that the
receiver is sanctioned
but also this news agent
just not stops there.
It tries to understand who's
the receiver, who's the sender
by going and interacting
with the sanctions list
that is available
to mark if the person is
under the sanctions list.
And it also checks the
geopolitical situation
of the transaction to see
if some transaction needs to be restricted
based on the country of
the sender and receiver.
And the third orchestration
workflow is that
you have all the agents in the workflow,
which is your complex and
the full use case that we see
and it involves both risk
and the learning agent.
So let's try to see how this
orchestration goes through
and now our going to be, our
focus is about to learn about
how this risk agent comes
into the whole picture
and how does it really influence
the whole decision making process
and how this learning agent
is going to keep us involved
in this whole process about
to figure out how this
patterns are not being repeated
in the future.
So once this agent has been executed,
let's jump into what we
are really interested about
which is your risk agent.
So we have marked a rule engine system
in this whole workflow and
this rule engine could be
your organization's rule engine
or maybe the compliance's rule
engine that you might have.
Alright, so the rule engine
that we have created is that
the agent has figured out that
there's a high risk of
entity rating for the sender
and there is a sanctioned
status of the receiver.
Let's go into this audit report and see
how this agent really worked out
and what are the information
it was able to figure out
from this whole thing.
So you can see here that
these are the rules that
this particular agent was
able to pick up and execute
based on how it really work.
So this agent is not particularly
an LLM focused agent,
it's a Python agent
but it's driven by your machine learning,
classical machine learning
model or your rule engine.
Based on all these rule
engines which has been created,
these are the contributing
factors, it has figured out that
it might influence the transaction status
and what needs to be done
with the transaction here.
And with that being said,
the learning agent tries to
picks up all these learnings,
put back into the DynamoDB
that we already have so that
when the next such patterns occurs,
your agents are much more
intelligent enough to go ahead
and make more informed
decisions around it.
So now that we have seen a scenario
with almost all the
three different use case,
let's try to mix and
match different scenarios
and see how that really helps out for us.
So we are going to run the
whole, the L3 three use case
with the second scenario which is your,
you're gonna execute a payroll
which is from a Singapore public official.
The verdict is that yeah
you need to file an SAR
but this transaction is okay to be let out
but you need to keep monitoring to see
if something really flags out
in the past, in the future.
So you can see that who's the sender
and the receiver of the agent.
The reasoning agent picks out that
this is a payroll payment and so on
and this is a verdict
that it comes out with.
Now let's even more go with a very simple,
low risk entity scenario
and let's run with one
of the most simplest
agentic workflow that we have here.
With that being said, we
are going to run a scenario
which is a synthetic community payroll.
Though this is a very low
role, sorry low risk entity,
this still flags out that
you need to file an SAR,
which is your suspicious activity report
and you have to monitor
the transaction over here.
And if you go into the
audit report, it figures out
and shows you the whole detail about
what really made this
decision needs to be made.
So with that all being said,
we have seen scenarios where
how a transaction is being taken
and how it's being sent into Kinesis
and how this whole agentic
workflows has been deployed
in AgentCore runtime,
which makes it super easy
and with the help of gateway
to access the more tools
outside the agent to give the
agents much more accessibility
and also the memory to keep a context
of every single transaction
that comes from,
from the perception to the end
of the agents to figure out
to make up more informed
decisions around it.
So we have used couple of strategies
to keep the memories much more consistent.
So we have used short-term memory
but we have manually written down
each and every output of
the agents which goes there.
So this is a complete demo that goes into,
but let's take a bit of time to understand
how this couple of other
agents has been written
because not every single
agent that we have seen
is not a Strands agent in particular.
So let me go to one of
the agents that we have,
which is your...
So let's start with the perception agent,
which is your most familiar
agent that we have.
So, here the perception
agent is not really your,
an LLM powered agent, but it
is a Python powered agent,
but it still utilizes the tools
which is being exposed
to this in a way that
it was able to access the information
about your KYC details and much more.
And we have the context agent
which tries to retrieve the same
about the 60 days transaction details
of both the receiver and the sender.
And even that is exposed
to you from DynamoDB
through a gateway tools,
through AgentCore gateway tools.
And we all know the most important agent
is a reasoning agent,
which we've already seen
at the start of the demo.
And this also ensures that
it drops down the whole information about
how the decision is being made
and how it is being made as well.
And the reasoning agent has
a couple of entities like
the indicator, what hypothesis it has made
and what explanation it has given.
And also the most important
thing is how confident it is
with the score that has been generated
so that this transaction
could be flagged or not.
And next we have is our...
Before that we also have a news agent.
So news agent is something
which we have actually taken
a special interest to create it.
Usually this news agent
would be a couple of APIs
which gives you information
about the SDN reports
or the securities reports or
the sanctions list and so on.
But for the simplicity
of this particular demo,
we have stored the entire
sanctions and the securities list
in a knowledge base and we have
exposed this knowledge base
to the agent so that it
can access to figure out
whether this receiver or sender
is part of this particular
sanctions list and so on.
And most importantly, not
everything could be just covered
by saying that, if it just
from this sanctions list,
it is meant to be a
fraudulent transaction.
It's not necessarily need to be.
So, we also actively monitor
what is a geopolitical
situation that occurs
around the transaction.
Like for example, there
is a war-stricken country
and it's trying to transact
an amount which is absurdly,
which is very high.
Of course the human who is in the system
would be able to easily
understand that hey,
there is something
wrong which is going on,
but your agent might really pass it out
because that's not
really that a flagged out
as a suspicious transaction.
But the news agent which
has access to the internet
through the tool of using the browser,
it's able to understand that hey,
there is a war-stricken country
and this is trying to make a transaction.
And with all this
information about this news,
the the KYC details and the
history of the transaction,
your reasoning agent
now has more information
and as much efficiency as you as a human
to make more informed decision
that this transaction might be flagged
as a money laundering
transaction with being over here.
And the rest of the agents keeps
the actions being executed.
So the action agent figures out
which sort of risk band
that it falls through.
And we have your risk agent,
which actually combines
your existing machine learning models
or the classical models
that you might build
for your company or your organization
so that you don't leave
out the legacy system
out of the picture, but you also use them
as one of your helping hands
to make much more informed decisions.
This also helps you to
keep the compliancies
much more intact with the new solutions
and keeping the whole legacy
solution into the system.
And all that being said,
the audit helps you
to keep the entire trial
of the transactions
and that helps you to
keep your compliance team much more happy
to understand how this agent is making
much more informed decisions.
And we have finally the learning agent
where it gives you the feedback loop of
how this transaction has been evaluated,
and what was the risk which was associated
and what was the reasons it has been made
and how this entity's
risk band has been updated
post this evaluation.
And this learning agent
keeps updating the databases,
which helps you to make
much more informed decisions
of such existing patterns
occurring in the future as well.
So with that being said,
this completely helps you to understand
how we have built an entire workflow
to understand how to flag out transaction,
which might be a money-laundering
fraudulent transactions here
and the multi-agent orchestration systems
have been really helpful
to increase the accuracy
and decrease the time in
flagging of the system
and improving the efficiency
of the whole organization as well.
So this is Vivek Raja, I'm
AWS machine learning, sorry,
I'm AWS Machine Learning Hero
and along with me is
Bhuvaneswari Subramani,
who is a AWS Hero.
And we have Ayyanar Jeyakrishnan,
who is representing AWS community
and he's also a Machine Learning Hero.
We'll be around in this
hallway if you have doubts
or you wanted to interact more about
how this solution works.
Sorry?
Okay.
So this is us and we'll be
available in the hallway
if you wanted to catch up with
us to understand more about
how the solution works or how
you wanted to integrate these
with your existing solutions
that you have in your company
or you wanted to explore the same.
So thank you everyone for this.