Morning everybody.
Um,
we are here at a session, Dev 320
advanced feature flags, faster releases,
and rapid recovery.
So if that's what you thought you're gonna hear about,
you're in the right place.
My name is Steve Rice. I'm general manager
for AWS app config.
Um, also parameter store today we're gonna
focus on feature flags and
actually use app config as the code talk
example. Um, so there are other
solutions out there for feature flagging. I was quickly
talking to some people. A lot of people are using a homegrown
solution. We're gonna show you app config.
Some of the concepts are available on other services
or other offerings as well.
Um, first I just wanna say
we want this to be interactive. I think code talks
are, they're one of my favorite types of sessions
and it's way more fun when people are interactive.
Um, so we do want questions along the way.
I probably will cut us off
at some point with the questions so we can keep moving
forward. We do have a lot of content to cover.
Ben's got to write a lot of code,
um, and so please raise your
hand. I have a microphone. I might just
repeat your question so everybody can hear this, um,
but first, just real quick, just how many people,
this is your first reinvent.
OK, wow, great. Welcome.
Hope you're having a great time. Hope you're
getting in a lot of steps. I'm sure you are. How many
have been did 2 reinvents?
OK, 3.
5.
6.
Anybody 6 or more?
67?
Wow, 8,
dang, 9.
OK, 8, you're the record. OK, cool.
I have swag
that I'm going to give to you outside of
the session,
so I'm gonna give you, I, I didn't see who it was. Find me and
I have a jacket for you. Um, I have some
swag that is an incentive for participation.
Um, I'll give it out at the end outside.
Uh, great. So again, my name is Steve Rice.
Um, I've been using Future Flags for a very
long time, really excited to talk about Future
Flags. I feel like they're the secret weapon
of moving fast when you're developing
software as well as responding to
issues on production,
flipping flags as operational flags
to, uh, address an issue that's out there. So
I'm gonna be, I'm joined by Ben. You wanna introduce
yourself, please? Hey everyone, my name's Ben. I am a
senior software development engineer at AWS
and I work primarily on the AWS
app config team.
Great. Great. So, uh, in
terms of where you are on your future flagging
journey, I'm gonna ask how many people
are using a homegrown solution?
For feature flagging, OK,
actually I should really ask how many people are not using feature
flags at all yet? OK, a couple of people, yep,
um,
that's totally fine. Uh, homegrown
usually is a lot of hands, um,
and, and again I've worked at many companies we've
started with a homegrown solution. What often
happens is,
uh, you realize that hey, there's some new capabilities
that we need beyond just having a database or an
S3 bucket to flip on and off things
and should we,
you know, move off of our homegrown.
Uh, should we develop those features in-house,
and you know that's a decision that you all have to make,
um, but AC config is obviously a third party
solution, but we're well integrated into AWS
and have integrations with a lot of computes.
So, um, so in order to sort of
set the table for today we're gonna role
play a little with me.
Um, I'm gonna pretend that I'm a business owner
and Ben is an engineer and he's gonna
use feature flags.
So the, uh, situation I'm trying to create
here is I own a coffee shop.
Um, it's called Lambda Latte,
uh, which is maybe I don't know about AWS,
but I'm a business owner. I don't know much about
technology. Um, Ben is my brother-in-law,
and I heard he's a good coder, so I asked him, Will you
please make an app, and I really need this app for
my business.
Um, I'm really good at making coffee. I'm
not great at technology,
so I'm not gonna be. Like a solid business owner
that's gonna understand the requirements process.
I'm gonna change my mind a lot and to be honest,
feature flags are a really good solution for some of these
things. So, um,
uh, Ben and I had prepared a little bit of a, uh,
you know, preceded demo here of a
coffee app,
coffee shop app from a place called Lambda
Latte. Great
Ben actually if you wanna sort of explain the, the background
here, go ahead, yeah, absolutely. I'll walk us through
that application now. So as Steve mentioned.
We're going to be using this Lambda Latte
application as our base for our feature flag demos
today. So the purpose of this
application is for customers of
the Lambda Latte Coffee Shop to
download the app and see some information about the coffee shop,
place orders, things of that nature.
Give you a quick walk through the app since we're
gonna be spending a decent amount of time on this today.
I just wanna give a quick overview to make sure
that we all
understand what the, the, the context
around these demos is.
So I'm looking at the Lambda the Lambda latte
app. We can see it has 3 tabs.
On the home tab, I can see some
information about the coffee shop, how many orders are in flight,
uh, you know, maybe I'm rushing to the office and I want to see
if there's a long line or not, then I could look here.
Uh, we've got today's featured roaster, we have equipment
status.
No one likes showing up at the coffee shop and all the espresso
machines are downright, so you can check that here.
And then, of course, we have the stock of the various
types of milk that the shop has
left. We also have a couple of other
tabs I'll show quickly. We have a my rewards tab
which shows you the rewards that you currently
have, and then finally we have an order tab,
which is basically the full menu and the ability to
place an order.
And there's one more thing you'll notice about this demo
application is that there's a selection at the top for
the customer profile.
So since this is a demo,
uh, this app lets us view
the.
The app through the lens of different users.
So right now we're looking at the app through the lens of Elena,
who is our default
user. We also have two other customer
profiles that we'll be clicking on. So we have Marcus
and Jasper,
and these two users have a
loyalty status associated with them, gold
and platinum,
and that will come into play in a later
demo. So just for now
realize this is a way that we can quickly just switch
between different users of the application. For
now there's no difference between.
Any of these three views, but that will
change. OK,
that's the Landa Latte application
from the customer's point of view.
However, since this is a code talk, I want to
spend some time upfront talking about the actual architecture
behind this application and how it's set up, and
where the code is that we're gonna be modifying later in the
talk. So in order to do that,
I'm gonna switch over to Quiro,
and I've got some steering docs
set up, one of which is architecture. MD
which outlines the architecture of the
application. Render the preview
of that so we can take a look.
So here's my setup.
I have the lambda latte at the top, the
lambda latte front-end web application,
which is hosted at Sun Domain.
This is making requests to my back end, which
is really just an AWS lambda
function. And the
purpose of this lambda function is to
effectively just get feature flag
values from app config.
Now in order to get those feature flag values
from app config, it's actually using
the app config agent,
which is a sidecar process that
that we, the app config team vend
to simplify your integration with app config.
Uh, it has some built-in resiliency features
so that your flags are highly available even if
you're having networking issues, etc.
Um,
in the lambda context, this is mended as a layer
or an extension, that's why it says layer there.
And then of course this agent or layer is talking
to the AWS app config
service directly.
So this is the setup architecture for the
application. It's
fairly straightforward. Does anyone have any
questions about how this is set up? Does this generally
make sense?
Lambda function backend,
front end web app,
OK. Um,
now, since this is a live demo,
uh, you can see here this, this
diagram is titled Production Environment.
Since this is a live demo, I don't wanna spend time
every time I update my code redeploying a lambda
function, etc. So I have a local development
environment set up that will let me change code
and affect those changes instantly instead of waiting for
deployments.
That setup is here. It's very similar to
the production setup that we just looked at. The
differences are that everything is running
locally, so the Lambda latte app I have running locally,
I have a local HTP test
server that just directly invokes my, my lambda
logic,
my lambda back in logic.
I have the app config agent running locally,
and then we have the app config service. Now do
note the the app config service here, I'm not running that
locally. This is the real production app
config service.
OK. Any questions about architecture before I
move on to looking at the code?
Great. Ben, I have a question. Yeah,
you're showing lambda. Does this future flags
work in things beyond lambda?
Great question.
Uh,
yes, app config works
anywhere. Uh, we have, so I mentioned
the app config agent.
We vend the, we vend this agent
in lambda as a layer.
However, we also vend the agent as a container
image, so you can use it in places like ECS,
uh, EKS, or your own Kubernetes cluster
or just Docker running on your, on your, uh,
laptop.
We also vend the agent as an
RPM so you can download it on EC2
instances or on-prem instances.
OK, let's take a look at the code.
So as the diagram mentioned, we have this
app config.pi. I'm gonna make
sure this is large enough.
Um
App config.pi file, which is our lambda
function, uh, logic.
So you can see we have this top level function lambda handler
takes an event and context. If you're familiar
with lambda functions, these are the two inputs that all
lambda functions take.
And in this case, we have a
request structure that looks like
this that we see online 17 through 22.
I'm basically providing a dictionary
called flags, and within that dictionary, I'm
including the keys of the flags that I would like the
function to retrieve.
Now you'll notice that these keys are also pointing to
empty dictionaries in this case.
Um, we're ignoring those for now, they'll come into play
later. The response
structure
has a flags dictionary as well,
and then for the provided keys, it will
populate the feature flag value
that came from that was returned by
the app config service.
So in this case, the piece that's highlighted on the screen now, this
is what the app config service said the the
flag value was for flag one.
We also have another top level field called errors, so if
anything goes wrong with retrieving one or more of your
flags, then you'll see those keys appear in this section,
and there'll be some reasoning as to why those flags
could not be retrieved, in this case,
not found. OK,
so I'm gonna just quickly give an overview.
Of how this code is set up. We have some setup code that's reading
some environment variables, parsing the event
data. The main logic is here, where I'm
going through each of the flag keys and the
requests, and I'm getting that flag from the app
config agent.
Finally, I'm building my response, handling errors, and
returning. As far as the get flag from
agent code, this is making again
a local host HTTP request.
This is the same in the dev environment and in the prod environment.
The request looks exactly like this to the app config
agent, and I'm
asking the agent for that particular flag
and doing some error handling.
OK,
that's the overview of our back end
code. This is the
primary file that we're gonna be modifying throughout our
demos in this session, so I want to make sure
we have a high level overview, overview first before
we dive into the changes.
OK, the last thing I want to show, I mentioned that
we're using the production app config service
for these demos.
So I'll come back to my browser and move the lambda latte
app to the side,
pull up the app config console,
and in the app config console, I
am looking at a feature flag configuration
called lambda latte,
and this configuration currently
has 3 feature flags in it, which we're going to use at various
points through our demos.
And with that, that's an overview of the
uh Lambda latte application,
it's architecture, how it works, how it integrates
with the app config service.
So that's gonna lay the baseline for the demos
that we're gonna be talking about during the session today.
Any questions about how this is set up or what the
application's purpose is or its architecture
or anything like that?
OK. And
to the technical people in the room you explained
it really well, but I'm, I'm a business owner
and I got this coffee that I need to sell
and uh what I
have learned from my customers is
around December they love to have
a peppermint spice.
Type of coffee like the peppermint spice latte
is like a really hot seller
and people talk about it and
what I'd really love to have, I don't know how it'll work, but
I'd like to have the app updated
and I think I wanna have some texts about a peppermint
spice update, but like I wanna promote
this, uh, this drink in
my app. So can you just make that happen? Yes,
I can just make that happen. All right,
great. OK, so let's talk about this
first use case where we want to promote, promote
a product on our website.
In this case it's the Lambda latte app and we wanna promote
the peppermint, uh,
I think it's called Peppermint candy cane latte that
we're, that we're, that we're that we're promoting here.
OK, so to do this,
this is really meant to be a like
baseline just feature flags one on one type demo.
So I already have the code that's required
in the front end,
uh, the front end web application and the back
end lambda function that's required to, to do this
simple flag retrieval and rendering this
simple banner experience. So we're not actually gonna dive into
the code for that
for the sake of time. Again, this is just meant to be
very simple feature flags one on one demo
off the bat here.
So, I can see in my feature flag config,
I have this one flag called
featured item.
And this featured item flag,
if I scroll down,
here's the toggle button for my flag.
It's currently off.
We're gonna turn that on. You'll also notice this
section called attribute values.
So app config feature flags are more than
just an on-off switch. It can just
be an on-off switch, but we also provide this
functionality called attributes,
which is effectively just arbitrary, uh,
metadata that you attach to a feature flag.
And it, it's really powerful because it can
drive, you can use those attributes to actually
drive the behavior of your
application. And so in this case,
we have 3 attributes that are defined. We have a description, a
name, and a price.
And these values that are that are set
in this feature flag are actually going to be used
by the front-end web application to render
the experience.
So the turning this flag on will
turn the banner on, and then the value of these attribute
values determines the content of that banner.
OK, so I've turned this flag on. What I
need to do now.
Is save my changes and deploy it.
So an app config, every time you make a change, every
config change, feature flags included,
are versioned.
And so when I save a new version of my config, I
need to go deploy that new version, which is what I'm doing
now. Since this is a demo,
I'm gonna do what we call an instant deployment.
We don't recommend instant deployments in any production use
case. We'll talk more about, uh, we call this deployment
safety. We'll talk about this a little bit more later,
but since this is a demo, I'm gonna go ahead and do an instant
deployment.
Now, I will say when I click the start deployment button,
the console, the app config console on the left-hand side
is gonna render a new screen that's gonna look really exciting
and you're gonna wanna see what that screen is doing.
Don't look at that screen after I click this button. Look at
the right-hand side. Look at the Lambda Latte app because
that's where the, the banner is going to be appearing.
So let's start this deployment and keep our eyes on
the Lambda latte app,
and there we go. Our featured item banner
is now displayed.
I didn't make any code changes, I didn't redeploy
my back end, I didn't redeploy my front end. I just
made a change in the app config console.
I will also to highlight.
The power of attributes.
If I change this, I don't know, peppermint
candy cane latte 2,
and I save this and update it
and deploy it.
Then we should see the content update.
There we go. OK.
Steve, what do you think about that uh promotion?
I love it. That's, that's exactly what I'm
looking for. Can I make it go away
after Christmas?
Absolutely, uh cool,
um, sorry for the corniness of the simulation
we actually didn't practice this, uh, as
much, so, um, OK, great, but
my next request as a business owner
is I do have this, uh, loyalty
concept but really today it doesn't really
land and I've heard that if I reward my best
customers in certain ways and I can tailor
those rewards
that they'll actually spend more money
um so is there a way that I can sort of look
at different layers and maybe different give a different
kind of flag to each type of user?
Yes, absolutely.
OK, so for this
featured item banner
demonstration that we just did, it's important to note
that
this is a, this experience that we just rendered
is the, it's the same for everyone, right? So I'm viewing the
app as Elena now and I see the banner.
I view the app as Marcus, I see the same banner,
view the app as Jasper, and I see the same banner. There's no differentiation
between the different users and the experience
that they're seeing.
And so the ask now from the business owner
is, OK, well, I wanna do something a little bit more
sophisticated than that.
I want to render different
experiences for different types of customers
or segments of customers that we, we call them.
And in this case, the segmentation is based
on the user's loyalty status
and based on their loyalty status, what we wanna do
is render different sets of
rewards depending on loyalty
status.
So if I click the my rewards tab right now,
I'll see currently I'm Jasper, who's a platinum loyalty
member. I just have a single reward here. It's a free
espresso. It's, it's code R-001.
OK,
if I go to, if I switch over to Marcus,
he's a gold member, well, I, I see the same thing,
and of course, Elena, as you may
suspect, the exact same rewards.
And so the ask is, OK, well, I, I want
to honor my, my most valued customers, and
I wanna, I wanna offer different sets of rewards
to, to diff to customers that
are in different loyalty statuses.
So let's do that with the feature flag.
First I'm going to go.
Back to my
featured item. I'm actually gonna turn this off so I can
save some screen real estate here. We've got a
bit of a small screen here,
so let me just deploy this.
And we should see that banner turn off.
Um OK,
it's gone. OK,
so let's talk about how we can make this,
this use case work with a feature flag.
So in app config, we have two
types of future flags which are denoted by
this uh selector down here at the bottom.
The previous flag that we looked at is what we call a basic
flag. And a basic flag is really just,
it's the same for all end users, right? I turn
something on, I turn something off. It's the same for everyone. It's,
it's a basic flag.
However, if I have a more advanced use case like
customer segmentation, like we have in in the
coffee shop demo here, then I can create
what's called a multi-variant flag.
A multi-variant flag is a flag that allows
me to create
alternative feature flag values and therefore
alternative user experiences
for different sets of users based on some rules
that I define.
So, I actually already have this one
set up so that we can talk through it without me having
to click a bunch of buttons.
So we'll see if you remember when we're looking at our
basic flag, we're looking at the, the, it's called
the flag value section at the bottom, we just had a single
toggle, we had a single set of attributes,
variance builds on that and allows you to define
the toggle state and the attribute values
for each what we call variant.
And in this case I have 3 variants. I have platinum, gold,
and default,
and each variant has a rule that I
define. Now this is kind of a compressed view, so I'm
actually gonna open this in the split panel so we can get a better
view of these variants.
So again, I have 3 variants platinum, gold, and default.
Taking a deeper look at the platinum variant.
I can see that it's turned on. I want rewards enabled
for my platinum customers,
and I have an attribute called items which lists
the reward codes for the rewards that I'd like
to offer to my platinum customers.
Also, this variant has a rule.
This is a fairly simple rule where it's checking if
the customer's loyalty status is equal to the
string platinum.
Now, you'll notice,
or rather when you request a multi-variant
feature flag from the app config agent,
in this case, you pass in what we call
request context.
So rather than just saying I want flag ABC,
you say I want flag ABC and
the user type is admin and the user's
loyalty status is none, and the
user joined,
you know, on whatever date, etc. etc.
whatever type of context that's relevant
to the rules that you author for your multi-variant feature
flag. So in the case of the Lambda Latte
app, we're just interested in this, this loyalty status
piece, so we have a pretty simple
rule that serves that use case.
However, note that rules can get
fairly complex with an app config,
so I can do um.
Some different operations. I'm just gonna clear this.
There's a bunch of operations we support. We can talk about this
more later.
Um, for now, I'm just gonna continue with
the demo. It
also supports compound rules, so ands and orders, etc.
so you can get fairly
complex and specific with the types of users that you want to
target with different experiences.
OK, the gold variant is
probably not very surprising. I'm checking loyalty
status equals to equals gold for my rule,
and I'm limiting the items to R1 and R2.
And then my default variant.
The default variant doesn't have a rule because this
is kind of your fallback.
So if you make a request to the agent and the context
that you provide doesn't match any rules of the other variants,
then this is the fallback default variant
that's served to that request. So in this
case we just have
uh R-001 for those customers.
OK, so this is our
multi-variant flag that models
how we want to display different types of rewards
to different customers.
Now again, since this is a demo, I've already
got the front end code in place
to basically
pull this flag, parse the uh
the items attribute value, the
list of items, and it does like a, a
quick look up to say, 0, R1 is is this
reward, R2 is this sword, etc.
So the front end code is already written.
However, the back-end code is not sufficiently,
uh,
set up to
pass this request context
that I've been talking about to the app config agent,
which is why,
again, I just did a
deployment in the previous demo which deploys all of
my flags,
since I have them in the same configuration, which means
this is actually my live config right now.
But remember when I clicked through the different
customer profiles earlier, we were seeing the same
experience for every customer.
Everyone was just seeing one reward, and that's because I, I
haven't made that back end update yet to properly
pass in request context and get
the proper variant for the given
end user, uh,
and then render that experience appropriately.
So what we're going to do now is go into the back end and
make that code change to properly
retrieve a multivariant
feature flag from the app config agent.
So let's do that.
Let's head back into Quiro.
And let's open the app
config.pi file, which is of course
my lambda backend logic.
And we are going to
uh go through this code and make a couple updates
to properly
handle and pass request context
to the app configuration.
So earlier we were talking about the input event structure and we had
the flag's dictionary, and each
flag, uh, or each key in that dictionary
had it in itself an empty dictionary.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna take advantage of that
empty empty dictionary
and use it as a place to put
request context.
And so, I would have something like, in
the case of the Lambda Latte app, I
would have loyalty status,
for example, uh, gold.
So now our request structure,
uh,
or with the code updates that we're about to make, our request
structure will support
this type of requests where
context is included.
So how do we do that?
Firstly,
let's go directly to the code that's
that's making requests to the app config agent,
because this is where request context is
passed in.
So you'll see right now, we have our,
uh, what's called here the base URL for the app
config agent, which again is running on localhost
port 2772,
happens to be the default port for the app config agent, you
can set it to whatever you like.
And
the way this request is working right now is
it's just, it's saying
with the example I was using earlier, it's saying, hey
app config agent, give me flag ABC.
But we want, what we want to do is update it to say, hey, give me
flag ABC but also pass in or use this
context.
So let's do that.
So the way we do this
Is by
passing in a, an HTTP
header called context.
And so
Let me just
write out what I'm doing,
a request, context in.
Context HTP header.
And just to give you a visual before we actually
write this code, here's some
examples of
the context header.
So the key.
Is context and
In the case of lambda latte, I
might be doing something like this, loyalty status equals
gold. That's
of course a single context value, but we
support an arbitrary number of context values. So you can also
do something like this where you say the
context is
uh
K1 equals V1,
K2 equals V2.
So you can pass in as much context as you like.
OK, so what does this, what does the code actually look like?
So if I have,
well, first I need to update my function signature
to actually accept
request context. Right now it only accepts the flag
key, but
Excuse me, in addition to the flag key, we also want to
accept request,
context.
What do we do with that request context? Well,
if I have, if there is request context
present, then I want to basically build the
HTP header like we have in the examples
on the lines above.
So the first thing I'm gonna do.
I create this variable called
context parts.
And this is effectively going to build my
uh key equals value piece
of my head. So
I'll take the
Just build this here and
then for key value
in.
Quest context. items.
So I'll iterate through my request context and I'll
create this uh K equals V
type setup,
and then I will create the actual header
content. Which of course
will join
these uh K equals V.
Parts into a comma
separated.
List
Which then, of course, we will add
to our HTP request.
We'll add the header called context,
and we will pass in
the context header.
OK, so now when my backend code
makes a request to the app config agent, it's gonna
include this request context in the context
header so that the agent can evaluate it and return the
appropriate variant for my
particular end user that's making the request.
Yes, um, so
you're facing a request to call your agent. Um,
it's an agent named Leon McCafey.
Yeah. That's absolutely correct. Ben,
can you repeat the question?
Yes, so the question is, so in this code I'm,
I'm making requests to localhost 2772,
which is the app config agent,
and the question is, every time I make a
request to the agent,
is that making another request to AWS
or, or is the agent handling the caching? Is that the question?
That's right, the agent's handling the caching, so
the way that multi-variant feature flags
work is.
Each time you pass in, so the the first
time you request this flag, yes, there's
gonna be a call to the app config service to get
uh the, the configuration
information, but then for each subsequent request,
regardless of the context.
There's no new network call being made. The
agent is locally caching the config and locally
evaluating
the, uh, the rules, so that
way you, you get the resiliency of
not having to have all these network calls,
uh, you get the performance improvement of not having
to wait for the network calls, and then of course the,
the performance of doing the actual evaluation
locally within the agent instead of on the remote app
config service. So you get that really performant,
uh, rule evaluation. Does that answer your question?
So if you have like already have like a recent instance going if there's.
You know that you. Yeah, you would just use
this. Yeah, so the agent works as, as, as
your cache for app config data. Yeah, there's
no need to insert
a cache of your own.
Great, thank you.
Other questions, questions, yeah,
uh, one here,
uh, what happened to that cash scale,
what is the values of cash?
So the way the cache works is
by default, it will never
evict any data.
So this is a resiliency strategy
that, that we use.
Um,
for example, if you get,
so let me, let me
back up for a second. So the way the cache works is
the agent will obviously make that initial
call to app config,
pull the configuration data, in this case the feature flags,
and then what happens is it spins up a
background thread within the agent that periodically
pings the app config service asking, hey,
do you have any updates for this config?
And so that'll happen on a, it's a configurable cadence
by default, it's every 45 seconds, it'll check
in with the app config service to say, hey, do you
have any updates for this config,
right? And that process continues in the background
for the life of the agent process,
right? And so there's no, there's
no, uh, data eviction.
If there's some kind of network event that cuts
off your access to app config or all of
AWS at some point, then the agent,
the agent will still serve the latest
config data that it knows about
from its cache.
persistent is that is the light
of the session.
Good question. Um,
can you repeat the question?
How persistent is the agent cash?
The answer is that by
default, or I shouldn't say by default, but
there's a few layers of
I'd, I'll say resiliency that the agent offers.
And so
the first obviously is in memory, which
I've already talked about, but that doesn't help you much if your,
if your application restarts or if your host reboots,
etc.
and so we have additional features built in.
To protect against that type of scenario, for
example, we have an on-disc backup
option that you can enable,
and so that's not available in lambda, of course,
which is what this, uh, demo is about.
However, if you're running in a container environment
or if you're running on EC2 or on-prem, etc.
then we, it's a best practice to enable
that on-disc backup mechanism so that
in addition to the in memory caching, you get the
on-disc caching.
OK. Uh, there's a question here in the middle, yes.
So, um,
when you're showing the deployment, what exactly is
being deployed?
Yeah, so the question is, when I'm showing the deployment,
what actually is being deployed?
And the answer is that I'm deploying my
configuration data through app config.
So app config is a feature flagging
service.
Feature flags are a special
type of configuration.
And what app config does at its
core is it allows you to
create versions of your configuration
data and then deploy
those uh and then deploy your configuration data
by version, right? And each version is an immutable
set of data, you can't change it,
right? This is one of the key,
uh,
value props of app config is that
your data is immutable and when you want
to change it, it's more than just creating it, you have to
create it and deploy it.
And the, the benefit of that is if
you decide, you know, you make a deployment and then you
decide, oh wait, this is breaking something
or it's not working the way that I want, then you
can roll back that deployment and you go back
to the last known state of the config,
right? Does that make sense?
Is an occupation.
Exactly, yeah, so you saw the
app config deployments that I was doing earlier.
Those of course were instant deployments, so
they, they happen instantly.
And so you saw how our application updated after
I did that deployment.
It's just a, it's, it's a, uh,
kind of app config as a control plane
kind of concept. It's, it's not, it's not taking
hosts out of servers, it's not deploying software, it's
just deploying
the new newest version of my configuration
in the app config service.
One of the things that we do and we can get to other
questions in a second, but is that's really important for AP
config is the idea that you should deploy
slowly and gradually. Um, every
change that you make, including a configuration
change, could break your
production environment and if you think back to the last
18 months, a lot of the major outages
of providers have been related to configuration
changes
that were deployed everywhere all at once,
um, so Ben's demo showed an
instant deployment that's
a bit of an. Type pattern he's doing a demo, so
it would be boring for you to wait 15 minutes, but I'll
say we use app config inside of
AWS and Amazon and we have a policy that
it has to be at least 30 minutes
of a deployment,
um, and bake time, uh, for any change
of configuration unless you're
breaking glass and you need to address something right away. You can
do that with hap config, but yeah, this idea of it's
just similar to like a code, it's the metaphor of a
code pipeline, right? It is I'm deploying configuration
in a way similar that I deploy code gradually.
OK, we'll take one more question in this section, then
we'll move on with the demo here up front.
Um, is it possible to have the agent
evaluate
differently based on whether or not they can reach the
applicant service? I'm thinking about
cases where there might be a security sensitive configuration
that you might want to be closed on,
um, in case the service.
Um, the agent doesn't have anything like that.
Can you repeat the question?
Oh, sorry, the question is, can I
change effectively the, the
response that the agent returns based on the availability
of the app config service
or the reachability of the app config service, I should
say. Is that correct?
Yes, the answer is no. There's no built-in
way in the agent to do that right now.
Uh, so if you want, if you want functionality
like that, then you would have a thin, a thin
wrapper around your agent calls that say, you know, for this
set of flags or whatever,
uh, use this default value if I can't, if I
can't retrieve it, right? Does that make sense? OK.
OK, let's move on with this demo. We will get
to more questions later.
So again, what are we doing? We're trying to update the
content of our my rewards
tab on the Lambda Latte app
to uh.
Be different based on customers' loyalty status.
And so what we did is we made some code changes.
And I actually,
there's one more change that I need to make. So
this function get flagged from agent.
I've added request context.
I need to actually pass that context in up in
my main
uh handler functions, let's do that.
So, now, when I look
through my request object, instead of just looking at the keys,
I'm going to look at the entire item.
And I'm gonna do
a flag key request context, and then when
I call get flagged from agent, I will pass
in. Request context.
OK, and I believe that's all the changes
I need. Let me take a quick
peek.
OK. So
I made some changes to my backend code, so now I have
to restart my back end.
So let's do that.
OK, it's running again.
Now let's head back to
The application.
And the rewards tab should
be
working, but it's not, of course.
I check on a couple other users.
OK.
So something is broken.
Let me try.
Like I said, live demos are fun. Live coding is even
better, so let me
restart things.
And we will give this a shot.
OK, I'm not sure where the bug is here.
Um, what I was expecting to see
is for Elena, who doesn't have loyalty status,
I was expecting to see reward one,
and then for
Marcus, who has gold status rewards 1 and 2,
and then Jasper with
status platinum to see 4 rewards.
I think doing live debugging is
gonna take
too long.
I've heard the audience loves it when it doesn't go perfectly,
Ben, so you, you nailed it. I don't, I don't
love it when it doesn't go perfectly, but.
Do you have? We
have, sorry, what was that? It's gonna debug for you, Ben. Oh,
we have a debugger in the ground.
Uh, you did request that header.
Yes, I.
You can find down in the fire block.
Oh Yeah, that's
a good call.
How about we put this block of code after this variable
exists? The
All right,
good eye. Thank
you. OK,
wow, thank you.
OK.
Uh, so again, Jasper, a platinum
member, has 4 rewards.
Uh,
Marcus, our gold member, has 2 rewards,
and Elena, our default
status member, has a single reward.
So again, what, what's the point of this? The point is that
we can use a feature flag to render dynamic
experiences for different segments of customers.
In this case, for the lambda latte uh demo
example, the segment is based on
the user's loyalty status.
OK,
um, Steve, does that fulfill your, your
business requirements? Absolutely. That
gives me a lot of flexibility and allows me to customize,
and that's a more advanced type of feature flag,
uh, this multi-variant flag. Again,
a lot of customers think of feature flags as
a gate to releasing new capability,
um, but you can use it for a lot more than that.
Um, I'm gonna take off the hat of the
Lambda latte, uh, uh, coffee
shop owner and talk to you a little bit about some other
feature flag use cases.
Um, so again, the idea of
a release flag is mostly what people think
about feature flags. I'm going to have my code
hide the functionality behind some sort of a
toggle,
um, and then I'm going to deploy the code,
but nobody can get to it because the toggle is off.
Then I'm gonna turn it on slowly. That's
really important that I'm gonna turn on for 1% of
my fleet or 1% of my audience. You have
configurable options for that.
And over time I'm going to increase that
10%, everything's going well, 20%
everything's going well, 40%, 0 my gosh, something
went wrong and we do see this inside of AWS
sometimes that you don't see these problems until you really
start to hit a scale
so again the idea of just a
culture of I'm going to develop
quickly but release slowly is really
important when you're using feature flags.
So that's sort of a release thing
um I'll tell you one of the big, I I think I
said app config is the feature flagging
solution for
Amazon and AWS. It's how we think
you should use feature flags.
Um, one of the big weeks, uh, this
week is a really big week for app config
when. People are on stage announcing something announcing
this new capability that coders actually
pushed to production a couple weeks ago,
but it was all hidden so you couldn't access it.
Then feature flags are being flipped as Matt Garman
is on stage and Peter DeSantis is on stage
to make sure that that thing lights up,
um, so it's a, it's a great tool,
uh, to, to sort of control and you
know the engineers are not like sitting there trying to do
CICD deployments while Matt Garman's talking.
The code's already out there and all they do is a small feature
flag deployment.
Um, the other
big thing, a big week for us is actually
last week.
Last week was Black Thursday in the United States. It's
a really big shopping week, and on Amazon.com,
what's that? Black Friday, sorry, the,
the day after Thanksgiving, Black Friday is a really
big shopping day,
and Amazon.com uses app config
to, uh, control during peak events.
So if you bought something,
sometimes who's bought something on Amazon.com, most people
will raise their hand.
Um, if you bought something, you always
see people that bought this also
bought this, and it's a really cool suggestion,
and most of the time it's appreciated.
Well, if you're on Black Friday,
you're gonna still notice that, but you might
only see 3 suggestions of
things that you might wanna buy
instead of the normal 5 to 7 things
and you can imagine why that might be on a peak event
when people are using the website a lot we
wanna actually have less expensive queries
to the back end and get 3 different things. So that's
more what we call an operational flag.
So the first one is that release flag and,
and, and Ben demo that.
There's something that we use app config all the time for
called an operational flag
that allows you to respond quickly
to things on production.
I can have something like a throttling
limit. So if you have
an application that's a bad actor.
Um, and you, sorry, you,
you have, you have an application where you have a bad actor
that's messing around with your infrastructure or whatever
and you wanna just block that account ID.
You don't wanna have to push out a code change
to block that, let that go through your CIC. That could
take minutes or hours for it to go
through, um, a code deployment.
You wanna be able to respond to that immediately.
And so using configuration data and
then ops flag to allow
certain customers or block certain customers is a common
use case as well, and you can just push that out immediately
block that person.
Um, another, uh, use case
we see is like you might want to throttle the number of
background processes that are operating at peak time.
I used to work at a company where
at the end of every quarter there needed to be a lot of
reports generated for our customers so the customer
could click a button and generate reports,
and we wanted that report to be as
quickly as possible in the customer's hands, but
since it was the end of the quarter, every quarter
people
all on the same day would be requesting
that and so we basically had a queuing system.
That we would turn on with a feature flag that says, hey, I
want to queue these requests and then I'll email them a copy
of the report rather than generate it real time for them.
So again, a great way to operationally handle
what's going on.
Um, from, I think we have
something about in our abstract about like
responding to security events quickly.
So another use case we see a lot by our customers
and inside of Amazon is the
uh toggling of the verbosity
of your logging.
So you normally are going to be running your login
of course at at info level, but something
might be going wrong. You're not sure and
you want to get a lot more information so you can
actually flip with a feature flag or an
operational flag,
uh, the verbosity from info
to debug,
and Ben, I know you have a demo on that, right?
Yep, OK, great. We can take a look at that. Great, thanks. All
right, um.
OK, again, so the, the previous two
demos were about what we call release flags,
where you're controlling the release of some kind of feature,
uh, question, yeah, go ahead.
You might end up on a lot of that,
so say some of the problem with that.
people I'm
having a little bit of trouble hearing you.
So say there might be a
situation we might end up with a lot of
release flags,
stale release flags and clean up,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's the case. If I have to do a cleanup,
I mean, I can turn it off here.
Maybe there is a feature here,
but should I make code changes to
clean it up there as well for a specific,
say, in this case it's la.
Yeah, a lot of that,
but I won't use it in future for him really.
I just need one specific feature. I turn it
on. That's all,
right? So
if I have to do a cleanup,
do I have to do a clean up in the code because I
was not sure
the end point. Right,
right, so the question is if I have these flags that
I have been around for a while and I'm not using them anymore,
sure I can delete them from app config, but do I also need to go
clean up my code? Is that the question?
Yes, um, the answer,
do you have to clean up the code? Technically
no, but it is highly, highly recommended, right,
because over the course of time
you're, you know, fundamentally when you're adding a feature
flag to your code, you're adding a branch.
In your logic, right? And so if you, if
time goes on and you end up with hundreds or in some
cases thousands of feature flags and you have thousands
of unnecessary branches in your code, it's
just, it's ripe for disaster someday, right?
Developers gonna come in and they think they're changing something
unrelated, but really they change how
feature flags evaluated and then your application just starts
behaving unexpectedly.
So yes, as far as the cleanup story goes,
yes, you can delete them from app config. We also
recommend deleting,
uh, or cleaning up rather your code where
you introduced that branch,
right? And do you mind showing
the little short term flag as we have a
little mechanism in the console here that you can
see. So if I create a new.
Feature flag by clicking this add new flag
button. I'll do a basic flag
and we have this box here that's called this is a
short term flag
and so when I do this, you know, at the time that I'm creating
my future flag, I can say hey this is a short term flag.
And I have a target deprecation
date of, uh, let's say end of Q1.
And so now when I, you know, I'm
looking at my list of flags in my app config account, I
can sort by deprecation date and I can see, oh,
these are the ones that I,
I don't, I shouldn't be using anymore. I said I wouldn't be
using it by this date, so let me go check on that and see if I
should clean that up.
Yeah, app config won't delete that flag
on your behalf. That'd be really risky for the
service to do,
but it will remind you that you have
quote unquote overdue flags that you wanna go look at.
We know that when an engineer creates a flag, they
have a guess about when it will be deprecated,
but it's not a super reliable, so it just
uses a kind of a reminder system,
yeah. I don't know if you have this set up in your
demo, but basically in the console,
you, if you're using the console, you can see overdue
flags. You can filter for overdue flags. You
can also do that on your own, uh, you know, everything you
see in the console is obviously available
via API and cloud formation and terraform, etc.
so you can look at that data too.
So the, the logging value is an
interesting one, and this is a problem that we've had where
developers have turned on debug logs
and we forgot
and then it ends up blowing up like our,
our logging, our logging, yeah,
so. If this
is a solution for that and you set this,
they won't necessarily turn it back off.
Correct. I mean, depending on the, depending on the
use case, you hear that a lot at AWS,
um, depending on the use case,
if you wanna have logging on for, you know,
a couple of months,
then I think this could be kind of helpful to remind
you, hey, you, you should update this flag.
If you are just turning on for a couple of hours, I
don't think this would be a good application. You probably need a
different mechanism for,
um, for flipping that.
Another question over there, sir.
by welcome you. When
you create a flag, can you create a what? Yeah, that's,
that's part of the metadata here on this creation screen,
yeah. for
that. Your code does
not have access to this value.
It's just in the app config control plane where
you can see this, yeah.
That's correct. You could of course add an attribute
that we talked about earlier and just put it in there too,
but yes, the, the deprecation date, this field strictly
is not included in the response,
yeah. Yeah, we,
we talked about it quite a bit as a service team
about how we would want to have customers
use it and it's it's just it's
too risky to have uh people just
automatically are putting a process in to delete a
flag. Um, so we
purposely chose to not expose that down into the
agent. Yeah, we actually have a
somewhat new feature that we released that we call deletion
protection. So if you go try to delete, you know, any
kind of config, app config obviously supports feature
flags. We also support what we call free form
config, which is bring your own config data. We
don't care what the format is. You just give us the data and we
manage the versioning and the deployments,
um. In that case,
we, if you go try, you know, we track your
usage of it or track the requests that you're making
for it, and if, if you try to delete that config
and we say, oh we actually you hadn't, you have live traffic
on this thing, then by default we'll say, hey, you can't delete
this unless you click the I know what I'm doing button.
For example, we don't have that for individual flags at this
point in time, we do have it at the config level,
right? OK, let's
do the logging verbosity demo and then we'll come back
to uh more questions if there are any.
So I'm going back to my lambda latte config and we're
going to take a look at our 3rd and final flag,
which is called log level.
This flag has an attribute
called level, and
of course right now it's set to info.
Actually, before I change this, I'm going to go back to the lambda
latte application and pull up
the uh logs.
So let's take a look at the
JavaScript console here, there's, I just cleared
it out, so there's nothing here. You can see it's not printing
anything right now, nothing interesting is happening.
What I want to do is go in and edit my flag
and change this to.
Debug
and you'll notice another thing about app config
feature flag attributes is that they
allow you to add constraints to them.
So in this case, I've said, hey, this is a string.
And I don't want any values
to be allowed except the ones that I'm that I've defined
here, so we call an enum.
It also supports regular expressions.
So if I come in here, you know, and I'm,
I'm, I'm, uh, debugging
something at 3 in the morning and I want to flip the logs and
I'm just trying to do this quickly and I'm half awake and I accidentally
put a space in here, and the app can make is gonna tell me, hey, you,
you can't do that because it doesn't match the enum, right? So it's
another convenient,
uh, or powerful feature of, uh,
attributes or constraints.
So let's turn on debug logging. I'm gonna update my future
flag and deploy it.
So we'll start that deployment and then I'll come over
to my console and I'll expect
in the next couple of seconds for my debug logs to
come in, which are gonna show like, hey, I'm
about to make a request for this user
to the back end.
Here's how the back end responded. I'm about to make a request for this
user to the back end, here's how the backend responded. This is
happening, I think it's every 5 seconds that this is happening,
and you can see these are my, my debug logs.
And then of course when I'm done I can go turn it back off.
Um, if you're worried about forgetting about turning debug logs
off because it can get quite expensive over the course of
time. Something that you could do is
set up like a a
cloud watch
alarm so you could emit a metric on your log level,
and then you could set up an alarm that, you know, if, if
your log level stays uh something
more granular than info for, I don't know,
12345 hours, whatever it is, then
that alarm can go red to alert you're on call so
you know, oh, we forgot to turn that thing off. So that could
be one strategy for
remembering to turn this back off.
OK, great. That's the ops flag
demo with a logging level use
case. We have about 10 minutes
left. We're gonna cover just the
idea if I can spend 2 minutes and we'll just have
questions, um, 2 minutes covering a couple of other things.
I said this before, but,
um, feature flags are very seductive.
People think it's no big deal just to flip a feature
flag. If something goes wrong, I'm gonna flip it back.
But you can see from. How we have set up our
service, they're very dangerous.
99.9% of the time, no problems,
but when they go wrong, things can go really wrong. If
you were around for 2017
S3 outage in US East One,
that was an extra semicolon
in a configuration change, and that was
before AP Config existed,
um, and that was part of the reason we, we launched AP Config internally.
Um, so these things
do require a kind of a culture change. It
requires caution. You should treat your configuration
like it's code and make sure that you're not just
willy-nilly pushing things to production just like you would
push untested code to production,
but they're super powerful too. Again, they allow you to
respond to things very quickly.
So, um,
two quick PSA in or one quick, um.
Uh, I do have some stickers over there and
then out in the hallway we're happy to answer questions
afterwards. Why don't we spend about 5 minutes,
uh, answering questions here
in the room in case you have some shared questions, and then Ben and
I will be outside,
uh, uh, answering questions too. So I'll also
say before we take the first question, I'm just gonna. Pull up our
final slide, which is if you want to
head out during the question section,
um, thank you for attending first of all. Second
of all, we have some resources up on the screen.
Uh, the top one is the app config user guide. So
this is what your your resource for learning about
all things app config, including the concepts that we talked
today. And then the bottom QR code
is requesting a meeting. So if you have a more, uh,
detailed use case that you'd like to talk through with us
and our team,
then feel free to use that link to request
a meeting with us.
Um, OK, I'm looking at the clock. I wanna make sure
you all have time to get to your next session or lunch or
whatever is next for you all. Um, Ben and
I will be right outside.
Um, I, I was gonna do like trivia
and give out, so I, I have some
jackets, and, uh, I don't know how I'm gonna allocate
them. Maybe first come, first served. We do have stickers
sitting over there, so grab those. There should be enough for everybody.
Also, don't forget the survey. Yeah, do the survey
and thank you all for coming.
Thank you. Enjoy the rest of your reinvent. Thank you.