- Quick show of hands.
Who here has tried to scale AI adoption
across a large organization
and found it much harder than
the blog posts make it sound?
Exactly.
Prime Video and AWS have
been right there with you.
And today, James and I are here to share
lessons, challenges, and breakthroughs
that led us from isolated AI experiments
towards AI native transformation.
I'm Lilia Abaibourova,
a technical product
manager with Prime Video.
Unlike most traditional PM roles
that focus on customer-facing features,
my role is on developer experience.
All of Prime Video
developers are my customers
and my team obsesses over metrics
like internal tool satisfaction
and average revisions per code review.
Last year, I started an AI
enablement program in Prime Video
and I'm excited to share the journey
of how we went from AI system adoption
towards AI native transformation.
So today we will start with
what we mean by AI native.
Then, James will take you on a journey
of how he accidentally sparked
a company-wide movement
of AI adoption.
I will cover organizational transformation
and measuring outcomes,
and we will end with a really fun demo.
But before, just to set the stage
a bit about Prime Video.
Here on the screen,
you see some of our global reach numbers
as well as fun highlights
from recent Prime Video
Studios original content.
We have thousands of other
titles in our catalog
from Prime Video Studios as
well as our channel partners.
And of course, we're big into live sports.
Last Friday, we streamed
an NFL football game,
two NBA games,
all running smoothly
during one of the biggest
retail days of the year.
What's behind all of these?
Hundreds of developers
innovating constantly
on behalf of our customers
and making sure everything
is working smoothly.
That scale and complexity
is where AI native transformation
can really bring massive impact.
Last year, I was here at re:Invent
and I shared a journey
of our early AI coding
assistant adoption in 2024
as it became...
as it evolved from an apprentice assistant
towards an expert assistant.
This year, we are here to
talk about the next step
in that evolution,
AI native development transformation.
But what do we mean when we say AI native?
It is fundamentally different
from the AI-assisted development process
that most organizations practice today.
Think about a typical workflow with AI.
You might get requirements for a feature
and paste them into AI chat
to brainstorm a potential
architecture approach.
Once you land on something,
you paste more context into an IDE
and write code.
Some of it is generated with autocomplete,
some of it is written by hand.
Eventually, once the feature is ready,
you might paste more
context into another tool
to create documentation
or a launch announcement.
So we use tools like autocomplete
and AI chatbots constantly,
but we use them in ad
hoc and isolated manner,
pasting context between
them all along the way.
The impact of productivity
is on individual productivity
and isolated tasks.
AI native is a fundamentally
different approach
where we reimagine how we build software.
AI tooling is embedded throughout
each step of the process
of software development
and every role, PMs,
developers, designers,
are enabled with AI.
Instead of autocomplete, we rely on agents
that can own multi-step
workflows end to end
and context is embedded and shared
throughout the tooling and infrastructure
and goes throughout teams as well.
And that's what leads
to organizational
productivity transformation.
But like all transformations,
it didn't start with a top-down mandate.
It started grassroots
with builders experimenting, sharing.
And James is here to tell
us about that journey.
- Thanks, hey there.
My name is James Hood.
I'm a principal software
engineer at Amazon.
I've been with the company for 16 years,
most of that time spent in AWS.
I did do about a five-year stint
in retail fulfillment
software in the middle,
but again, vast majority
of my time has been at AWS.
Now I am a principal engineer
and I'm also a former AI skeptic.
I don't know what your
experience has been like with AI,
but my previous experience
looked something like this.
I would see some flashy AI demo,
it would look mind blowing and exciting.
I would then try to use it myself
on real software problems
and I would find that the tools
just fell over, really struggled,
and it left me feeling very skeptical.
Now memes are my love language.
So I have this slide up here.
But if you wanna look at another way,
I was in a cycle
where this demo would spark
curiosity and excitement,
which would lead me to experiment.
I would end up with
failure or disappointment.
And then, I would be in a
skeptical state after that.
Then maybe another demo came up,
which took me around
that loop one more time.
But it doesn't take many
times around the loop
before it's really difficult
to get somebody from skepticism
back to that curiosity phase.
So what changed?
Well, a number of things changed.
Reasoning models got better,
introduction of MCP,
so different technical
innovations happened.
But for me, my big aha
moment came when I realized
that, you know, these
large language models
that back these systems,
they're kind of these
mysterious black boxes
and depending on how you
prompt them and use them.
They have these emergent behaviors
that were not intentionally designed in.
And what I realized,
I read a lot of tech articles constantly,
and I came across some articles
that describe some techniques
that I was able to reproduce.
And when you take the tools
and you combine them with the techniques,
that is this journey toward becoming
what I call a gen AI power user.
My first major success story
was using these techniques
to build a feature at the time
into Amazon Q Developer CLI.
I built a major feature into that tool.
I'm not on their team,
I'm not familiar with their codebase,
and it's written in a language
that I didn't even know
at the time,
and I went from concept to
pull request in two days,
and it went from concept to
production launch in seven days.
And I'm gonna show you
exactly how I did it.
So one of the constant narratives
that I hear around AI
is I tried to use this AI tool.
And yeah, it generated a lot
of code very, very quickly.
But when I looked at it,
I didn't like the code,
I ended up having to change it a lot.
And by the time I'd done all of that work,
maybe it was just faster
to do it myself manually.
Now the fallacy in this argument
is that essentially you
gave it a rough, vague idea
and you had to go to a very
precise implementation.
And I will tell you,
if you remove AI from that scenario
and you substitute a human in
and you do the exact same thing to them,
you're gonna get the exact same result.
That's because software
development is a process.
We have decades of experience
that to go from a rough
idea to implementation,
you have to go through a process
that requires research and
requirements clarification.
You need to design a solution,
you need to create an implementation plan,
and then you can implement,
and that's going to increase
your chances of success.
So I was able to leveraging
these techniques,
use AI as a way to speed
run me through this process.
So the first step is to
research the codebase.
I'd come up with this rough
concept for what I wanted.
I had written a little, a short doc.
I'd even shared it with the Q CLI team
and they said, "Yeah,
I think you're onto something with that."
It was a Friday.
My wife was outta town for the weekend.
I went home and it wasn't
just some like idea I had,
like this feature was really blocking me.
Like, I really wanted
to have this feature.
And I thought why not just
create a proof of concept?
So first step is to research the codebase.
So I downloaded the codebase
and, at the time, opened up Q CLI,
and I just said, what is this codebase?
And it went through and the
file system searched through
and it told me a little
bit about the codebase.
It said it has these main components
and one of 'em was the q chat component.
And I knew that was the
one I wanted to change.
So I said: Do more research
on the q chat implementation
and give me a summary.
And it did.
And I said, okay great,
create a directory called planning
and write this summary information
to a file called codebase.md.
And it did and it did a really good job.
Now I knew I wanted to
add a new slash command.
So I said: write a file
in the planning folder
called slashcommand.md
covering how slash
commands are implemented.
Include enough details so
a developer could implement
a new slash command
using this information.
And it did.
And I looked through and
did a pretty good job.
I said, great.
Researching the codebase, done,
that was five minutes.
Next step, clarify requirements.
Now this is something
I got from an article,
but I had put my rough idea
doc into this Markdown file.
And I said: Read rough-idea.md.
Ask me one question at a time
so we can develop a thorough,
step-by-step spec for this idea, kind of.
And the prompt had a
little bit more to it.
If you think I'm hiding
some magic from you
or you're eager to take
pictures of these prompts
so you can copy and paste them,
I have a demo that is coming later
where you don't even
need to do that anymore.
But what this did was it turned
the agent into this partner
that would ask me questions
like it asked me, you know,
what specific problem are you trying
to solve with this feature?
And I would answer it
and it would ask me just
clarifying questions.
Sometimes, I didn't always have the answer
or I didn't always need
to have the answer.
Sometimes for example, it said,
how do you want the sub command structure
to look with this?
Do you want to use flags?
Do you want to use git style?
And well, first, it asked me the question
and I just said gimme some options.
And so then it said, okay,
you could use git style subcommands,
you could use parameters.
It gave me some options and I said,
I like that one but tweak it this way,
and that's the answer
that went into this file.
So after about 24 questions,
I realized we were getting
to the end of requirements clarification
because it started
asking me questions like,
should I implement it like this?
And it just starts
spitting code out at me.
And I said, okay,
I think we're done with
requirements clarification.
So at this point, I'm like 40 minutes in.
Again, I thought I was doing
a proof of concept at the time
so I was just kind of like quickly trying
to get through this.
So the next step is design.
And I said based on all
the planning docs so far,
created detailed design document
so a developer can immediately
begin implementation.
And it did.
And I read through that design doc.
Again, I thought it was a proof of concept
so I kind of quickly skimmed.
I went back and forth a little bit with it
and had to correct some things
and maybe made some
manual edits to it myself.
But at that point, we're
ready for implementation plan.
I'm about an hour into this process.
So again, this is something
I took from an article
and it says convert the
implementation plan.
So the design doc had an
implementation plan section
into a series of prompts
for a code generation LLM.
They'll implement each step
in a test-driven manner.
And there was more to it.
It was, you know, make sure each step
takes a meaningful step and
is kind of self-contained
and there is more to it.
But again, if you're stressing
that I'm not sharing the prompts,
I'm not trying to be secretive,
I have a much better solution
for you coming later.
But it followed what I said
and it came up with
this like 14-prompt plan
to implement step by step this feature.
I also had it generated a to-do list
so that it could keep
track of where I was.
And finally, we're ready
for implementation.
So my next step was to say,
read all the documents
in the planning folder
and implement prompt
one from the prompt plan
and update the to-do with progress.
And it did.
And then I said, great,
read the planning folder again
and implement prompt two.
And it did it.
After prompt two,
I had to figure out how
to build the package
'cause I actually didn't even,
like, I really didn't know this codebase.
So it took me a little bit
figured out how to build it,
actually had the agent
help me a little bit
with how to build it.
And once I got it building,
I was able to kinda start it up
and test a little bit.
I think I got to prompt five or so.
And the reason this context
feature was even needed
was 'cause I need,
I had to keep saying like
reread the planning folder
and I wanted a way to pin it,
pin certain files,
and that's what the context feature was.
So by the time I got to prompt five,
I was able to like start
it up with my feature.
And then, I used my feature
to build the rest of it,
which was pretty fun.
So, this was a pretty
mind blowing experience
for me to go through.
And this success,
this initial success and these techniques,
got me very excited.
And what I'll say now,
as compared to that vicious cycle earlier,
is I'm now in what I call
this AI native virtuous cycle
where I hear about something new
or I try some new technique
and I have a lot of
curiosity around these tools,
I experiment with them.
successes and failures regardless,
I share my learnings with others.
And then, one thing I
always like to point out
is that I think both the
healthy virtuous cycle
as well as the vicious
cycle involves skepticism.
I don't have to tell you
all that, you know, AI,
there's a lot of noise
around AI externally.
And so I do think that
having a healthy skepticism
is an important part
of getting in this AI
native virtuous cycle
and making sure you set your expectations
and be curious, test things out.
But don't assume just because
some things don't work,
that the whole thing is worthless.
There's really big value
to be used in these tools.
So after this experience,
I felt this tremendous sense of urgency
to spread this knowledge
across the company.
And what I did was I created
a Slack channel internally
and it's called
amazon-buildergenai-power-users.
And that channel has grown
beyond my wildest imagination.
This was just in March
that I created this.
I can't share exact numbers,
but there are literally
tens of thousands of members
of this channel with
people around the company
who it started with my
story that I had shared.
But now, we have this
massive grassroots movement
of people who are actively
working out different techniques
and sharing their learnings
and sharing different tools
and it's been an incredible experience.
One last note that I
wanna say about this story
that I told is, you know,
one differentiation I like to make
between vibe coding
versus what I was doing,
which I consider AI native
software development,
is that if all I did was say implement
prompt one through 14 and that was it,
then it would've taken
me two hours, right?
But I said it took me two days
to put up this pull request.
And as true as it is that
I don't know the language
of this repository that I was working in,
I've also been programming
for over two decades.
So while I can't fluently write that code,
I could read what was going on roughly.
I was following along
as it was implementing.
I was making-
I was going back and forth with the agent,
like questioning aspects of the code
and using, leveraging my
human judgment and experience
to make sure that we were
headed in the right direction
the whole time.
So I think that's a really
important distinction to make.
Now this movement
that happened internally in the company
and is still ongoing is,
again, very exciting.
I don't think that you can succeed
in AI native transformation
without this kind of
grassroots energy and movement
and excitement from
your builder community.
However, transformation
has to come both from-
you can't rely purely on bottoms-up
and you can't rely purely on top-down.
It's a mix of both.
And so I'm gonna hand it back to Lilia
to talk about some of the
organizational support
that was given to help continue
that transformation
based off of this energy.
- Thank you, James.
So James shared
how he sparked a grassroots movement,
but grassroots movement needs
organizational support to scale.
We found that to support
a large-scale adoption program like this,
you need three pillars:
access and infrastructure to make sure
all teams and roles
are getting access to
best in class AI tools
and there is no friction with
access to context, et cetera.
Second is culture and learning.
We learn that becoming AI native requires
this type of learning
flywheel that James showed
should become part of the culture.
And finally, trust and rigor.
So this is where we make sure that, sorry,
there are controls and governance built in
at every layer of the
stack and every process.
These three pillars reinforce each other
and we'll go deep into each one.
So let's start with AI
access and infrastructure.
Software development involves
cross-functional teams
of product managers,
designers, developers,
to take product through phases
from ideas to coding,
to deployment, operating, learning,
which is where new ideas come in.
This is the sequence we commonly refer to
as software development lifecycle OSDLC.
Up till now, AI-assisted
processes and tools
have accelerated primarily
the coding and testing
part of this process,
offering code suggestions,
generating unit tests,
spitting up individual programming tasks.
AI native methodology goes beyond coding.
It fundamentally reimagines
how we build software.
James walked us through how he used Q CLI
to clarify requirements, design solution,
and we have scaled it
from individual workflow
to team productivity.
Every phase of the software
development lifecycle
and every role has embedded AI support
with some shared tooling,
some customized tooling.
And let me just walk you through
a couple of the tools here
as some of the terminology
might be new as of recent,
Kiro is an AI native development agent.
It has both ID and CLI interfaces.
And what we've been excited about
is that it's been gaining traction
not just without developers
but also PMs and designers.
We use it for prototyping ideas
and that way we can accelerate
some of the early phases
of the software development lifecycles
so we're not blocked on engineering teams
to help us with the initial prototypes.
We also are able to use Quick Suite,
which is the business intelligence agent,
and it helps us with
researching requirements,
learning from past
experiments, analyzing data,
and quickly creating
automating agentic workflows for business.
But beyond that,
many teams have been building
tailored agents and solutions
that are more customized
for their domain codebase and problems.
So for example, we've built test agents
to be able to automate
testing and quality validation
across hundreds of devices
that Prime Video supports.
And similarly, we have
operational agents that use AI
and hundreds of data sources that we have
to be able to diagnose, troubleshoot,
and sometimes even suggest solutions
for operational issues and incidents.
And what connects all of this
is shared context and capability layer
where we use knowledge bases
and model context protocol
to make sure that all roles
can share the same context
without needing to paste it
between different steps and tools.
So for example, when a
product manager creates a spec
with an AI assistant tool
that's best for spec
requirement development,
that becomes available to
our development team in Kiro
via an MCP integration.
And then as they build
the code and merge it,
that code becomes available
to operational agents to use
as part of the context
along with metrics, logs,
and other data sources.
So how did we build this stack and enable
the context sharing all the way through?
At the foundation, we of
course built everything on AWS.
So building blocks like identity
and access management,
compute, observability.
For the model and capability layer,
it helps that AWS Bedrock has
the best selection of models,
the largest selection of
models of any cloud provider.
And we also leverage
some of the managed
solutions like for example,
AgentCore, SageMaker for our workflows.
But context matters as much
as the model quality as we talked earlier.
So MCP servers and hosts have
become our context backbone,
connecting AI tools
to up-to-date business
and technical content.
What has been key in
Prime Video is balancing
the central investments.
So for example, access to code repository
or issue tracking system
is funded centrally.
Whereas teams are building out
more specific knowledge
bases and MCP servers;
for example, access to all the
Prime Video catalog metadata
that is essential for
all the Prime Video teams
but are not necessarily
needed for other Amazon teams.
And at even more local level,
teams are building,
sharing prompts or steering files
to enable development
in the manner that you
saw James shared earlier.
And finally at the top is the experience
and tool layer where, again,
it's a mix of all the
shelf tools like Kiro
as well as customized agents
that I mentioned earlier
that teams build for their needs.
So you heard James share
his workflow re-imagination
with a development workflow.
I wanted to see if the same
infrastructure that we built
for enabling our development teams
can also help other roles
like product managers
and reinvent our workflows.
As part of our AI program,
I write a regular newsletter
with some of the new releases
both internally and externally
as well as fun success
stories that builders share.
And that process of searching
the external sources,
the internal Slack channels,
curating and editing the
manual tools used to take me
two to three hours to put
out good content out there.
I started leveraging AI
for some parts of the individual tasks,
like searching the latest stories
related to AI and development tooling,
and eventually evolved
it into agentic workflow
where I can fetch data from
internal and external sources,
build agents that can pull things
from different Slack channels,
and curate them,
and then publish everything
using a Kiro template.
So now, this helped me change this process
down to about 30 minutes
of polish and review.
But this is just one PM workflow
and we are seeing the same transformation
across teams and roles.
So things like operational
review documents, data analysis.
We are seeing PMs, TPMs, sorry,
and managers, not just
developers really engage
with the agentic
capabilities that we have.
When every role starts
reimagining their workflows,
that when we see transformation happen.
And what we need for that
is for learning and experimentation
to become part of everyday culture.
So how did we enable that?
We leaned in into the AI
native learning flywheel
that James shared earlier.
Teams learned new techniques,
experimented with workflows,
shared results widely,
and it created curiosity
and healthy skepticism
that led to the next
wave of experimentation.
That loop and not a top-down mandate
was what drove adoption that lasts.
So how did we build that flywheel?
We started with safe sandboxes.
Demo days and hackathons
where teams were encouraged
to use AI to automate parts of the process
that weren't AI native yet,
maybe building test workflows
for different devices
or automating some of
the on-call operations.
And as that started gaining speed,
we've formalized some of the mechanisms.
So some of the early adopters
became our official AI champions.
Our principal engineering community
started an AI bar raising program.
At Amazon, we use the
concept of bar raising
for calibrating interviews
and for up leveling the quality of code
and follow ups after incidents.
And so we applied the same
concept to AI maturity.
Finally, we codified best practices
into a quick start guide for teams
who were ready to move
from AI-assisted workflows
more towards AI native.
And it wasn't just the recommended tools,
but importantly techniques.
For example, maintaining
live-in architecture specs
or the spec-driven development
that you saw demonstrated earlier.
We also embedded AI reflections
as part of rituals at all levels.
So be it a team retro or an
organizational quarterly review,
we have an AI learning section,
or time allocated where we share
both successes and challenges.
And that's what becomes-
that's what makes
experimentation truly normal.
But mechanisms alone weren't enough.
We also had to be intentional
about who we reached
and what they needed to learn.
If you accelerate only
one part of the process
of one role and one team,
then you're just moving the
bottleneck somewhere else.
So if our development team became twice
as efficient and fast,
but decisions and requirements
were still following the old processes,
then the overall, we
were not really getting
more efficient as an organization.
So we needed to design a
learning path for every role
and not just teach them new
tools and prompting techniques,
but also the new ways of
working and collaborating
with each other and with AI.
So for engineering,
we've ran workshops on
spec-driven development,
technique that James shared earlier.
And then, we've also had training
on agent workflow creation.
For product managers and designers,
we were already leaning
and heavily onto AI
for writing and creating
prototypes, sorry,
and creating specs.
But with learning how
to use coding techniques
or white coding techniques;
in that case for PMs, it was okay,
we started doing prototypes as well.
Just recently, I ran a workshop
for about 50 product managers
and many of them coded for the first time.
And it was truly transformative
for them to realize
how much more power they had
to explore some of the
ideas and interactions
that they had with AI tools.
Our data teams have created interfaces
for natural language
queries from their data
so that they didn't have to be bogged down
in creating simple queries
and instead focusing on
more complex problems.
And we even trained our
leadership to use MCP
to do things like
streamline goal reporting
or querying strategic
document knowledge bases.
Speaking of MCP, model context protocol,
you'll notice that that's
highlighted in every quadrant.
So every role had to learn
how to use access and use
relevant knowledge bases and tools
via model context protocol.
And as people adopted new tools
and experimented more and shared,
we realized that in some cases,
we were moving faster than our processes
and guidelines were ready for.
So that's where trust and rigor comes in.
And I wanna start with
sharing a couple stories
from like early pitfalls
on our way to AI native transformation.
First was the code review overload.
As AI got good enough to
generate multi-file changes,
we found ourselves in a
situation where tech leads
and senior engineers were bogged down
by a large volume of large code reviews.
So even though the code
generation accelerated,
what we found is that this created
a bottleneck in the code reviews.
And to address that, we did a few things.
We leaned in
into the Amazon leadership
principle of ownership.
And as James was describing earlier,
it's not web coding,
it's really important to truly review
every line that you produce, of course.
And then, we've also built
some code review agents
that we incorporated into the workflow.
There's always a human
review that's required.
But in some cases,
we realized that we can
leverage agentic code review
for some part of the process.
And so with those changes in place,
the code review velocity
started flowing again.
Second was policy and process friction.
As teams started building more agents
and automating workflow,
sometimes fully autonomously
without even human in the loop,
agents needed access to data.
But our review processes were built
for human approvals,
not agentic approvals.
And so the innovation was slowed down
by this friction.
What we did was partnered
with our security privacy
and other stakeholders
to modernize some of the processes
and even automate some
of the governance steps.
Having learned from
these lessons early on,
we realized that rigor and
mechanisms for governance
need to be built in at
every layer of our system.
So you'll remember the AI enablement stack
that I shared a little while ago.
And so at each layer,
we've built in the right
guardrails and controls.
At our infrastructure,
we had to build in things
like capacity controls
because, of course, AI usage
can spread so quickly
without realizing it.
We've also, of course,
enabled IAM policies
and other mechanisms
that we would use for
any production workload.
And so we applied it
for our developer tooling
and infrastructure.
At the modeling and capability layer,
we've created prompt
templates, fallback mechanisms,
and rigorous evaluation sets
so that every time a new model came out
or something else changed,
we could quickly move on and adopt it
and have confidence.
At the context layer,
that was probably one of the
more challenging ones to crack.
But like enabling the right set
of authentication controls
for remote and local MCP servers
and codifying the right
approach organization-wide
has really helped us unlock
safe experimentation there.
And finally, at the experience layer,
Kiro and workflow-specific agents
enforce the right permissions
based on a combination
of single sign-on
authentication within Amazon
as well as the
service-to-service authentication
that we use for agents.
So with this controls in place,
builders didn't have to
worry about compliance
or be as tentative or uncertain
about what they can use
and what they couldn't
and the safe path became
the easy path to take.
So those were the three pillars:
access and infrastructure,
culture and learning,
and trust and rigor.
The natural question is,
did it actually work?
While I can't share the exact numbers,
I wanna be transparent about
how we measured the impact
because you can't transform
what you can't measure.
Early on, we were focusing on AI adoption.
And probably the whole first year,
we were obsessed over that number,
but eventually it got
saturated, of course,
as everyone was using AI for
those kind of isolated tasks.
So we started focusing
in our adoption metrics
on more tool-specific to
different phases, OSDLC,
adoption per roles.
So we still monitor it very closely,
but it's not just pure adoption.
And in terms of velocity
and efficiency outcomes,
we use DORA metrics,
the industry standard
metrics for velocity.
And so we've been seeing
meaningful increases
in our deployment velocity
as well as code review velocity.
But of course, it's really
important to control
for incident rates and rollback rates.
So this is something that we always
have to keep hand-in-hand
attention metrics.
But beyond those
organizational-wide adoption
and velocity metrics,
we've also dove in deeper
into specific areas
that we were trying to
change with those agents
that we built for specific use cases.
And so that's where we track things
like efficiency gains and time gains
and other metrics that
are best for the use case.
Finally, probably the
best source of insight
is really listening to our builders.
So regular surveys, interviews,
and importantly leadership
listening sessions
have been a good source for us to learn
where we can make changes
and what's working well
and what needs an improvement.
Here are a couple of quotes
from our recent engineering
round of interviews.
I'm particularly excited about the top one
where this engineer used to spend
three weeks at a minimum
on something that wasn't even coding.
So it was not the part of her job
that she was most excited about,
but it was about designing,
writing down the design documentation,
iterating with the team,
aligning with different stakeholders.
And so with AI tooling,
the writing of the document
has become done another three days.
And then, she really could focus her time
on discussing with stakeholders
for integration use cases.
And with that, it's back to James
for an exciting demo.
- All right, I think I'm
contractually obligated
to give a demo if it's
an AI talk, I don't know.
Great, so thanks so much for
taking us through all of that.
Again, it's so important, like
grassroots energy is great,
but then that structure
of organizationally
is how you really make it scale.
Now that story I told you earlier
where I was saying don't
worry about copying prompts,
we have something better.
That story was from way back
like early March timeframe or so,
and it was a story that
I shared internally
and it sparked a lot of excitement
and I got a lot of feedback
that many people found it very inspiring.
And so I thought it was
important to share that story
with you all as well.
That said, March was a long time ago,
especially in AI time.
It was a very long time ago
and we've come a long way since.
There, I'd posted an internal blog
with that whole breakdown
and there were people like copying
and pasting these prompts.
Well, we've found a much
better way to do this
and we just opened-sourced
it less than two weeks ago,
and it's called Strands Agent SOPs.
And rather than read a blog post to you,
I'm just gonna show 'em to you.
Let me log in here.
All right, so this is...
give it a minute, there we go.
This is the github repository.
SOP stands for standard
operating procedure.
What is a standard operating procedure?
Well, it's a document with a set
of detailed step-by-step instructions
that help usually a person
to do some routine task or process.
In this case, these are agent SOPs
and they help repeatedly,
repeatedly follow a
set of steps and tasks.
So I have kiro-cli pulled up here.
I'm actually in the codebase
of the Strands Agent SOP,
and I'm going to run this.
If we look at our prompts,
we have a strands-agent-sop
MCP server that we vend.
And do you remember back when I said,
what is this codebase
and explore my codebase?
Well, now I have a
agent-sop that I can run
that generates this prompt.
And now the agent says, great,
I'll help you run this
codebase-summary SOP.
There's some parameters
required codebase_path.
Otherwise, I'll default
to your current directory.
Well, that is what I want.
In this case, I'm going to tell it
to go ahead and consolidate.
So it'll generate a number of documents,
but I want to create a
consolidated AGENTS.md,
which is the default,
and that's all it needs.
So now it starts running this
standard operating procedure.
It starts reading through the codebase.
Now I wanna show you what
this actually looks like.
So a standard operating-
agent-sop is just a Markdown file,
but it's a very specific format.
It has a title.
It has an overview saying what it does.
It has this parameter section
that talks about different parameters
that this SOP can take.
And then, it has a list of steps.
You can see step one is set
up and directory structure,
initialize the analysis environment
and create necessary directory structure.
Now if I just stop there,
the agent might do different things
every time that you run it.
The magic happens with
this constraint section.
There's a constraint section
that includes these
RFC 2119 style keywords
like must all and caps or should
or should not or must not or may.
And this adds constraints
around how it should execute this step.
So in this case, you must validate
codebase_path exists.
Or in this case, analyzing
the codebase structure,
you must use Mermaid diagrams
for all visual representations.
It seems really simple,
but with this structure,
also with these steps,
you end up-
we also have an example section
because LLMs work very well with examples.
And then, there's a
troubleshooting section as well
that helps it with troubleshooting.
This format, we have found internally
the agents respond incredibly well,
like our results with just
kind of free form prompting
versus free form prompting
versus following these constraints.
The agent, we internally
lovingly call deterministic
that their behavior is kind of it strikes
the perfect balance between you want it
to follow the same procedure every time,
but you wanna leverage
the flexibility of agents.
And what we can see
is that this summary has been
running in the background
or this codebase summary
has been running in the background
and is generating these files.
So it generates this
codebase information file
that talks about the technology stack,
has the directory structure, right?
And programming languages used.
It talks about the architecture
that found in the codebase
and it uses Mermaid diagrams,
which is a very concise text-based format
that Markdown can render.
And it just generated
a new one, components.
And it's going to continue
following that SOP.
And every time you run this,
it's going to generate
the same set of documents
with the same sections in it.
Sometimes, the text is a
little bit different each time,
but it's the same critical information
because it's following this
standard operating procedure.
Now you may have been
looking at this saying,
okay, this is great,
but this seems like a big
pain to write this document.
This is very long.
There's a lot to it.
And SOPs would be a pain to write
if you had to write 'em by hand,
but you don't have to.
So the SOP program
that we vended open-source,
it offers MCP server.
It also comes with this rule embedded.
So you can say rule
and it outputs this rule
that you can use with whatever
agentic system you use.
In this case, I'm using Kiro
and so I import it as a steering file.
You don't have to worry
about reading this format.
This is just something that tells the LLM
that exact format.
And with this as a steering file,
I can then author these very easily.
So in this case,
I'm going to use this context feature
to add my steering file.
Okay, so you can see now this
agent-sop-format is there.
And just as an example,
I'm in another folder right now.
I'm going to say: Create
an agent sop that,
given a person's name,
outputs a short, fun poem
incorporating their name.
So all I have to do is chat with it.
And then, it's going to create this SOP.
It knows the format
because I put that into
its steering files.
And there you go.
So now we have this SOP
that's called Name Poem Generator.
And you can see it follows that format.
And since I have the MCP server loaded,
I'm gonna go ahead
and reload kiro-cli
and I should see my Name Poem SOP pop up.
So if I run the prompts command,
there's now this name poem.
I can run it.
Says, okay, it needs to know my name.
So I put in my name.
And then, it wants to confirm
the spelling of my name.
Yay, LLMs.
Okay, so generated some poem.
But I can also-
so I can say:
add an optional hometown parameter.
Okay, so now it's updating this agent-sop
to add this hometown parameter.
Okay, so now I'm going to run this again.
Another thing about agent-sops
is if you know the
parameters ahead of time,
first off, this-
so you notice this parameter
is called person_name
and this is called hometown.
Well, if I run this name-poem
and I pass it some arguments,
I don't, I can-
it's an LLM that's interpreting this.
So I can just say:
My name is James and I
am from Tucson, Arizona.
And it'll parse the
parameters out of that.
And look, there's my poem.
Now it's desert-themed
because I'm from Arizona.
Okay, so cute, cute demo but this is-
we want something more real world, right?
And we just wanted to show you
what the agent SOP format looks like.
However, note that I have
the github MCP server loaded
and I have access
to these different github
tools that it provides.
And so how about I say create an agent sop
that triages github issues given
a repo URL.
Little more real world.
Anyone have a github repo? Yeah?
I mean I love poems, but...
All right, so there's my SOP.
Let's go ahead and take
a quick look at it.
So it creates an SOP, takes the repo URL,
it grabs the repository info.
Fetch open issues,
says all open issues from the repository.
Analyze each issue.
And then, generate triage report.
And it says to save it to this file.
And then, present findings.
So I'm gonna say, update this:
Search for unlabeled issues.
Triaging means applying relevant labels
and adding an issue comment,
or a triage comment to the issue.
And don't write the report to a file,
just output it.
And add a dry run flag
that won't actually
make the updates
but reports what would've happened.
For demo purposes.
So I'm just able to
converse with this agent
and you can see it added the dry run flag.
It updates the SOP with
what triaging means.
And then, you can see it's
modifying these constraints
under the covers.
Now because I have the github repo,
or excuse me, because I
have the github MCP server,
you'll notice that some
of these constraints
actually name tools.
And that's because MCP puts all the tools
in context of the agent.
So when you're authoring this,
you wanna make sure you have
the MCP servers available
that it may need to use
and that'll help it create
a more effective agent SOP.
All right, so now I'm gonna run it.
Okay, it's made the updates.
I'm actually gonna run it on
the strands-agent-sop repo.
It's relatively a new repo,
so not too many issues.
And now what you'll see under /prompts
is I have this github-issue-triage.
Okay, it says great,
give me your repo_url.
And then, the dry_run flag's optional
and it defaults to false
but I'm gonna set it to true.
Okay, so now it's
triaging unlabeled issues.
So it's calling the github MCP
server's search_issues tool.
And you can see that it's
applying the no:label feature.
It's in dry run mode.
It outputted that here
and it called out a couple issues.
It said, okay, here's
a high-priority issue.
This is labels to apply:
enhancement, feature-request, mcp.
Comment to add,
and this is the comment
it was going to add.
And then medium priority,
these other two issues,
and it calls out labels
that it's going to add.
Now, if I didn't run this in dry run mode,
it would actually make
those updates to the issue.
I could also go back and forth with it
if I don't like how that's, you know,
don't like this comment
or want it to use a different style.
I can just go back and
forth with the chat.
Now this issue #22 is kind
of standing out to me.
How about we actually implement it?
So again, I'm in the agent-sop repo.
I just used my codebase-summary
that generated this super nice AGENTS.md
based off of scanning the entire codebase,
and now there's this AGENTS.md
that gets my agent up to
speed with this codebase
and understanding this codebase.
And now I'm gonna run
this thing called pdd.
This was prompt-driven development,
which was an internal predecessor
to Kiro's spec-driven development.
And this is that issue
that I was looking at.
Issue 22, I didn't create this.
This is not my user.
This is an actual feature.
Oh, a little bit of latency going on.
All right, let's try this again.
Okay, so this is an agent-sop
that takes you through that entire process
that I walked you through earlier.
So this asks for my rough idea.
So I can say rough_idea is
this link to this issue.
And then as this project directory,
this sop/planning.
So I just gave it this rough_idea.
Uh-oh, yay, for live demos.
Let's see, if I get this
again, I might have to restart.
Oh, okay, great.
So now it read my issue.
Okay, so now it knows,
it starts doing some setup.
It creates this directory structure.
So it creates this planning folder
that has design,
implementation, and research.
It took that issue and it
copied it into this rough idea.
And then it starts asking,
do you want to do
requirements clarification?
Do you want to do some
preliminary research first?
Any additional context
you want to provide?
It also tells me to run this command.
That way, it pins anything,
any documents that are created
as part of this process.
So I can say, sure,
requirements clarification.
So we'll start there.
And again, I didn't have to share some,
like copy paste some prompts,
this is something that you
can download and you can use.
So it starts writing
this idea-honing file.
And it says, okay, question one,
what's the scope of the tool?
This feature request was asking
for MCP tools in our MCP server.
So it says, this issue
mentions adding list-sops,
use-sop tools to the MCP server.
Should these tools:
A, Replace the current
prompt-based approach entirely;
or complement the existing prompts;
or be configurable.
I want both of them.
And then it'll continue.
It'll just ask me questions.
And then once we get to
logical stopping point,
I can tell it to move ahead to design.
I can tell it to go to
an implementation plan
and I would absolutely do that for you.
But we are out of time.
- [Audience 1] Quick
question, if you don't mind?
- Just a second.
But if you're interested in seeing me
implement that entire feature,
you should come to our code talk
or you should come to my
code talk later today,
which is happening,
which is talking about how Amazon teams
use AI assistance to
accelerate development.
And it's ambitious,
but I'm gonna try to implement
the whole feature on stage.
So it'll be exciting either way.
Come see that this afternoon.
We also have a session being given
by Eva Knight and Bethany Otto,
and they have done a lot of work
on kind of how they
measure the impact of AI
across the company.
So that's another good one to catch.
We also have a QR code for
the agent-sop github repo.
So you can download it,
you can try it for yourself,
you can give us a star,
it would be fantastic.
But with that, we're at time.
Really appreciate your time
today and thanks so much.
(audience applauding)