- Hi everyone, and welcome to DEV 415
where we are gonna look at
how to build scalable,
self-orchestrating AI workflows
with A2A and MCP.
My name is Gunnar Grosch,
I am a developer advocate at AWS.
- And my name is Allen Helton.
I'm an AWS serverless hero
and an ecosystem engineer at Momento.
- So, this is a 400-level session,
so we're gonna assume that
you know some things about AWS
and certain things about the
services we're gonna use,
but we are specifically
gonna focus on a few things.
For instance, the
agent-to-agent protocol, A2A,
MCP, Model Context Protocol,
and some of the specifics
around the services
we're using to build these agents.
And we're gonna do it by
showing a lot of the concepts.
We're gonna jump in
and show some demos as
well all throughout.
So, this is basically,
what we're gonna cover.
How you can design these
self-orchestrating systems
using choreography instead
of central control.
We will look at, like I said,
the A2A protocol and MCP.
How you can use that so they
can discover each other, these agents,
and how they can do that
and invoke each other in a dynamical way.
And then how MCP gives
agents the consistent way
to access tools, context, and data.
And then finally, how AgentCore and Lambda
can turn these agents into
autonomous, scalable workloads.
- Okay, so why are we here?
Why is there even a session
on this in the first place?
Well, if anyone here has used AI agents
before generative AI,
we should already know that generative AI
doesn't really follow linear playbooks.
It's kinda the Wild West.
You never know what you're gonna get.
Reasoning jumps based on context,
definitely not on your code.
So, we need to prepare for that.
And every single task
that you give an AI agent
can potentially take a different path,
even if you call it multiple
times with the same context.
And so, because of that, that
whole paradigm in general,
static wiring with traditional
orchestration services
don't really work the same way.
So, what we need is to break out agents
and we need to have agents
that talk to each other,
agents that collaborate
with each other at runtime.
Ones that can adapt workflows safely
and ones that have stable outcomes,
even if their reasoning
isn't always right on track.
And this really can be
boiled down to the debate
of choreography versus orchestration.
And it is, it is kind of, kind of.
Choreography is powerful,
but if you've ever used it,
it can be a little bit
tricky when you start
introducing non-determinism
in your structure.
And as much as we'd like to think
that coordinating agents is
just this ideal pie in the sky,
it's a lot like a game of telephone,
if you've ever played that.
Where each agent along the chain
adds its own interpretation
instead of clarity on the
commands that came in.
And so, these small little deviations
compound into major workflow errors
or very, very different outcomes,
if you don't set it up right.
Maybe you have the wrong
collaborator inside of a workflow
or you have the wrong action,
either way, you're gonna
get the wrong outcome,
which is really what
we're concerned about.
Collaborating on a shared
plan, separating that work out,
is really what we're looking for.
So, if you don't have that,
which sometimes can be
seen in choreography,
you're not gonna be able
to reproduce results.
You're not gonna get consistent outcomes
inside of your complex workflows.
So, debugging and when you're
actually in production,
practical considerations means that
you have to reconstruct a he
said she said kind of deal,
and that's very difficult.
So, what we're here today
really to talk about
is that autonomy without rules is chaos.
Absolute sheer and utter
use case for no success.
And that's why we're
gonna be talking about
deterministic coordination
and really hounding on determinism
in a non-deterministic paradigm.
- So, we're gonna jump
straight into our first demo.
Before we dive into actually,
using multi-agent coordination,
we're gonna start with one
single autonomous agent.
So, that gives us all a
clean baseline basically,
to see how agent in the loop in action
without anything else involved.
So, think of this as kind
of a warmup to it all then.
One task, one agent,
and one clean workflow.
So once you understand how this works,
I think a lot of the
things around multi-agent
will become much easier
to understand as well.
So, this is the first demo.
We're looking at a, think
very common situation
in the last mile delivery.
Driver arrives at a customer's address
to drop off a package,
but the customer isn't home.
So, instead of turning this
into a manual exception
that someone has to follow up on later,
we want the system to take
the next step automatically.
So, the moment the driver reports
that the delivery
attempt was unsuccessful,
the agent will then
evaluate that situation.
And this scenario is
intentionally very simple.
It shows how one single agent
can then react to these real-world events,
interpret what it means,
and take an appropriate next action.
So, like I said, it's there to
give us a baseline for this.
So, Allen, take it away.
- [Allen] Okay.
So, here we have our
delivery driver web portal.
This is what they look at
whenever they are unable
to deliver a package.
And this is for my logistics
company, Swift Ship,
number one competitor to amazon.com.
And as you can see here, we're not,
we don't have chat interfaces,
really we're just filling out a web form.
We're gonna say that the customer
is not available for delivery.
We'd left a notice on their mailbox,
and we'll attempt redelivery tomorrow.
This is this scenario I imagine
many of us have run across before.
Very frustrating, but
it is a fact of life.
It's what we're gonna see here
is a peek behind the curtain
for what is actually,
happening behind the scenes.
And you can see here that,
and this is updating in
real time by the way.
So, you can see here that
we're gonna schedule that order
for delivery with our
order management agent
and then we're gonna notify the customer
of that rescheduled delivery.
Now, like you said, this is
an intentionally simple demo.
Probably the most boring
one you'll see this week.
- Underwhelming, I think is the word.
- Underwhelming, yes,
that's the word I was
definitely looking for.
The word I used to describe all my demos.
But the point there is that
that's an agentic workflow
that is about as simple as it gets
and it has run through everything
that we are about to talk about.
- Yeah, so before we start
wiring these agents together,
we need to align on some
of the technical primitives
that make these autonomous systems viable.
So, these aren't high-level
concepts, they're mechanisms
that then keep these multi-agent
workflows deterministic,
like Allen talked about, and reliable.
So, if these foundations aren't solid,
well, choreography is
gonna break down quickly.
So, let's look at some of
these foundation to begin with.
And I've mentioned agent to agent,
A2A protocol a couple of times.
And that is what gives our agents
a consistent way to discover each other,
and then also to collaborate.
Each agent they publish an agent card
that defines its capabilities
and the version of each
capability that it has,
and the input schemas
that it's gonna expect.
In our architecture, we are
using these capabilities
and exposing them through
Lambda function URLs,
you'll see that later.
It means that each agent is reachable
through just standard HTTP endpoints.
And when one agent needs another
to perform some sort of work,
it is then just gonna create
a typed A2A invocation.
And this invocation includes
the capability name,
the version, the task identifier,
and some sort of structured JSON payload
that then conforms to that schema
that was a advertised in the agent card.
Then, we had Model Context Protocol, MCP.
And that's, I think most
people now know what it means.
It feels like it's been around for ages.
It turned one year a month ago?
- Yeah, if even.
- Something like that.
So, but it feels like it's
something we all know by now,
but MCP provides us with
this standardized way
for agents to load context
and interact with tools.
Instead of passing raw
text or unstructured data,
agents can call these MCP tools
that expose typed validated interfaces.
So, that could be shipment
data, order information,
it could be inventory levels,
other types of workflow inputs
that are all retrieved
through these tools.
So, MCP is what ensures
that every interaction follows a schema.
That removes ambiguity-
- Nice.
- and improves the reliability
of model reasoning.
So, MCP tools, they define
these strict input and output shapes.
Agents will then always work
with predictable structures.
And that's super important,
because it means that the
behavior of the system
remains stable even when multiple agents
are relying on that same data.
And then we have our
core services, of course,
and the system is built on
three core system or services for us.
Together that then support
these autonomous agents.
The agents themselves in our architecture,
they're gonna run as
standard Lambda functions.
So, nothing strange about that.
Each Lambda execution is isolated,
which means that every Agent
Loop starts with a clean state
and it loads exactly the state
that it needs to have once it's invoked.
So Lambda, as we all know,
it gives us elasticity,
it's predictable concurrency behavior,
so the things we need to be able
to build these scalable systems.
We have Bedrock AgentCore as well
and we're using two capabilities
within Bedrock AgentCore.
We're using memory and we use
observability for our agents.
So, since Lambda doesn't have any
built-in state between invocations,
we are using AgentCore memory
as a way to store and
retrieve task information.
And that gives us a consistent view
of what has already happened
basically within that workflow,
even when multiple agents are contributing
and collaborating on the same
tasks at different times.
And then we're using Momento,
that's where Allen works.
Momento is our,
I think we can call it our
fast coordination layer.
It's using this Momento
cache for lightweight state.
Cashed MCP tool responses
and quick lookups
to do things that really don't belong
in any durable or long-term storage.
So, this gives us low latency
access to shared information
without slowing down
that entire Agent Loop
that we'll look at.
So, those are our three main components.
- And before we go any further,
we've talked about what we're building,
but now we're gonna talk about
what specifically we're gonna be building.
In order to do that,
I kinda wanna take you
three years back in time
when ChatGPT was first introduced.
It was a marvel at the time
and looking at it now is still
great, but it is a chat bot.
I ask it something, it responds to me,
I ask it something else,
it responds to me again.
And that's really the
extent of the exchange
I can have with a chat bot.
Fast forward a little bit,
and the Model Context
Protocol releases last year
and agents started booming,
everybody started making agents.
Now, what's the difference
between an agent
and what we were doing with ChatGPT?
Well, an agent, it's basically a chat bot,
but it's been empowered to do something.
It's been given code via tools
that it can actually go and
do things on your behalf.
So, if you say, go book me
a flight or what, you know,
where can I go to buy a
pineapple for my pizza?
It'll look it up, say, "Oh
that's on Maui probably.
Let me book you a flight
there," and it'll do that.
It'll actually do that, but
as part of that exchange.
But that's really not it.
That's not what we're building today,
because that's still a chat interface.
I'm talking to it, it's
talking back to me,
but it's also doing things too.
But what we're talking about
today is autonomous agents.
These are agents that you can't see.
These sit behind and are placed
inside of your architecture.
Ones that hopefully, you're
already pretty familiar with.
That run async in the background
that never see humans.
These are responding to
events in your system.
These are actually, responding
to things that happen.
So, in a very basic situation,
really what the Swift Ship
delivery system is doing for us
is inputs come in via API gateway.
There's a compute layer,
sometimes with Lambda, goes to DynamoDB
and from there we can
execute our async workflows
with something like EventBridge
that then passes all the data necessary
to an agent maybe running in Lambda
that responds to that specific event.
So, very different from a chat bot
that has been given a tool.
This is something that's interacting
as a result of something
happening in your system.
- So, the autonomous agents
that you'll see here today,
they are built on what
we call the Agent Loop.
It's a very simple,
but yet very powerful
way to look at agents.
And I think once you
understand the Agent Loop,
a lot of the entire architecture
makes a lot of sense straight away.
So, the Agent Loop is the execution model
that every agent should follow basically.
No matter where it runs,
if it's in Lambda as a Lambda function,
if it's running in
AgentCore, or in a container,
or in EC2 instance anywhere.
This loop isn't tied to a
specific compute service.
It's more of a discipline
of how to build these autonomous agents
so that they behave predictably at scale.
So each iteration of the
loop, it looks the same.
We start with the Compose phase,
it loads its typed
context through MCP tools
and retrieves tasks state
from AgentCore memory for instance.
Then we move on to query
where we call the model.
And in our case that's using Bedrock
where we call the model through.
And that gives us a structured tool result
and a schema-aligned output.
Then we have the Execute phase
where we actually do something,
and that maps that structured output
from the LLM to real actions.
Those could be A2A in vocations,
it could be an API call,
or memory updates for instance.
And then we have a question,
should we continue the
loop or are we done?
So, we decide whether
the workflow is complete
or if we should persist state
and then run another iteration of it.
So, by following this
pattern consistently,
each one of our agents,
they become re-entrant,
they become even potent,
and they are safe to run
in a distributed system.
So, let's break down these phases
to look more exactly
what that actually means.
So the first one Compose,
that's the phase where we
transform an incoming event
into a deterministic input package
for each or for the model.
So, even though our agents
run as Lambda functions,
like we've said, this loop
structure is platform agnostic.
And in Compose, the first thing
we do is we hydrate context
through for instance MCP tools.
And these tools enforce strict
schemas and validation rules.
And the agent always begins
with types structured data
instead of having loosely
formatted prompt text,
like in a chat for instance.
So after that, the agent
reconstructs any prior task state
that it might have from
AgentCore memory in our case.
And because Lambda
functions are stateless,
this is what makes the loop re-entrant.
Every iteration will
lo load its own history
and the context instead of
relying on warm function state.
And once the data is assembled,
we start building that
system prompt that we use,
and we follow something
called the RISEN framework.
And this creates a stable contrast
for the model and its behavior.
The role section defines exactly
what the agent is responsible for.
So, it stays focused on its role.
Instructions specify how
the model must behave
and that includes constraints
and error handling rules.
Then steps outline the
deterministic procedure
that each agent follows
on every iteration.
And then expectations that
describes the precise output shape
that the model must return,
and that's anchored in the same schemas
that our code will validate.
And then finally narrowing.
It makes the agent's boundaries explicit
by stating what it must not do.
So, to make it even more clear,
this is a simplified version
of the system prompt used
by one of our agents.
And it's structured as you
can see according to RISEN.
So, when you read through
it through that lens,
it becomes clear that it's not just
a block of descriptive text for the agent,
it's a behavioral contract
that it must follow.
So, we have the role
for the specific warehouse
management agent,
we have the instructions,
we have the steps,
what are the steps for
it, what it should do.
Then we have the expectations,
what it's supposed to do,
and then narrowing,
making sure that it stays
within its boundaries.
And at this stage of the Compose phase,
the agent is not only building
its system prompt using RISEN,
it's also reconstructing its
understanding of the task
by loading state from AgentCore memory.
And since every Llamda vocation
starts in that clean
environment, like I said,
the agent depends on this memory
to be able to restore the
context of the workflow.
And it includes previous decisions,
intermediate results,
correlation identifiers,
and any other types of events
that are generated during
earlier steps in the workflow.
So, AgentCore memory, it is
structured and it's queryable.
So, the agents loads
that specific name spaces
instead of pulling out
big blobs of opaque text.
So, this allows the agents
to then build its prompt
in a deterministic way.
So, the memory is also
optimized for reentry,
which means that the agent
can safely then resume work
even if the previous
invocation perhaps timed out
or had some sort of retry as well.
And agent discovery is in this system
it is driven entirely by A2A
and it's using something
called agent cards.
So, tiny JSON text, you
don't need to read it really,
but this is a document that is
the authoritative description
of what an agent can do.
It is machine-readable capability surface.
So, instead of us hard
coding these RPC calls
or maintaining some sort
of registry for our agent,
instead every agent will
publish this capability card
at a well-known path,
and then when another agent
needs to delegate work,
it fetches these cards,
interprets the capabilities,
and decides how to interact
based on the contract the card exposes.
So, it defines the name of the agents,
its purpose, the actions it supports,
and the schemas for input
and outputs of each action.
We have a more visualized
way of showing it as well,
like a proper card.
This is something Allen hacked together.
I think you have it available
so people can see it at the
end as well in the resources.
But it's kind of a friendlier way
of representing these agents
and these cards in the same information.
Turning that JSON into a
capability graph basically,
that shows the actions
that the agents supports
and how those actions fit
into the larger workflow.
- Okay, so you've assembled
all of this context,
you've built the system prompts,
you have fetched additional
data to build the user prompt,
you have loaded agent cards into memory,
you've done everything
that you need to do.
Now, it's time to feed
that all into an LLM,
but it's not that simple
unfortunately never is,
because models vary wildly
in their output and their behaviors.
I asked two different
LLMs the same question.
All, you know, related
of course to Swift Ship
when we were doing our
interviews for LLMs,
and just gave it a prompt,
what would you do in this situation?
And I asked a LLM that's known
to be very clear, very
blunt, Cohere, command R,
and it gave me a blunt answer.
And then I asked a model, it's
a little bit more capable,
does some more reasoning.
It's not quite as blunt, and
it gave me a longer answer,
and probably a better answer
for the situation that I am using it for.
So, the model differences here,
they're not just stylistic.
Really, they have to fit the scenario
that you're building for,
and that will ultimately end up shaping
how the loop behaves,
because it's going to be responsible
for planning out a multi-step workflow.
And speaking of that,
this is about time where we branch into
something a little bit deeper with A2A.
Where we introduce two
different types of agents
used primarily with A2A and
multi-agent collaboration.
We have supervisors and we have workers,
very much like an engineering team,
exactly like a tech lead or a manager,
and individual engineers that
are actually doing the work.
So, the supervisors and the
workers, they run the same loop,
but they have very different needs.
And when it comes down to
which model you're selecting,
very different model
capabilities that they require.
Supervisors are kind of that orchestrator.
They need to know everything.
They need to be responsible
for global reasoning.
So, a multiple planning out multiple steps
in a long workflow.
They need to be capable
of dependency resolution.
So, what do I need in
order to satisfy this,
or given the agent cards
that I've been presented,
who do I need to call to
do this step or that step?
And also, they need the ability
to be able to judge an
output from a worker.
Is this good enough?
Does this satisfy the reason
why I called you in the first place?
Workers on the other hand are,
to put it simply, the grunts.
They need to run fast,
they need to run cheap,
they need to run deterministically,
and they need to be really schema perfect,
meaning, if I tell you, you need to
have these parameters
to operate this tool,
you need to use those
parameters to operate that tool.
So, when we're thinking about
this phase in the Agent Loop querying,
really there's model selection,
but there's also agent selection.
So, you have multi-layer reasoning
for what you're looking
for with the query.
So, that's why you have for supervisors
more reasoning capable
models, like Nova Pro,
or there is a Nova Premier
in one of our rehearsals.
I said that and Gunnar laughed at me,
'cause he didn't think that was real,
or you know, Sonnet, or opus 45,
ones that are really
capable of strong reasoning
versus ones that are workers
that do very specific things.
So, you could do like Nova Canvas,
if you're drawing an image,
or one of the Sonnet,
or the Haiku, smaller,
lighter models that you need.
Something just real quick and real fast.
Okay.
- I don't like you calling me out.
So, all right, we've composed
and we've now queried the LLM
and now it's time for phase three
where we actually, do
something in the end.
And like in our previous demo,
now we can do some sort of simple action
where we turn the model output
into real effects in the system.
And the first step, of
course, is schema validation.
We need to make sure that
the expected output shape
from that RISEN prompt and everything
that doesn't conform to that
is gonna be rejected basically.
This protects the system
from malformed model output
and any type of partial structures
or drift across retries.
Once the output is validated,
the agent is then gonna
perform the action described.
And for instance, that could
be updating a database,
it could be calling an API,
it could be writing to DynamoDB,
updating state in AgentCore memory
publishing event or anything else.
Every action should use item potency keys
that we derive from the task ID.
So retries shouldn't be able
to create any duplicate side effects.
Most of the time,
Execute produce some sort
of concrete system update.
But in some cases, the
action the model request
isn't a local update.
Instead it's gonna be a handoff.
When the model indicates
that another agent
should take responsibility
for the next step,
Execute isn't gonna
perform the work itself.
Instead, we're gonna look
at A2A agent invocation.
So, Execute has now determined
that the next action
isn't any local update,
it's gonna be a handoff to another one.
So, we've composed a prompt,
we've queried the LLM,
we're trying to execute something,
and this agent can't do
that thing themselves.
So, what happens then instead
is that we construct an A2A payload
that encodes the capability of version,
the required typed input,
and the task identifier.
And this is gonna conform
to that A2A protocol.
So, the specification of the protocol
tells what this message
is gonna look like.
The receiving agent is then gonna know
exactly what to do when it receives it.
So, we then publish this message
and that's gonna launch
an entirely new Agent Loop
where we start off with
composing, we're querying,
we're performing some sort of action,
and that could be a local one,
or it could once again spin off
to a new Agent Loop to do something.
Then it decides if it should continue.
And if that one is done,
we're closing that loop,
reporting that it's done,
and can do the same decision
on that initial loop as well.
So, this is how we get that
distributed, scalable and
deterministic behavior
without having any central orchestrator.
The agents define if they need
to launch a new Agent Loop.
- All right, phase four.
Let's close the loop on closing the loop.
(Allen chuckling)
We're gonna again talk about
supervisors and workers here,
'cause this is actually,
a really important piece.
And before I go into details
on continuing the loop,
I wanna talk about where we are in code,
not gonna show code, but we're
just gonna talk about it.
So, if I've written an agent,
phase one is composing the prompts.
This is actually, code that you write
in your applications that's loading data,
it's assembling string.
We've curated the LLM,
that could be the Bedrock
converse API invoke agent,
whatever it is.
We've done Execute action.
As far as the code goes,
we're still in that converse call.
And now we're on phase four,
which is continuing the loop.
We're still in that call.
So, we haven't received a response yet.
This is still in the
capabilities of that converse
or invoking the actual agent.
And what it's doing here,
it's done work and it's asking itself,
do I have enough information
to finish the task that I'm working on?
And based on whether or not
it's a supervisor or a worker,
it's gonna evaluate different things.
The supervisor, of course,
has its global perspective.
What was the original
hierarching task at the top?
What was the command that came in?
What's the event that I'm responding to
that I need to satisfy?
It looks at the results
from the other agents.
Basically, the output from
the tool calls it made
when it invoked the sub-agent Loops.
And then it's also considering
the unmet capabilities
that track back to that
global parent task.
It's doing things like validating
the schemas returned by the workers.
Is this actually, what I asked for?
Does it have everything that I need?
And what it's doing here
is it's figuring out,
do I need to call more agents?
Do I need to wait for some to respond?
Maybe it's gone async and I need to wait,
or am I actually done
and I can really continue
on with the code?
So, that loop's gonna continue.
So, if that answer is I need to do
one of the first things,
it will go back and it will
build that system prompt again.
It will execute actions.
It will do everything that it needs to do.
The worker, it's roughly the same thing,
but its scope of what it's
concerned about is tighter.
It's a little bit smaller,
because it's not doing as much work,
it's not doing the planning,
it's figuring out, you know,
did I satisfy the individual
work item that came in
and the A2A terminology, that's a message.
There's a task that goes
across all the agents
and then there's individual messages
that go to the sub-agents.
Did I do what the message
said for me to do?
Yes, cool.
Maybe I need to run some more
tools and do some more work.
Maybe I need to validate the results.
Again, this is before you get
a response back in your code.
And so, it's gonna go
and it's gonna decide,
do I need to refine my results?
Do I need to do it again
for that one very specific requirements?
Okay, I think it's time.
- It is time.
- We're gonna talk,
we're gonna make things
a little bit harder
for the Swift Ship delivery
and set it up first.
Build it up, build up the excitement.
Now, we've seen firsthand a single agent
can satisfy a simple prompt,
Customer wasn't home, I
left them on the door,
I'm gonna reschedule it.
Cool, that's not exciting.
Versus Reinvent, we have exciting things
that we're gonna talk about
and I know I'm not supposed
to spoil what the scenario is.
So, I'm not gonna talk about that.
But what I am gonna talk about
is why we need multiple
agents specifically,
and what you don't want, actually, first,
show of hands, does everybody
know what a monolith is?
There's a lot more of you in here.
I can't see you with the lights.
Okay, everyone knows what a monolith is.
Are they good? No.
Okay, all right.
So, there's a new term on the streets.
They call it a mono agent,
and it's an agent that does everything.
It has access and the capabilities
to access your payment systems,
to access your ordering services.
Has access to everything in the database.
Think that's a good thing?
Nah, it's not, it's not.
What we need to do is
we need to scope agents
down to specific domains.
And in the case of Swift
Ship in our example,
what does that look like?
You know, we say that we need
to scope things down to domains.
Well, we're going to
have a supervisor agent,
that I call triage agent,
figure out what to do.
Here are your workers.
And those workers are designed to be
for a very specific part
of my application, domain.
I have an agent for payments.
One that is tasked only
with handling money.
That's its only job.
It's not responsible for
anything else besides money.
I have another worker
that's responsible for
the warehouse, inventory.
Do I have what I need?
Do I need to order more
things in the warehouse?
Do I need to allocate stuff for an order?
And then I also have
an order agent worker,
and this is the one that's actually,
responsible for moving that data along.
I can update statuses, I can
duplicate orders, if I need.
And so, what we're doing here
is we're exposing capability
surfaces based on domain,
and not one single agent
is allowed to cross
those domain boundaries.
Focus it in, tighten it up,
only have the permissions for
one area of your application.
I said a lot of words,
this probably sounds
familiar to a lot of you.
Is that familiar to you?
- It does sound familiar to me.
And has anyone heard about microservices?
It's kind of familiar to how
these agents are working.
So, even though the agents
they use LMS for reasoning,
they behave much closer to
distributed microservices
than I think most people expect.
The same architectural patterns
that appear, we see here,
but they surface through
A2A interactions instead
and the Agent Loop instead of
having rest calls perhaps
or service meshes.
So, agent discovery works in
a similar way to service discovery.
So, instead of registering
in some sort of mesh or DNS layer,
each agent is gonna publish
that agent card that I showed before,
exposing capabilities,
versions, schemes, and so on.
And then other agents can then
resolve these capabilities during runtime.
So, this gives us late binding
without having hard-coded knowledge.
And health behavior, well,
it also maps quite cleanly
to how distributed system works.
Instead of pulling health checks,
agents will infer health from behavior.
They will, let's say an A2A request fails,
some sort of validation, or a times out,
or it returns some sort
of inconsistent data.
Well, the system will naturally retry
and it chooses perhaps a
different execution path.
So, there is no central
health manager in place.
Instead the system converges
on healthy behavior,
because agents respond
to real interactions
not through external probes.
And task distribution,
while it works in a similar way
to load balancing basically.
We rely on AgentCore memory
and distributed state
to coordinate these task IDs that we have,
but also item potency keys,
progress markers, and so on.
So, a lot of this is
very familiar to things
we've been doing for may
I say decades now even.
But when we move from that single agent
to a multi-agent workflow,
the system only stays predictable,
if every interaction is deterministic.
Allen talked about that before as well.
Choreography can remain elegant at scale,
but only if each of these
agents follow the rules
that remove randomness from the workflow.
So, the idea here is simple.
If the inputs are the same,
well, the outcome should be the same
even when several agents are involved
and running in parallel maybe.
So, we begin with clarity in prompts.
Every agent should use the risk pattern.
The model should start
with a stable contract
for the behavior of the agent.
The role section should
limit the scope of the agent.
The instruction defines
the rules it must follow.
The steps gives it predictable procedures
that are repeatable.
And then expectations
define the output structure,
and narrowing section prevents it
from drifting into responsibilities
that it shouldn't have,
like Allen talked about.
So, this removes
interpretation-type errors
that can then ripple through
any type of distributed system.
And item potency, super important here.
In any type of distributed system,
retries are not an exception.
They happen all the time.
It's regular to have that,
because of network variations,
or perhaps cold starts
with Lambda functions,
or timeouts in different
parts of the system.
So, every agent must be able
to receive the same
instruction multiple times
without us ending up
transferring money multiple time
to Allen's account for instance.
And this is why we use task IDs,
this is why we have memory checks,
consistent verification
before executing any action.
And we also make sure that
the APIs that we create,
that they are authentic.
Each call should represent
a complete and safe unit of work.
There shouldn't be any partial
updates within these systems.
If an agent updates state
or performs an action,
the workflow should be able
to perform it incompletely,
completely, or it should be
able to roll back, if needed.
We've pushed this ahead
quite far in this
presentation, right, Allen?
And I think it's time.
- Yes, we did kick this can
down about as far as we can.
Can't really talk about
production software
without talking about observability
at least a little bit.
And we're gonna talk about this
before we even do the demo,
because A2A really when
you're talking about
multi-agent collaboration,
but specifically, with A2A,
has a couple of really cool things
that I wanna make sure that
we know before we see it.
So, when you think of observability,
typically, think of three things,
metrics, logs, traces, it's the same.
It's not really any different with agents.
There's definitely
plenty of talks this week
going very deep into this subject,
but we'll talk about it
at least at a high level.
Bedrock has a very brand
new observability dashboard.
I think two weeks ago came out with this.
That just works.
If you use Bedrock,
if you use really any of
the APIs inside of Bedrock,
you get to see a CloudWatch dashboard
that rolls up all the important metrics
for operational cost performance.
Things like what's your
total invocation count,
what's your per model token spend,
what's the invocation latency,
what are the input tokens
versus the output tokens?
Things that are going to act more or less
like non-functional requirements,
but definitely requirements
on your wallet.
And Bedrock does actually,
or CloudWatch does a really good job
at servicing these things
front and center for you
without really taking
anything into consideration.
You don't have to build
anything to get this.
What I want you to take away
here, metrics are important,
but you can't really optimize
multi-agent systems without metrics,
because you're gonna be using
a lot of different models.
You're gonna have different
models for workers,
you're going to have different
models for your supervisors,
and they're gonna be taking in
different amounts of tokens,
they're gonna be spitting output tokens
out at different rates.
So, you need to have that insights
so you don't spend all your money on LLMs.
Okay, but here's the cool thing.
Here's A2A that does a really cool job
for observability, and
specifically with traces,
and a task, an overarching task in A2A.
If something comes in,
a supervisor is going
to start up a new task.
It's a multi-step plan.
Goes all the way across the
life of this invocation.
Supervisor lives with that task
and then it's going to
cast out these messages
to its sub-agents to
actually, do the work.
And A2A provides a fantastic opportunity
to hook in and watch in real time
as these orchestrated workflows pan out.
And this is where Momento comes into play.
We have a service called Topics
that's a centralized
third-party event bus.
And you can just hook
straight into these messages
inside the A2A protocol,
and subscribe to 'em in the front end,
which is why we're talking about this now
before we see the demo.
So, at the beginning, at the end,
even at tool calls in the
middle for these agents,
you get opportunity to see what on Earth
is happening in this formerly black box
that is agent execution.
Okay, we talked about observability.
- Yeah, it is finally time
for the real star of the show,
which is our full
multi-agent workflow demo.
This is where it gets exciting.
So, new scenario.
Allen or one of his drivers is out there
trying to deliver a package.
Now, we have a bit of a bigger issue.
Driver arrives at the stop
and discovers that the
package has been damaged.
We can't just schedule a
redelivery in this case.
Needs to trigger a bunch
of different actions
inside the warehouse,
in the order department,
and so on to make all of this happen.
So, now let's see how that same system
is able to handle this type of scenario.
Let's jump over to.
- Okay, so the reason that we use
agents in a scenario like this,
is 'cause of this comment box
right here that says Notes.
We can code for anything that
happens in exception type,
but notes, this is free text,
anything can happen in the notes.
So, we're gonna test it,
we're gonna see what happens.
I have in here, "Package
severely damaged during transit.
Contents appear compromised."
Let's make that worse.
"Contents caught on fire,
then were run over by my car,
and the car behind me.
Then the ashes caught on fire.
This was my fault."
- [Gunnar] Typical delivery event.
- [Allen] Yeah, we see these
a lot at Swift Ship actually,
it's kind of a problem.
And so, I had a photo prepared,
but I did the hackathon yesterday
and now I just have 100
pictures of eggs on my machine.
So, can't find.
- [Gunnar] There is another a
picture of a package on fire.
- [Allen] It's a package that was on fire
that was run over by a car.
Instead I'm not gonna show
a bunch of pictures of eggs.
So, we're gonna submit this.
So, now that we've done this,
triage agent sees this package
that got run over, it caught on fire,
the ashes caught on fire,
they're gonna run over again.
And there's definitely
things that have to be done
more than rescheduling
that package for delivery.
Gotta replace it.
We're a good delivery company.
We'll take care of your packages for you.
And again, this is happening in real time.
So, I'll zoom in, we'll take
a look at this in a minute,
but we're gonna let it
run its course here.
We have multiple agents
that's are in the mix.
Now, I see why you wanted
me to record a demo before
instead of doing it live,
'cause this is not what I expected,
but I feel like that just
drives the point home-
- [Gunnar] Yes.
- [Allen] that agents
are non-deterministic.
So, what we did see, is
it an incomplete workflow
of the triage agent saying,
"Hey, we need to refund that package.
It was destroyed."
We're going to give them their money back,
and they we're gonna
toss the responsibility
over to the warehouse agent.
And we're going to see
is there inventory left in the warehouse
to actually do a full
replacement and send it back out.
My guess what happened is I
didn't reset our demo data
and there was no inventory.
So, what it's supposed to do,
this actually might have been
a good demo we can restart.
No, it's fine.
What it's supposed to do
is allocate the inventory.
Say, "Yes I have it."
And the triage agent comes in
and says, "Oh great, okay we're
gonna duplicate the order,
we're gonna allocate that inventory again,
and then we're gonna finalize that payment
to payment processing."
But that didn't happen,
'cause I forgot to reset the demo data.
But we did see multiple agents actually,
collaborating based on that Wild West.
That is the notes on the delivery system.
- Let's quickly jump over
just to show the architecture of it.
We've been talking a lot about this.
I think it's cool to
actually, see what this means.
And it's nothing strange really.
It's similar to what Allen
showed earlier as well.
A very simple one.
It's Amazon API gateway
and he submits something in that form
that cause a Lambda function
that just stores something.
The delivery status message in DynamoDB.
It's connected, has a DynamoDB stream
that sends an event to EventBridge.
We have a rule there
that picks up that event,
and it's gonna trigger our triage agent.
That's the first agent that
then decides it runs the loop,
it decides what it's gonna do next.
Invoke the payment agent,
invoke the warehouse agent,
the order agent, and so on.
And all of these are using
Bedrock for querying the model,
but also for AgentCore memory.
So, it's a super simple
and very common serverless architecture.
There's nothing strange about it.
So, let's then move over
and see some code as well.
- Yes, we can talk about
it and see demos all day,
but for all the engineers in here,
if you're anything like me,
you're not really gonna
get it until you see it.
And we're gonna take a look.
So, A2A, we talked about the agent card,
which is how supervisors
know what you can do.
This is basically, their ID card,
has the name, has the description.
What can I do as far as capabilities go?
Do I stream, do I push?
But this is the important part here.
This is the part that
can change on the fly.
And in the future when supervisor agents
need to load information
about the order agent,
they see, oh, this guy, this order agent,
is responsible for changing order statuses
or duplicating orders.
And we have in here no schemas,
this is only natural language.
It's the beauty of A2A.
We're not really doing anything
that's tightly coupling us.
This is just natural language.
What can you do?
And what can I ask you
has in here examples
change the order from this
to that of that order,
and it knows what to do.
So, that's the agent card.
We have down here inside
of our agent handler,
our system prompt.
We also talked about
building that system prompt
with the RISEN framework.
What's your role?
What do I want you to do?
What are the steps to do
what I want you to do?
What do I expect?
And each one of these things
in here is used specifically,
to build up that determinism layer.
What do you do in this
situation or that situation?
And it will go through
and use this to figure out
what to do when the time comes.
We also have tools.
Cool, that's what takes
us from chat bot to agent.
What's a tool?
A tool has a schema.
This specific one is
changing the order status
and it accepts order ID
and the new status and then any notes.
And you know what it's doing?
Exactly what an API controller would do,
if you were trying to
change an order status.
It's calling DynamoDB.
That's it, there's no LLMs in here.
This is just running deterministic code
to set a status of an
order to a specific value.
An agent knows based on the
real, the description up here,
exactly what to do and what to expect
when it calls that tool.
So, we looked at a worker
agent, and we looked at a tool.
Let's look at the supervisor.
Surprise, surprise, it's the same,
because really we're doing the same thing.
It's not different just
because we have the supervisor
versus the worker.
We might give it a little
bit more information.
In this case we do.
We tell it what to do
in different scenarios.
So, if there's just a basic non-delivery,
just reschedule it.
What do you do in a total loss?
And that's where we were supposed
to see the payment agent,
and the order agent,
and the warehouse agent,
but the data wasn't there
in the database to do it.
But this is where you again
are defining deterministic behaviors.
It's really important to build these out
so you don't have to
build them out in code.
It's telling the agent what
to do in given scenarios.
And we've tailored these steps
based on the types of events
that it's gonna be responding
to in our system, not chat.
And that's about it is the same.
Here, this is probably the last thing
that we'll look at in the code
here is registering agents.
So, we just have the URL
of the agent card of all of these agents.
And what this is gonna do
is in the code that I wrote specifically,
this is a layer on top of A2A.
It's gonna go and it's gonna
fetch the agent card from that URL
and inject that into the system prompt.
So, the triage agent knows
what the capabilities are
of these three agents.
All it is a URL.
The last thing, actual
last thing, for real,
is the how does a supervisor agent
actually, talk to a worker?
This is a big aha moment for me
when I was building
this several months ago.
It's just a tool call.
Supervisors have a tool that says,
"Invoke agent, give me the agent URL
and give me the command,
give me the task ID so I can track it."
And all it's doing is
it's using the A2A client,
published by Google, and
sending a message to it.
And then we kick off our
Agent Loops on the sub-agents
and it returns that data back
in our Execute action step.
And that's really all there is to it.
That's multi-agent collaboration and code.
- Easy, right?
All right, so let's
bring this all together.
Few key takeaways that I think
you should try to remember.
That agents are what drives this system.
It's not workflows.
You don't design these
flows, you design behaviors.
So, each agent is responsible
for a specific job
and the system emerges from
how they collaborate together.
And A2A is really the key
to what enables this real collaboration.
Instead of having some sort
of central orchestrator,
the agents discover each other at runtime
and they delegate work and they
launch new autonomous loops.
And MCP is what makes context reliable.
Being able to use tools and schemas
that returns this
deterministic typed data.
And AgentCore together with
service infrastructure,
it allows us for massive scale
when we build these systems
and with very, very little
undifferentiating heavy lifting.
I love that phrase.
So, deterministic and determinism
is what then difference from chaos
into a system that is reliable.
And make sure that just like
with any distributed system,
you design the system for item potency
and with compensating actions.
I'm sure you all want to try out
and start competing with Swift Ship.
And from the looks of it,
we can easily compete with Swift Ship
since packages aren't delivered.
But scan the QR code
takes you to a GitHub repo
where all the code is available,
and feel free to submit
pull requests, I guess,
to create a new agent that
can order from the supplier.
So, then the demo would work,
yeah.
- Yes.
- So, you can deploy this
yourself and experiment with it.
And you can use it with or
without Momento as well.
- Yes. Yep.
- So with that, we want to thank you all
for joining us in this session
about building autonomous
multi-agent systems.
I hope you found it enjoyable.
Remember, to fill out this
session survey as always
and we'll stick around on the outside,
if anyone has any questions.
Thank you all very much.
- Thank you.
(audience applauding)