- [AM] We're gonna be
talking about building .NET
applications with AI.
And it's funny, when we were
putting this talk together,
we were going to do a
Semantic Kernel talk.
And then, as many of you in the audience
probably are following along,
Microsoft said goodbye to Semantic Kernel
and brought in,
- [Nicki] Agent Framework.
- [AM] Agent Framework.
So we will have some
Semantic Kernel in here,
but we are also going to bring
everybody into the future
with Agent Framework as well.
- Which is still in beta.
- So you're gonna get
a little smattering of everything, right?
- [Nicki] Yep. Yeah. You're
gonna get everything.
Everything that's available today,
as well as everything that's
still in preview or beta,
just so that if you're building
something in the future,
you can take advantage of
the next generation of
frameworks from Microsoft.
- [AM] With that, there's
a giant caveat, obviously.
All of this is still in preview.
Things break things, things
don't stay the same, right?
So all of this code is experimental,
the best kind of code, right?
(Nicki laughs)
The stuff that you deploy out
and you go, man, maybe
this will work one day.
Anyway, I'm AM Grobelny,
I'm a principal developer
advocate here at AWS.
I've worked at AWS collectively
for about the past seven years.
I've been doing .NET ever
since I started programming.
C# was my first language.
That's how I learned how to code.
- [Nicki] I'm Nicki, I'm
a principal engineer.
I actually am working
on the Amazon side now.
I used to work on the AWS side.
.NET was also very early on in my career.
It's very nostalgic.
I don't currently work on .NET.
I actually work on the mobile
shopping app for Amazon,
but C# was also my first language
and how I learned how to code as well.
So, you know, we thought I'd
do a little throwback here,
join AM and and talk about .NET for y'all.
- [AM] Nicki and I have
done a lot of talks
over the years together,
but we have not done a talk
together in at least five years?
- Four, maybe?
- Four years.
- Maybe you're right.
- A long time, basically.
But .NET never leaves your blood, right?
- [Nicki] He didn't miss me though,
because most of our talks usually
is just me making fun of
him the entire time, so...
- [AM] That's true.
She will be heckling me
so you don't have to,
don't worry about it.
(Nicki laughs)
She'll cover that.
All right, we're gonna get
through some PowerPoint.
We're gonna get into code
for most of the rest of the session,
because this is a code talk after all.
But we do wanna set the
scene with some of the tools
that we're gonna be using, right?
So let's talk about the
problem space first, though.
AI and chatbots
and all of the beautiful
L-L-L-L-L-M things
that are going on.
(Nicki laughs)
First off, we're talking
Agentic AI, right?
This is, we're rife with all
of these different phrases,
these philosophies.
What is an agent?
- [Nicki] Yeah, what is an agent?
Why don't you tell us?
- [AM] Well, I won't tell you
because I will speak in the words
of somebody much smarter than me.
AWS has a distinguished engineer.
His name is Mark Brooker,
big fanboy of Mark Brooker over here.
Please don't tell him I said that,
even though this is recorded.
Anyway, I got to interview Mark yesterday,
just happenstance, but
I follow Mark's blog.
Mark talks a lot about AI, Agentic AI.
Mark is one of the engineers
that brought Aurora DSQL
to life last year,
if you were following the
reinvent announcements last year.
He worked on a lot of
really interesting projects.
He co-opted a definition
from Simon Willison of
what an agent is.
And I think this is a good
basis to start any time
that you're starting to
work on Agentic workloads.
What is an agent?
At its core, it's very simple.
It's an LLM that exists in a loop
that is able to call on
tools to do additional work.
That's it, right?
But this is more of a philosophical thing
than it is a technology thing.
And Mark actually had a little
quibble with the use of LLM.
He said, that's limiting.
There are other model types.
You might have an SLM
in that group, right?
But an agent needs those two core things
to be "an agent".
A loop in which the actions
occur, prompts come in,
and then tools to call to
extend the functionality of
that LLM, right?
That's it.
And a lot of these
frameworks, a lot of the tools
that we're gonna be
talking today achieve that.
But Nicki, you work on
like real problem solving
with AI and I wanted to...
- I do.
So what are some actual
problems that you might want
to use an LLM application to build?
A good example of one
is like you can use it
to summarize meeting notes
and then extract the action
items from that meeting
and then assign them
to various team members
that were in the meeting.
Or you can use it for personalization.
I know we do a lot of personalization
in the Amazon app itself.
You can also use it to basically
create a support chatbot
so you can have it, give it
access to your documentation
and have it interact
with customers of yours
and use the API documentation
it has access to,
to answer questions from that customer.
- [AM] All right, we've
broken this talk into,
I'd say two categories.
Primarily we're gonna be
talking about tools built
by Microsoft that you can use
and tools built by AWS
that you can use at the
intersection of the two.
But we're also going to frame
this in some of the basics
of the tools that you'll use,
the framework that you might use.
Those are Semantic Kernel and
Agent Framework these days.
And then finally, we've
also thrown in a discussion
of AgentCore, right?
So this is our Amazon Bedrock AgentCore.
This is an AWS product for running
and providing, you know,
more of the operational side.
- [Nicki] The infrastructure, really.
- Yeah.
- The infrastructure to run
your LLM apps.
So the Microsoft tools
that we're gonna show you today are useful
to program your LLM app.
And then you're thinking,
where am I gonna deploy it?
And that's where the AWS tools come in.
- [AM] All right, we gotta
start at the very, very basics.
If you've done any programming against AI
or LLMs with .NET, I hope
you know this already.
If you're brand new, welcome!
(Nicki laughs)
We're excited to try stuff out.
This is the foundation
of pretty much everything else
we're gonna be talking today.
This library is very simple to understand.
It is just the abstraction layer.
Because look, this space, I
know we say this about all tech,
but this space in particular
is moving extremely fast, right?
So instead of having to
learn each individual method
of invocation or sending a prompt
or setting settings,
Microsoft has built a library
that abstracts that away, right?
Because you're just trying to
typically build something like
a chat client, right?
- Yeah.
- [AM] So you can have an
abstract chat client that then is
built into a concrete class
by a provider like Anthropic,
or in our case AWS.
We have built extensions,
which we're gonna talk about.
And I will just give you a little bit,
this is one of our first
code snippets here.
It's not really that complex,
it's not even that compelling,
but it does a lot and
it does a lot for you.
So this is using
the actual direct Microsoft
extensions themselves,
adding a chat client
and then asking for a
response from the client.
- [Nicki] Simplest use case
there is on the planet.
- [AM] Yeah. All right.
Now building on that foundation,
Microsoft has built a framework
called Semantic Kernel.
- [Nicki] So the, basically,
the abstraction layer he
was just talking about
are interfaces,
and Semantic Kernel is the
framework that implements them.
So it uses Microsoft extensions, AI,
and it's composed of a few parts.
So we have plugins
and plugins are gonna be
like your function calls
and your tools.
So you're gonna give the
LLM access to be able
to tell the date or the weather,
or you might give it
access to search the web,
rag, essentially.
And then it has AI models
that you can access
or you can give it an AI
model you'd like to access.
And then hooks and filters,
and hooks are middleware
to basically intercept
before the prompt gets sent to the LLM or
after the response
comes back from the LLM.
Maybe you wanna transform
the data a little bit
or maybe you wanna transform
the prompt before it gets sent.
Maybe you wanna observe
it, maybe you wanna log it.
And then filter is
basically a type of hook,
a specific type of hook
where you can give permission to that LLM.
So it's basically a permission
based hook where you can say,
yes, I want this prompt to
go to the LLM or no I don't.
So providing security there
or just, you know, not, it
doesn't have to be security.
Maybe you just decide,
I don't want that LLM called right now.
Or I want this other LLM called
based on this specific prompt.
- [AM] So as you can
tell, maybe as you listen
and I'll use a place near
and dear to your heart, I hope to,
to maybe help establish
what these types of frameworks do, right?
So this software is building
what we talked about already.
It's building that loop,
it's building that
function calling, right?
The tool calls for you.
You can do all that.
You can build that in software yourself,
or you can use a framework
like Semantic Kernel
that achieves that for you
to bring this into a
different area of technology.
Think about the glory days of JavaScript.
Anybody remember?
You know, having to make Ajax calls,
you remember Ajax?
- (laughs) Yeah.
- Oh, yeah. Fondly, right?
Yeah, everybody loves Ajax.
So again, a lot of these,
prior to things like React and Angular,
you would make the Ajax calls,
you would redraw the UI, right?
You would write that
all in JavaScript code.
Then they started building
frameworks that did this
for you, right?
So it's exactly the same idea.
You could build these agents,
you can make them do what
these frameworks are doing,
or you could just use something
that somebody else is maintaining.
Somebody else has built, exact same idea.
- [Nicki] Yep. Totally, yeah.
And you'll see from the
code snippet how easy it is
to use the framework,
but also to add, we're gonna show you how
to add plugins in in real time.
We're gonna show you in the code.
And so it just makes it super easy
to basically create your LLM application.
Of course you could write
all the code yourself,
but why would you when you,
when it's just basically
like 10 lines of code here
versus thousands if you were
gonna write it yourself?
So this code snippet is also very basic.
Basically just getting credentials.
I'm stating the modelId
of the model I wanna call.
This example is using
Bedrock and Semantic Kernel.
So I'm establishing the
Bedrock Runtime client
with a region and my credentials.
And then I'm building Semantic Kernel
and I'm adding Bedrock
as my completion service.
So you can obviously add
different completion services.
But Semantic Kernel has,
as you can see here,
native integration with Bedrock today.
And then you can basically call
the chat completion service.
So you can see here I'm
sending, "Hi, how are you?"
Which is really a dumb lame prompt.
And then I'm writing
the response to console,
which would probably the
LLM probably would respond,
"Hi, happy to see you,
how can I help you?"
Or whatever the heck it's gonna write.
- [AM] Yeah, and as Nicki
stated, right, Semantic Kernel,
and this is gonna be a key difference
that we see when we move into
Microsoft Agent Framework.
Semantic Kernel has
built in native support
for Bedrock
and it also has built in native
support for bedrock agents,
which if you're building new these days,
we would advise you to not
start with Bedrock agents,
but instead move to AgentCore.
Again, though, there is
not this native support
like in Semantic Kernel
for AgentCore, right?
- [Nicki] And for Agent Framework, either
because it's in preview.
- [AM] Well, that's gonna
be an interesting thing
that we're gonna see here in just a minute
when we get to Microsoft Agent Framework.
There is no native support
for any AWS services at this
time in Agent Framework.
This is my ask to you all.
Number one, this is brand new.
Actually, this altered the
foundations of this talk a little
behind the scenes.
Nicki and I were messaging each other
as we're preparing back in October or so.
Hey, wait a minute, what
just happened, right?
Because Microsoft made a
very exciting announcement,
admittedly that they
were taking auto glue on
and Semantic Kernel, moving them aside,
kind of combining what
these two were good at
into this new Microsoft Agent Framework.
But as of right now,
it's still in preview.
So I gave you the caveat up front.
I'm gonna give it to you again,
this is all experimental,
all the code you see may or may not work.
It's just to show you
how to use these things.
And hopefully my ask to you here is
that we as a community can go in,
this is an open source project.
We can request, "Hey,
we want Bedrock support,
"we want this support,
we want that support".
That's what I want you all to be thinking
as we continue in this talk.
Like how would you want to
use Agent Framework with AWS
and what should we take
as feedback from you all?
Again, Nicki and I are both resources
that you could reach out to.
We'll have contact information as well.
We're in direct connection
with the .NET AWS team as well.
They are looking for feedback too
on how you are going to want
to use this directly with AWS.
And as I said, there's a GitHub repo
that you can go open issues
yourself if you want to do that.
- [Nicki] Or you can even open a PR
if you really feel so inclined.
- [AM] Well that's aspirational,
but yes, please do that.
Anyway, so what is the difference
between Agent Framework
and Semantic Kernel?
I think that's yet to be fully realized.
I think from my usage of it so far,
I can say personally it's a lot simpler.
- [Nicki] Yeah, much simpler.
So you saw Semantic Kernel,
the code snippet had
about 10 lines of code.
Well, we're gonna show you a
Microsoft Agent code snippet
and you'll see it's a lot less.
- [AM] But it offers a lot
of the same functionality
that we just covered in
Semantic Kernel as well.
Obviously has tool calling as well.
Again, we said the beginning of this talk,
that's a pretty foundational
part of building agents.
You have to be able to call up to tools.
It also has the loop.
They're still adding in
more and more capabilities.
They've got capabilities for memory,
both short term and long term.
They've got chat history,
I believe so far.
They've got quite a bit.
- [Nicki] They have
multi turn conversations,
- [AM] Yes, multi turn conversations.
They do not have one-to-one parity
with all of the features
in Semantic Kernel yet,
that I've seen.
So again, this is maybe not something
that you're deploying today,
but it is probably something
you'll be deploying soon.
So it's good to get ahead and
learn about what is coming.
Let's take a look at that code snippet.
As we could mention, Nicki,
this is much simpler.
- [Nicki] Much simpler.
Yeah, you see it's much, much
less lines of code in general,
definitely less.
But here we're doing the same thing.
We're establishing the modelId,
we're obviously getting AWS credentials,
establishing our Bedrock Runtime client
and then passing it, the modelId.
And then we're creating
a new chat client agent.
So that's different from Symantec Kernel,
which is a type of AI
agent, as you can see.
And then I have my message
and then I just call
agent.RunAsync with my message.
And that's it.
And it's really easy to
integrate features into
a Microsoft Agent framework from here.
And it just, it's less
complicated than Semantic Kernel.
So for me, I can't speak
on behalf of Microsoft,
but it feels like Semantic
Kernel was basically like,
let's get something out
the door really fast
because this, you know, this
space is moving really quickly.
And then it feels like this
one, they really thought out
and they thought, how would
a customer be using this?
What easy code,
what's ease of use basically
for writing code for an LLM app.
And so they kind of put it together here,
which obviously it is using
concepts from Semantic Kernel,
but it just feels, it feels smoother.
It feels very easy.
- [AM] Yes.
Yeah, I will point out though,
you don't see any mention
of Bedrock directly, right?
So this is not a native
integration with Bedrock,
like in Semantic Kernel,
this is just a standard
interface you can see
as IChatClient, right?
So this would work with anything
that could implement IChatClient,
which as you can guess,
if you've been following along,
comes from that Microsoft
extensions.ai library, right?
So while there's not native support
like there is in Semantic Kernel,
you can still use Bedrock very easily.
Speaking of, let's get
into some of the AWS tools
and see why you can use it so easily.
We will speak on our implementation
of that library now.
So again, like I said at the beginning,
the Microsoft extensions.ai
are just abstractions,
not concrete classes.
They don't have concrete implementations.
You have to build those as a provider.
And we have, we've built the Bedrock MEAI,
which stands for Microsoft Extensions AI,
very creative, right?
It says what it does on the tin.
Anyway, so you get a few
things out of that, right?
You can use the embedding generator,
you don't have to set that up yourself.
An image generator
that also does not take extra setup.
So inside of our project
that is using Agent Framework,
Microsoft Agent Framework,
we are also pulling in
as a dependency package
this library, right?
Because again,
I said none of the Microsoft
Agent Framework code itself
has implemented any of
the Bedrock features yet.
If you're using Semantic Kernel,
you don't necessarily have
to pull in this package.
Semantic Kernel has built in support
for Bedrock in the code itself.
And here's the code.
If you wanted to use just this, right?
Just the MEAI package itself.
This is just doing the exact same thing
we've been doing in
all the other examples,
connecting to an LLM,
sending in a prompt, getting a response.
- [Nicki] Key thing to note here though,
is that this example is actually
not using Microsoft Semantic Kernel
or Microsoft Agent Framework.
- Right.
- [Nicki] It is just using
the extensions AI interfaces
as implemented by MEAI.
Our extension, basically.
- [AM] That's right. No
loop, no function calling.
This is at its basic, I
just want to talk to an LLM.
That's it.
All right, let's talk about the AWS tools
that you might use in
addition to these frameworks.
So this is where we
kind of shift, I'd say,
into talking less about,
I'm building the software
that's gonna run an agent into,
I need infrastructure to run that agent.
Nicki, you wanna, you use
Amazon Bedrock quite a bit?
- [Nicki] Yes, so we've
been talking about Bedrock,
you know, for how many slides now,
but we haven't actually
told you what it is.
And if you're not familiar,
Amazon Bedrock is our AWS
cloud service that provides,
you know, fully functioning models
and optimizations to app developers.
So, you know, we probably
are familiar with SageMaker.
SageMaker is our traditional ML service
where you can train a model
and you can do data transformation
and all kinds of things.
But if I just want an LLM today,
I don't wanna train anything.
I wanna use one of Anthropic's models,
or maybe I wanna use Nova, Amazon's model,
where am I gonna go?
I'm gonna go to Amazon Bedrock.
So I feel like it's really
for the app developer.
And in that same vein,
we launched AgentCore.
What is AgentCore?
Well, AgentCore just takes
that even one step further
and is offering a ton of
serverless infrastructure
for you to basically run your LLM app.
So we have Runtime, what is Runtime?
Runtime is going to run my LLM application
inside of a container for me.
I don't have to really do anything.
I just have to basically
provide an ECR image
for my container
and then it will
basically handle the rest.
So I'm not doing any of the maintenance,
I'm not doing any of the
scaling, I'm doing nothing.
Runtime's doing it all for me.
Gateway, Gateway is
providing my LLM application
access to functions inside of AWS.
So Lambda functions or other
APIs that you might have.
And then there's memory.
So we have short-term
memory and long-term memory,
and it'll basically stand
up another container
where it can serve memory
to your LLM application.
We have observability default,
basically functionality
built into CloudWatch.
So when you're running your Runtime,
you will have your container
logs in CloudWatch.
Identity is going to be
access to authorization
and authentication via Kognito.
And then code interpreter,
that's a really cool one.
That's basically running code
in an isolated sandbox for you.
And then Browser Tool is
giving your LLM access
to a web browser.
- [AM] And today we've got
a project that we built
that we're going to show
off specifically Runtime,
Gateway and Code Interpreter.
So I wanted to give you a
little bit more information
about these three aspects of AgentCore.
Nicki gave a great overview.
Runtime is where your actual
agent code will get deployed.
So again, this is another thing
that I'm gonna implore you all
and there is no GitHub repo
this time to open an issue.
So you will have to talk to me or Nicki.
We would love to hear how
you want to use AgentCore.
'Cause right now, most of the support
for using AgentCore
without setting up a lot
of things yourself as
you will see in our code,
is done in Python.
So Python has a lot of
decorators, some libraries,
I'm sure I see some
heads nodding out there.
Maybe you've already looked into this
and gone, wait a minute, I have
to build all this, hold on.
Okay, so we're gonna see,
I'll walk you through,
I did some discovery,
there's some things that I can
point out about if you wanted
to run .NET code in AgentCore
Runtime today, you can do it.
I'll show you how, but I
wanna make that easier for you
and I want to hear what you
want from that too as well.
So please feel free to share that.
But this is a very interesting service.
It runs on Firecracker,
which we're gonna see.
So it is an isolated microVM.
It gets invoked in two ways.
It is when you deploy
your Code to Runtime,
there is a API endpoint that you need
to implement called Ping, which,
any guesses what that does?
(audience laughs)
There you go.
Yeah, it will ping the service
to make sure it's healthy.
Then there is a /invocations.
So you are not actually
going to interact directly
with your agent running in Runtime.
You are going to have the prompt sent
through another SDK call in the AWS SDK
called InvokeAgent, right?
And then that in turn passes on
to your agent code running in Runtime,
which then invokes this /invocation.
So it'll look a lot clearer in the code.
- [Nicki] So if you had like
a UI basically with a chatbot
and you're interacting, your
UI is going to use the SDK
to call InvokeAgent.
It's not going to call like
an API endpoint directly.
- [AM] And this is just
a architecture slide
of how Runtime is operating the things
that I just described to you.
So it is a container based service.
You will build a an ARM
container specifically
and it gets uploaded into ECR,
which in turn goes and deploys on Runtime.
And it goes through this cycle of,
if I get a prompt through InvokeAgent,
I send it to /invocations in Runtime.
And whatever you do
inside how you implement
that endpoint, it's up to you.
- [Nicki] That's where
those other frameworks,
so that we talked about,
can really help you out
develop that application.
So that's what we're gonna
show you today with our code
is how to use Semantic Kernel
or Microsoft Agent behind
that invocations endpoint
when you deployed it to AgentCore Runtime.
- [AM] Yeah, and you might be asking,
well, why would I need this?
Why don't I just deploy
it on my own container?
Obviously you can do that as well,
but this handles scaling for you.
It handles session isolation.
So this is a very fun
problem to have to solve
if you have to solve it yourself.
You have to somehow isolate
sessions from one another when
you have users interacting
with your chatbot, right?
You don't want questions from user Nicki
leaking into user AM session.
Even though I would love
to see what Nicki saw.
(Nicki laughs)
- [Nicki] Well maybe you do, I don't know.
- [AM] But, so some of the things you get
are things like session
isolation by using Runtime
and in conjunction identity, right?
Nicki told us about identity earlier too.
All right, let's talk
about AgentCore Gateway.
This is one of my favorite
things in AgentCore.
It's really, really neat.
You don't have to build
an MCP server, right?
That's the the premise of this.
If you already have a REST API
and you've got an open API
spec, you got an MCP server now
if you wanna upload this to Gateway.
All you have to do get that open API spec,
create a target within the Gateway.
This is another really
interesting thing too.
You can have a single Gateway endpoint
serving up multiple MCP servers
and an API is not the only
way you can implement it too.
You can also choose a
lambda function, right?
- Mm hmm.
- To fulfill what you need.
So you get an endpoint for your Gateway.
You can manage things like
API keys that are needed
to invoke your REST API for example.
And you just provide
it targets. That's it.
You got MCP servers.
It's really, really-
- [Nicki] It's real easy.
We actually used it in our example
and we're gonna show you how it works.
- [AM] All right, and there you go.
Same thing.
As I said, you're gonna
have an API endpoint target
that's just gonna manifest then
as tools within the Gateway.
And same with a lambda target.
You just implement it
and then it is exposed
as MCP server tools
that your LLM running in
one of these frameworks
can utilize as a tool call.
Not much there.
- Not much to it.
- There.
- [Nicki] It's pretty simple.
You don't have to build an MCP
server, which I love to hear.
You don't have to build
in any kind of sentence.
AgentCore Code Interpreter.
So I kind of mentioned this
briefly about code running in a,
in an isolated sandbox.
And basically if you can
think about a use case
where the LLM needs to write some code
and run it to give you a response.
So let's say I tell the LLM,
Hey, I want you to read this CSV file
and I want you to calculate
the highest revenue
in XYZ category, which is
relevant to the CSV file.
Well, my LLM needs to go write some code
to extract the contents of that CSV
and then run the calculation.
And so where's it gonna do that?
So it's gonna do that in
AgentCore Code Interpreter.
An AgentCore Code Interpreter
is literally just another container
that the LLM can spin up.
It's an isolated sandbox
so it does not have
outbound internet access.
So everything is secure.
It can basically write
the code, execute it
and spit out a response
and then send you back that response.
You can also give that container,
well you don't have to
set it up, which is nice.
You don't have to do anything,
normally you might have to do that.
So this is another way to like, you know,
do something for you.
'Cause AgentCore is always
about doing things for you
and you don't have to do it,
but also you can give it IAM permissions.
So you can have that container be able
to access something
else in your AWS account
that you needed to access.
So here, if you look at this diagram,
the user is sending a
query, the LLM is invoked
and the LLM goes, wait,
I need to run some code,
and it's going to spin
up this other container,
the Code Interpreter where
it's just a container,
it has a file system and a shell.
It's going to run the code
that it wrote, execute it,
spit out a response.
Obviously you get
observability on this container
that is running via CloudWatch
and then it's gonna send
the result back to the agent
to then give back to you.
- [AM] And some of these
choices of what you use when
come down to, you know, trade-offs
as is everything in
software is trade-offs,
what you wanna do, how you
want to do it, et cetera.
You may be thinking, why don't
I just implement, you know,
in C#, a tool that does the thing
that I'm going, I'm trying
to do in Code Interpreter?
Well, number one, Code Interpreter,
if you notice on the slide
previous, supports Python,
JavaScript, TypeScript currently.
So maybe you need to do something
with a Python library, right?
And you need the LLM to do
that on a regular basis.
We've got an example that
we're using in our project.
One of the other neat things
of code interpreter is
you can include files
alongside the code that runs.
So maybe you're following me here.
You put a CSV alongside
this Code Interpreter.
And then you use statistical
libraries from Python,
which Python has a lot of
built in math and statistics
and data science libraries
that are very commonly used.
You want to do statistical
analysis for a data set
and give permissions to the LLM to do that
as people are prompting the LLM.
You would probably put this
in Code Interpreter, right?
Instead of building a tool to do this.
Not saying you couldn't do that,
you could probably build
a tool like that as well.
But Code Interpreter is
built for things like
what I'm just describing, right?
- Yep.
- Okay,
- [Nicki] Let's show 'em what we built.
- Is it code time?
- It's code time.
- [AM] All right, let me log
in before you, there we go.
Okay, let's see.
- [Nicki] Did that not work?
Okay.
- [AM] Hold on.
Connected.
Try it again.
- [Nicki] Of course.
Technical difficulties.
Love that.
Oh, there it is.
- [AM] You got to threaten it. Thank you.
- Yep. That worked.
- It got scared.
- Thank you. (laughs)
Decided to work.
All right, we're gonna start slow.
Not for you all, for me.
So we're gonna build up to what we built.
- He always needs it slower, so that's,
- I do.
- That's normal.
- [AM] You know, this
old brain doesn't work
as much as it used to.
All right, so I'm gonna start
off with an example here.
This is using, so weird, you stash.
- [Nicki] I know, this is bizarre.
Do you want me to sit next to
you? Would you feel better?
Oh, but that chair is taller.
- Yeah.
Anyway, all right, moving on. Sorry.
All right, so we're gonna take a look at,
I'll show you here.
Nothing up my sleeve.
I am using the Bedrock.MEAI.
That's tough to say.
- Jesus.
I'm done with the chair.
You know what, I'm not,
I'm not that tall.
So you sitting and me standing, it's fine.
- [AM] And it looks good.
So I'm using the MEAI package
here. That's it, right?
And I wanted to show you,
we saw this in PowerPoint,
but you know, it's not as
fun coding in PowerPoint.
So all that we're doing is instantiating.
This is from the AWS SDK for .NET.
We're sending in a model,
we're using sonnet-4 Anthropic model
and then literally just sending a prompt.
Is this thing on?
And of course it wouldn't
be complete if I did not
got that running.
So I know you're all gonna be like,
- Yes!
- Where are the,
where are the gasps?
Where are the oohs, where are the ahs?
There we go. All right.
(Nicki laughs)
Yeah.
- [Nicki] I don't know if
this one deserves that,
to be honest.
- [AM] No, not yet.
(Nicki laughs)
All right. Okay, sorry.
A little too early for that, I guess.
So that's connecting up to Bedrock,
which in turn is sending our prompt
to this Anthropic model for inference.
And we got the response.
I know. It's amazing.
- So magical.
- It is.
We'll take questions
in the back at the end.
All right!
- [Nicki] This is the next demo.
- [AM] We are going to
start slow again here
with our two Microsoft frameworks.
So we've got an example
here in Semantic Kernel
and we've got an example
in Agent Framework.
So this is your typical "Hello World".
Like if you just wanted to
get things connected up,
get a tool call going
and and see it working.
Do you wanna talk through Semantic Kernel
or Agent Framework?
- [Nicki] Let's go to
Semantic Kernel first.
- [AM] Okay. All right.
- [Nicki] So I mean, we
saw this in the PowerPoint,
but you know, it's always better live
'cause we're actually gonna see it run.
The only thing different here
from the code snippet you saw earlier
is I'm actually adding a plugin,
which I mentioned were
functions that I can call
to give the LLM more tools in its toolbox.
And this one is a date
plugin that we wrote
because LLMs can't tell time, we all know,
and all it does is just
give the LLM the date.
So if the prompt is, what is the date,
the LLM can then invoke the DatePlugin,
you know, well Semantic
Kernel helps the LLM
then use that tool.
- [AM] Yeah, I wanna point
out a few things here too.
Kernel, right, this class kernel,
this is at the heart of Semantic Kernel.
This is setting up the actual agent loop,
the function calls.
This is how you start any usage
of Semantic Kernel in any code you write.
If you are building this into
a web service, for example,
Microsoft in its
documentation recommends using
a transient service for each invocation
because they built it in a
way that's very lightweight.
You know, standing up a new one
is not intensive on resources.
This is a native support
built into Semantic Kernel.
- [Nicki] So you see in this example,
we are not invoking the
Bedrock Runtime client
because we don't actually need to,
because Semantic Kernel is doing it for us
with this native support.
- Right?
- All we have to do
is give it the modelId.
- [AM] Yes, and as Nicki
mentioned, we have a DatePlugin.
This will be another divergence
that we see when we look at
the Agent Framework example.
This uses these annotations, right?
You don't see this in Agent Framework.
We'll take a look at that example next,
but that's just a little
implementation detail.
Something I thought was very interesting.
The next thing I wanted
to call out too was this
FunctionChoiceBehavior.
This is registering those
plugins with the kernel, right?
So the actual framework
itself needs to know,
how do I use these tools, right?
That's why we have a description
"Gets the current date".
That's up to you to write, by the way.
If you don't write a good
description for your tool,
it's not gonna work very well, so...
(Nicki laughs)
You need that as well
so that the LLM can figure
out which tool does what.
And finally we've got chatHistory.
We're adding a user message.
- [Nicki] That's a distinct difference
between Semantic Kernel, Agent Framework.
You have to create a chatHistory array,
add a message to it,
and then pass that in
when you make the call.
- Let's see, my Program.cs.
Okay, so we've got Semantic Kernel.
You all want see it
running, I'm sure, right?
- [Nicki] Did you pray
to the demo gods today?
- No I didn't.
- That was a mistake.
- [AM] It was, huge mistake.
Oh!
- Oh, it worked!
- [AM] All right, that's, look,
LLMs are really good at a lot of stuff.
It's funny that it says I don't
have access to a function.
It does. LLMs are good at a lot.
- [Nicki] It'll say it gave you the date.
Well no, it's the wrong-
- [AM] It's not big on telling time.
It does know, it does not
know what day it exists in.
I promise you,
if you just ask an LLM what
day it is, it won't know.
But now it does because we allow it to.
So let's move over to Agent Framework
and see the differences, shall we?
- [Nicki] So remember, no
native Bedrock support,
no AWS support really at
all, because it's brand new.
And so you see here,
we have to establish the Bedrock
Runtime client ourselves.
Then we're gonna use our MEAI extensions.
We're gonna turn this
into an iChat client.
So now the Bedrock client
is going to implement
that interface for us using
those lovely extensions
written by the .NET team at AWS.
And then we are going to add the DateTool.
You see how it's very different
how we're adding a tool here.
It's not considered a
plugin. It's called a tool.
And we're adding a list of AI tools
and then we establish our agent,
we pass it our implementation
of IChatClient and our tools.
And then we have a message.
So we don't have a chatHistory array.
And then we can just run
our message asynchronously.
And if you wanted to have
multi turn conversation,
you would have to create a thread object
and pass that thread with the message.
So it's kind of more isolated in this way
in that you can just have a
single prompt and response
and not everything has
to be a conversation.
- [AM] Another thing I wanted to point out
that's very interesting to me
in this new implementation is
you actually can register
an individual function
from a class as well
so that you're seeing this
AIFunctionFactory.Create
instead of registering a type,
for example in Semantic
Kernel, Semantic Kernel,
you can also do things like
add a plugin by object.
If you need to instantiate
the object yourself,
maybe pass in some parameters
in the constructor,
you know, whatever you need to do.
This actually lets you just do
individual functions as well.
So it's kind of a little
more flexible, I'd say.
- [Nicki] Yep.
- All right.
- And that flexibility
is kind of goes to what
I was saying before,
how Semantic Kernel feels like
they just got something out the door
as things were moving quickly
and Agent Framework,
they really put more thought
into how you would use this.
- [AM] I have to use our
incredibly high tech solution
of commenting out code.
Look at that. Wow.
- [Nicki] This is not the
main event by the way.
This is a precursor.
We just wanted to make sure
you really understood the code
before we jumped into our,
the application that we built.
- [AM] Okay, so you can
see also from this response
a little more aware of
the tools for some reason.
Wish I could tell you why,
the difference between these frameworks,
I can't.
But I like this designation as well.
We asked for the time, right?
The LLM using the,
the actual function that we gave it
as a tool recognizes, I can't
actually tell you the time,
I can only tell you the date.
So it's very specific.
You know, it's tell you
exactly what it can do.
It's still got December 1st.
- [Nicki] Feels a little bit smarter.
- [AM] Wonderful. Okay.
All right.
So I'm gonna move over now
to our favorite Agentic IDE, Hero.
And we're gonna look at a
much larger project now.
- [Nicki] So this project has like,
as you can see from the file explorer,
four things going on.
So the HoroscopeAPI is a lambda function.
We're using Gateway to
communicate with this function
to our LLM applications.
HoroscopeUI is really just an MVC app
that's running a nice beautiful UI
and interacting with AgentCore
via the AWS SDK as we mentioned.
That's how you invoke
your LLM apps deployed
to AgentCore Runtime.
And then the other two
things were in there were
two different LLM apps.
One was Semantic Kernel
and the other one was Microsoft Agent.
And they're both deployed
to AgentCore Runtime.
So if you look inside
of those, which we will,
there will be Docker files there
and there will be a deployment script
that sends that image up to
ECR and then it is deployed.
And there's very specific differences
that make it an AgentCore
Runtime application.
And he kind of mentioned briefly
how you needed a ping endpoint
and an invocations endpoint.
You also needed to run on port 8080.
There's very specific things
that we will make sure
to show you of how to
actually get it running
in AgentCore Runtime.
- [AM] You all wanna see it
working first though, don't you?
- Of course!
- Yeah.
Yeah. And Nicki, you're very
proud of this UI, aren't you?
- [Nicki] I am very proud of this UI.
You can switch between the
LLM applications in the UI.
- [AM] Yeah, look at this.
Look at this feature.
That's incredible.
Okay, let's start with Semantic Kernel.
Semantic Kernel in this project
has more limited capabilities
that we built into it.
Then we spent time building
the Agent Framework side.
So we'll see that.
- [Nicki] We thought it
would be more important
because if you were starting to build
an LLM application today,
you're not gonna start building
it with Semantic Kernel.
You're probably gonna
wanna start building it
with Agent Framework.
- [AM] Yeah.
But I also wanted to
demonstrate like, you know,
if you build something with
different capabilities,
what does it look like,
et cetera, et cetera.
So let's start.
This is a Horoscope
agent, that's all it does.
It gives us a horoscope.
Unfamiliar with that?
We all have a zodiac sign dictated to us
by when we were born.
It just so happens,
and you can argue with me in
the back of the room at the end
that Pisces is the best sign.
(Nicki laughs)
It's just the data, I'm sorry.
- [Nicki] It also just so
happens that we are both Pisces.
- [AM] I only took a sample
size of me and Nicki.
So that's where the data came from.
- [Nicki] Okay, so go,
give us our horoscope.
I wanna know.
Are things looking up for me today?
- [AM] Okay, so we'll use it.
Let's see.
Okay, "Today brings a wave
of creative inspiration,
"dear Pisces."
- Wow!
- I feel it.
- I feel it too.
- I feel it in the air.
"Your intuitive nature's
particularly strong."
Okay, so I wanna show you
one of the differences
that we built into our app here.
"Can I get a horoscope for Pisces
"for the week?"
And I didn't spell Pisces
right, it probably won't care,
but not gonna tempt any fate here.
Let's see.
This one might be challenging for it.
Ah, as you can see,
- It's the same,
- Exactly the same.
It does not have capabilities
that we built into it
for a weekly one.
However, we will see in Agent Framework
that we actually gave tools for that.
So first off, why we
showed you this DatePlugin.
When you're asking for a
horoscope on a certain day,
you gotta know what day it is, right?
You don't want your user to do that.
So that was the first plugin
that we gave our Semantic Kernel demo was
how do I tell what day it is
when a user asks for a horoscope.
The next plugin we gave,
and this is,
this is actually calling our API directly.
So as Nicki mentioned,
and we can look at this depending on time,
it's not the focus of this talk,
but I do think it's kind
of an interesting project.
We built a AWS SAF application,
not familiar with SAF?
That's our Serverless
Application Framework
for deploying serverless applications
a little bit more quickly.
Anyway, we've got-
- [Nicki] This is just a lambda function.
That's all HoroscopeAPI is.
- [AM] Yes, it's API
Gateway allowed to function
and a DynamoDB table.
It also is using Bedrock
to generate the horoscopes in real time.
If somebody has asked for a
horoscope already for that day,
for that sign, it stores it in Dynamo,
retrieves it from Dynamo
instead of going to Bedrock
to generate a new one.
So we actually implemented
in get_Horoscope
as our tool, our plugin
as they call it in Semantic Kernel.
An API call directly.
So again, a tool can be
anything that .NET code can do.
You don't have to use MPC-
- MCP.
- [AM] I do that every time.
MCP servers.
You don't have to use that necessarily
as your tool definitions.
Anything like we saw,
our very simple DatePlugin
just gets the date.
- [Nicki] That's all it does.
- So this is actually
calling our HoroscopeAPI
that's deployed.
We've got, we didn't go
through the API endpoints yet,
but we do have a daily,
a weekly and a monthly.
But you can see maybe why an
MCP server in this instance
would be a little bit
more convenient to use.
Because I'm gonna have to build a tool
for each of these endpoints, right?
I'm gonna have to build a tool for daily
and build a tool for weekly
and build a tool for monthly.
That's not true if I'm using
an MCP server, for example.
I mean you could potentially
build a tool in a way
that makes it more configurable.
There's other options as well.
But MCP, as we're gonna see
in Agent Framework example,
makes it a lot easier.
All right, so this is why
it can't do weekly horoscopes.
It literally can't.
It does not have the-
- [Nicki] It only has access to daily.
- [AM] That's right.
Okay, let's take a look and compare.
So again-
- DateTool.
- [AM] DateTool, exactly the same.
We've already seen this.
I'm gonna skip it.
Let's look at the HoroscopeTool.
So if you notice, doing the
same thing I just mentioned,
what about an MCP server, right?
I'm not setting up the MCP server here
because Agent Framework,
if I go to my Agent.cs
class that I've built here,
it will actually let you
take an MCP client,
use the MCP client
to list the available
tools based off the input
that you give it,
and automatically register those MCP tools
to the LLM as function calls.
Right? That-
- [Nicki] That's pretty freaking cool.
- [AM] All that's doing,
this tools.AddRange.
So we saw this already, AIFunctionFactory.
- [Nicki] You see he's adding
a bunch of tools, DateTool,
AnalysisTool, HoroscopeTool
and then the other one.
So he's adding specific
functions in the HoroscopeTool.
There was two functions.
One to get your horoscope,
the other one to get the
different Zodiac signs.
- [AM] That's right,
but with my MCP tools,
like we can keep looking at this.
I'm actually doing a ListToolsAsync
and I've set up, okay.
You'll have to trust me.
I can show you if you want later,
but you have to trust me in this demo,
I've set up AgentCore Gateway
with an open API spec that
points to that HoroscopeAPI
and takes all of those endpoints,
weekly, daily, monthly,
and provides them as MCP tools
in that MCP server.
So as I connect up to that MCP server,
I can use,
and this is just a standard
MCP client library in .NET.
It's the one that everybody uses.
I make a call to the MCP server.
(Nicki laughs)
Do it every time, every time.
Make a call to it to
list the available tools.
It has my daily, my weekly,
and my monthly available to me.
We can actually go look.
Shall we switch?
- Let's do it.
- [AM] You gave me this beautiful UI
that lets me switch
(Nicki laughs)
and show people.
Thank you.
- (laughs) You're welcome.
- [AM] All right.
So I'll ask the same question.
I'll even copy-paste.
- [Nicki] Wow, how lazy of you.
- Exactly.
(Nicki laughs)
DAS developers are lazy.
All right.
"Can I get a horoscope
for Pisces for the week?"
Now we're on our Agent
Framework implementation.
It should work.
- [Nicki] Well, you didn't pray
to any of the gods today, so I don't know.
Oh, here's your weekly horoscope.
- There it is.
- Bingo.
- [AM] "This week brings a
powerful wave of intuitive energy
"your way, dear Pisces".
- [Nicki] (laughs) I feel like that.
- Do you feel the wave?
- I feel the wave.
(laughs) It's really strong.
- [AM] You can see it.
And also is calculating the week for us.
That's part of the API
capabilities as well.
I can even ask, should we do another sign?
- [Nicki] Yeah, sure.
What's your second favorite sign?
Oh, Scorpio! Do Scorpio.
- Why?
- Because it's another
water sign.
- [AM] It's another water, I
was gonna do Cancer because-
- [Nicki] Oh, do Cancer. Okay, do Cancer.
- [AM] All right.
"Give me
"a horoscope for Cancer
"for the month."
As this loads, I'll as an aside say
I'm very aggressive
with LLMs versus Nicki.
Nicki puts like, please and
thank you and things in.
I'm more aggressive.
- [Nicki] He's like very
demanding with his LLM commands.
- [AM] All right, what's going on
in the month of December for Cancer?
"This month brings you a
wave of emotional clarity
"and intuitive insights for you."
- Hmm.
- More waves.
A lot of waves.
- [Nicki] Do you feel like
that's coming from Taylor
right now?
- [AM] Yeah, Taylor I think
is having emotional clarity.
She does have natural nurturing abilities.
So, okay, we're right on.
This is great.
- Works.
- [AM] Okay, what else
should we talk about, Nicki?
- [Nicki] I don't know,
if you just wanna show
quickly in the MVC app
how we're invoking the Runtime?
AgentCore Runtime in the MVC app?
- [AM] Yes, I did wanna
show that. Thank you.
So we mentioned right
in AgentCore Runtime,
or do you want to take this?
- [Nicki] We mentioned that we have to,
if we deploy an LLM application
to AgentCore Runtime,
we do not call it like
via normal API call.
We actually use the AWS SDK
and this is very specific.
There are multiple SDKs for Bedrock.
So I made this mistake, but
it's not the Bedrock SDK
or the Bedrock Runtime SDK.
It is literally Bedrock Runtime AgentCore,
I think is what it's called.
- [AM] Here we are.
- [Nicki] Or is it Bedrock AgentCore?
- Where are-
- It's super specific.
You can easily get it wrong.
And so that's how you invoke the Runtime.
You might wanna also show the container
running on port 8080 and
having the invocations endpoint
'cause that's very specific to Runtime.
- [AM] So here's the actual
AWS SDK for .NET code
that invokes your agent within a Runtime.
So we have a RuntimeRequest object here.
We're giving it the RuntimeArn,
you don't know Arn, Amazon
Resource Name, right?
This is the actual identifier
of your resource running
in your AWS account.
We give it a SessionId.
Remember when I said Runtime allows you
to do session isolation?
There you go.
So if you give it a new SessionId,
that's gonna create a new
session for every invocation.
You can reuse the same SessionId
to invoke a prompt in the same session.
So you would connect this
perhaps with AgentCore Identity
or you could do your own,
roll your own, right?
Manage the SessionIds yourself, up to you.
And finally the payload
is literally the prompt.
Okay, what am I gonna ask AgentCore?
And we just do
InvokeAagentRuntimeAsync, that's it.
And then it sends us back a message.
We do some string reading
and JSON serialization.
- [Nicki] And deserialization.
- [AM] Yes, deserialization. Sorry.
And...
- And that's it.
And then the container is very specific.
So for that container to actually work,
it needs to be running on port 8080.
And you need to have your
/invocations endpoint
and your /ping one.
So there you go. There it is.
So you can see that /invocations endpoint
is actually just call,
it's, so we can do anything we
want inside of there, right?
But we, what we're doing is
we're actually calling into
one of our frameworks.
So in this case, Microsoft Agent Framework
to then implement our request.
- [AM] That's right. Yeah.
Something I wanted to mention as well,
if you're using the Python
libraries, for example,
to work with AgentCore,
there's like a starter toolkit
and some decorators and things like that.
It will set up a lot of this for you.
Oh, there you go.
- [Nicki] I just wanna make
sure you guys had access
to the code before the session ends,
'cause I know they're gonna
kick us out in three minutes.
So this QR code will get you a link.
We did not find a lot of .NET examples
with these tools online,
so feel free to use the code that we wrote
because we put a lot of
time into making it work.
- [AM] Yes.
You may have to make the repo public also.
- [Nicki] Oh yeah. Let me do that.
I'll do that.
- [AM] Yeah, you can do that.
All right.
Word of warning though.
As I said, all of this
code is very experimental,
very brittle.
I would not deploy this in production.
This is definitely code for learning
and seeing what's possible
and hopefully giving us feedback as well
to bring back to the .NET team here at AWS
to improve the experience.
As I said, there are some things
that are handled for you
when you're using the
Python tools for AgentCore
that are not handled in the .NET side
that I've had to build.
For example, can you go
back to the code real quick?
- Sure.
- I know we have
three minutes.
For example, there is a
decorator in the Python version
that will set up this type
of entry point for you.
You don't have to implement
invocations yourself,
you don't have to know about that,
abstracts that away from you.
You can use our code as an example,
if you want to get started today
running things in AgentCore.
The other thing that happens is a lot
of these good SessionIds,
these things like that,
are sent to you in a header.
So you would have to inspect
the headers coming in.
Not always the most fun thing to do.
And a third thing that I
learned while building this,
so Firecracker I mentioned earlier,
is the underlying way
that these containers are getting spun up.
Firecracker uses IMDSv1,
it doesn't actually use IMDSv1,
it mimics IMDSv1,
which has been removed from version four
of the AWS .NET SDK.
So I have in here an,
they call this MMDS, you can look this up.
Firecracker uses MMDS.
It's a microVM version of,
and this is, if you're
unfamiliar with IMDS,
it is how you retrieve credentials
from a role assigned to a compute runtime.
It's not EC2, ECS, et cetera.
You can use this MMDSCredentials class
that I've built here for you if you want
to retrieve the role credentials
for the container running
in AgentCore Runtime.
All right, we are right at time.
- [Nicki] We're, yeah. Related sessions.
If you want more about .NET and
GenAI, throw those up there.
And then just our
information at the end there.
We, if you wanna reach us,
these are our email addresses
and our usernames for GitHub.
- [AM] Yes. We'll leave that up.
We will go out, stand right in the hallway
if you wanna ask us questions, thank you.
- Yeah, questions have to
be done outside the room.