Hopefully you're all here for this session. If
not, there's still enough time to leave.
I'm Anna. I'm a developer advocate at AWS,
and I'm very honored to be joined by David
here. He's an AWS community hero.
Thank you, David. Thank you for the
for the invite.
My name is uh Victoria. I'm from Mexico. Sorry for
my bad English.
So today,
uh, we're going to talk,
uh, what are these
agentic workflow means and how we
can take advantage on the local
LLMs.
So. First, let's talk
about the pain point,
the cost of downtime.
Aberde research told
us that
in
the average cost of unplanned downtime industrial
operations are more than 2,060,000
per hour.
So
there are a lot of industries affected
by this,
um, problems. So and
I will take
the stage on that. Yeah, we'll cover some of them, but
there are many others. So mining, you're
underground usually.
Without any signal,
there's manufacturing where you're in remote
plants with legacy infrastructure,
oil and gas, usually on offshore
platforms in many miles
into the sea.
Energy,
government with data sovereignty requirements,
and retail.
Just a few of many industries that
can be affected by this problem. If
you want to run AI agents,
you require cloud.
So what's the cloud dependency problem that we've been talking
about? We're at a factory
and we want to analyze sensor
data and if we have Internet
connection
everything's OK. We talk to agents through Bedrock
and we're good to go,
but once that connection goes down,
then we have a problem.
What do we do?
So what do agents require
to work offline?
So first of all, agents are powered by
large language models, so they need to think, they
need to reason locally
so that we're gonna be running those agents locally.
Agents are powered by
LLMs, but they need the ability to take actions,
and agents do that through tools, so they
also need to be able to use those tools locally,
not through the internet.
They need to keep context between different sessions
so they have memory.
And then finally once we have connectivity
again to sync that information to
and from the cloud,
all of those things are required for agents
to work uh offline.
And the
solution that the VNI found and we're
bringing to you today
is using
strength agents SDK
and Olama together to have
the power of agents in
the edge. Let's ask Ana to
the audience
who have worked with strength agents
or an agentic orchestration
tool. Show of hands.
Great,
fantastic.
Who has used Olama to run locally.
Perfect, fantastic.
So we're all on the same page.
So the hybrid architecture that we built
and that we're proposing here today is
using strands agent to do the reasoning
using tools, having memory,
and when we're offline we're using models
through Olema
and the custom local tools that we created
for strengths
and when we're online we're back into the
clouds with Bedrock.
So talking a little bit about Olama,
Olama is an open source tool that helps us to
run lightweight LLMs on
our own computers. In fact, I can run
in my
old MacBook, uh,
small models like 8
billion parameters, uh, queen.
But we have a
A catalog of LLMs that we can
use with Olama.
We have models from uh from Google,
for instance, uh Hema 3
Mistra AI, uh,
powerful models from Meta Lama,
basically Deeps see 5
Queen GPT OSS,
and many more other models that we can run,
uh, in local, um,
facilities.
So
Olama will be giving us the power of
the model.
But agents require not
only models.
There's this whole thing that we call the agentic
loop
where it performs a bunch of steps
until it's happy with the response and
it sends it back to the user.
So how does it work?
First part is the reasoning part
where we receive the user input.
We process that input with a large
language model.
And then the model decides if it
needs to call additional tools or if it's
ready to send a response or not.
Then we have the actions, which are the tools
that the the model can call.
With these actions we are going to
send and receive inputs that can accomplish
the task that the agent
is trying to finish and
if the agent determines that it's
ready to respond to the user,
the agent responds
the final output to the user.
So it's why we call it a loop.
It keeps iterating between
reasoning with the model and actions
with the tools until it's happy with the
response.
The tools help add additional
context to the model and then it
gives the response back to the user. And that's why
I say that the the agents are
loops with superpowers.
So write these loops, superpower,
super powerful loops, it's hard.
So that's why we want to introduce
ourselves as Strength agents.
Strength Agents is an open source
Python and and since
yesterday also TypeScript,
SDK for building agents
using a few lines of code.
Basically. Strength agents is a
solution
think
for builders, so people that actually
write code. We are not reinventing the
wheel. We are only putting. The same
capabilities as a builder or developer needs
for agentic purposes.
Yes, and not only it's easy to use trends,
we're going to show you the code right now, but it
also is extensible, so we can add
tools, MCP,
memory management, a lot of different things
to make our agents more powerful,
and we're not only using
Amazon Bedrog LLMs.
In fact, we can use Olama.
We can use first party APIs
like Anthropic API, Open API,
and other vendors like
Grok, etc.
So it's a very extensible tool, and
agnostic, let's say, for a single
vendor. Yes, so we create the model,
we give it the tools, all the information
that it needs, the
capabilities that it has, and we
can simply switch to different models
if we want to.
So let's start reviewing a
single agent, the most basic
agent.
First we have to import the library
with import strands and then we
can instance an agent with the default
features. What is the default features basically,
um, Amazon
Bedrock with clotsonnet 4.0
in the Oregon region.
That's all.
So after that we can start,
uh, working with an agent,
sending a prompt, receiving an answer, accomplish
this powerful agenttic loop.
So this is the simplest agent that we can
create using strengths. If
we don't define a model, we're using the default
one. But
how about if we talk about
an agent that works locally,
so we need to import only
the Olama
model library.
In this case I'm importing some tools that
are um that I
create before
for my workload specifically
for instance I create a tool for read sensors
trigger an alert, etc.
uh that that custom tools are created
and we're going to talk about a little bit
later about how the tools works
but let's continue with the code.
Great. So now I am creating an
agent but
setting the model, uh,
isolama model where.
Uh, we have running now
Olama and our host.
We define the local host, the port, and the model ID.
In this case we are using IPSI in the 8
billion parameters model.
So in the previous example we're
not specifying the model. Now we're specifying
this model through Ola.
And for sure we need to include the tools that the
agent will be able to use to
accomplish the mission.
The system from basically what
the model needs to accomplish, what is the main task
that the er models that the agent
will work with.
Yeah, I like to say that it's the model's personality.
One important thing that this system prompt have is
that we are indicating that this model
is that this agent is it's working
fully offline
so the model will not
try to reach internet or to reach
external source or features.
At the end we only start
working with the agent sending a prompt
in this case checking our sensor
and alerting if
uh anything is wrong,
how using the tools that we have previously defined.
So here with less than 20 line of
lines of code we have a local model
using Olema and custom local tools
that our model can use.
Perfect. So our agents need
to take action. So how agents take
action outside the world,
that's the the meaning of the tools.
So how a tool works basically.
The agent
use a tool
to make an action
externally.
I always say that the uh tools
are like the the small handies of
the agents because have this powerful
to extend the capabilities outside
the scope of the, the single agent.
So how, how, what kind of actions
we can take, for instance, in this case, in this
specific workloads,
with sensors, analyze images, query
some databases, create work, uh, work orders,
send alerts, or anything that we can
code, how it works.
Here, we're gonna talk about things and then
show you the code.
So, here's how we create a Python
function that we can turn into a
tool. Same as before,
we're importing the agents
and now the tool from from strengths.
Creating the
the function to read sensors
and then we have some important info here in the
documentation. No,
yeah, that's right.
So this function, uh,
this function Python function read a sensor
we receive the sensor ID
and we have a
local endpoint
to trigger to receive, uh,
sorry, pull
some data.
So this gate to a URL we are using
request, uh, as a library to
get uh the data from the URL
and that's all we receive the data
from that, uh, mod bus TCP
raise for status, wait for that.
Have the answer.
Create adjacent to return or a dictionary
to return
in the function,
but the most important thing here is not
the function itself. It's the
decorator, the tool decorator.
With a single decorator we are creating this
specific,
uh, function. We are converting this function
into a tool that an agent
can use.
One important thing, Anna,
duck string,
it's the way that we define
the agent,
what is the purpose of this, um,
of this function. In this case, the
duck string says that,
uh, you can use this for, uh, read real-time
data for industrial sensor,
and the arguments that you have to send is the sensor
ID, and that's all.
The agent with this dock string will
identify how to create the
invocation process, the execution process of
this tool.
So the dogs are super important, so the
agent knows not only what the tool does
but what information he needs to
call that tool.
And apart from custom tools like
the ones that we just showed you.
Strengths has a set of tools
that are ready to use for the
operations for the actions that we most frequently
use. So,
it has an HTTP request one that
we can use to query APIs,
talk to sensors,
has system ones that we can also use
to run local diagnostics.
Workflows
we can even
give in to a human in the loop when we need
more critical
approvals, and this is super important because
you know agents can work autonomously,
but the best practice indicate us to use
human in the loop to validate
that capabilities.
And file operations. So, here my
personal recommendation to you is to check the strengths
documentations to see the ones that you have available because
I did create a
custom tool to save files and then I
figured out
one already existed.
And there are many more. I mean, there is only
a subset of tools that we find
valuable for these warlocks, but there are many.
More community built tools
and one more important thing about
community tools, remember that red agents,
it's an open source
solution so you can
make a for, create a tool, open a PR,
and the the strength agentsten
team can validate that tool and maybe
include into into the next release.
Perfect.
So let's talk how we can
interact with other
caveman systems.
So we have our agents running in
the edge, and even though we're
used to now having G AIs and chatbots
and models wherever we are, there are still
systems that require all
systems, yes, more primitive
data. So
that's why we have the structured output, uh,
as Ana mentioned, we have some ERPs,
CRMs, MIS, etc.
that, uh,
talk with other with other systems using
let's say APIs.
Hopefully maybe a lot of
these systems use rest APIs,
but other other systems
still use soap
envelopes to communicate with.
So we structured outputs how it works
basically the agent can receive.
Byanic model. Byanic model is only
a thing to define a data structure.
For instance, we have a a set
of data that we we need to
send to the API so we
can define the specific um
JSON format, let's say.
And then we can send the Pythonic
model to the agent and receive the
specific Jason as our answer
without any other data, you know,
models are very verbose, yes,
so we don't want to get a bunch of texts
and send that to an external system
that's expecting
an API call with specific
data. That's why we are using
structure output
andres has a really nice way of doing that.
So we, we're using pedantic here as David
mentioned, and we're creating this model
for a work order.
So here we're specifying the fields and
their types, and we even have a description
so the model can have additional information
on what those fields are.
So we have a part ID, the priority,
description, and estimated hours.
And that's our structured output.
And now when we are interacting with
the agent,
we Send the agent
that exact information
so we can answer us with.
The data type that other systems are
expecting in this example,
uh we are um talking
with the agent that the compressor
have an abnormal vibration that agent
maybe have some tools to analyze that
information and
with the structured output we're creating adjacent
or a dictionary with this
with that specific uh fields
in the exact order using the same
uh um values that
we are expecting too
so. After
that we can validate that results,
get into that variables directly, uh,
as part of the, the code,
and at last we can send this
information to an external system
without any intervention. Automatically
the agent is capable to create the
JSON and send
into the uh the
API. So instead
of sending a very large text saying
probably excellent question, this is your,
what you're looking for, we're sending the
specific data or external systems need.
Fantastic. So up until now we
talked about tools which are how
agents take actions.
We talked about some community tools
and we talked about how to structure our
output so our agents can communicate with
external systems.
What else? What else do we need?
So our agents,
we don't want them to forget things that happened, right?
So if a specific machine
required maintenance or was showing
an abnormal temperature or something.
We want the agent to remember that.
So we have session management
out of the box session management with persistent
memory with strength agents.
So in the case without,
without sessions, maybe we are, we
are interacting with the agent
and asking about check on pressure
or the agent and the agent
found some, some important data.
But maybe the app crashes.
The legacy hardware that we are using,
uh, power off. There's a power outage.
Yes, so if the app starts
and you ask again,
they just will say.
What are you talking about, man?
I don't, I don't know what are you talking about.
So like me yesterday at the omnia,
we don't want that to happen.
So with sessions
it's a whole different story.
The user asks the agent to
check on the compressor,
and then if the app restarts.
The agent can keep the conversation going.
Great. So
how it works basically, we only need
to import the library.
So, um, we import file session
manager. It's important to notice that,
uh, one agents have other ways to manage
the sessions like Dynamo DB, S3,
etc. But in this case we don't have connection.
We are not going to use that tools. So
we are using the file session manager. We only have
to define
the session ID that can be a unique
ID. Uh, per
user per unit per
machine, etc.
and we are going to store the data.
In this case we are storing the data in JSON format
locally in the same
computer that the agent is running.
And the agent
will receive the session manager
instance, and that's all.
The agent will be able
to uh communicate
and remember things
across the context.
Yeah, and here we're using the local file
system but we could be using SQL
or Reddit there or
if we're connected to the cloud other solutions.
At last, model context protocol.
This is a well known protocol created
by Anthropic last year.
We are now in the
and Model context Protocol is basically
a tool
that, uh, other vendors can expose to
you. You can, uh, install
or instance in your strength agent,
uh, agent,
and automatically
all the tools and data sources that that MCP,
uh, describes are available for you.
What do we have in the code?
Let's check.
So we have our imports
as usual.
And one thing that I appreciate about rends
is that we can import those
tools from the library and use them, same as
we did for the session management
or for the custom tools.
We don't have to be creating things ourselves.
We import our custom uh tools
and in this case I am uh importing
or calling an MCP server from
MongoDB.
Notice
sorry that at the end of the arguments
we have a local host URL
URI, so we are invoking a a
Mongo
collection locally.
So if you're using MCP
servers on your
coding assistant or on cloud
desktop,
you're used to that type of
information. But if not, we
just need to say which how the
The model is gonna communicate with that
information. Here's locally, so we're using
UV
and then
the
the arguments for MongoDB.
After that
we need to have to
import the full list of Mongo MCP
and then pass as a tool into
the agent.
So MCP is no more than like
tools exposed by third party
vendors that you can import
as a custom tool. Yes, but here
instead of David and I creating
custom Python code that would connect
to our local Mongo DB database
and get that information,
we're using the MCP server that already
exists for that.
And we can keep talking to
the agent as we've been doing so far.
So in this case with this Mongo MCP server
we are able to communicate to the the
database,
uh, show collections,
insert, um, uh, attributes,
insert data, modify data in
uh we can delete data too, so
it's important to implement human in the loop
process to validate if the action that
the agent going to take it's the best path
to accomplish the task.
Yeah, and here we're saving log information to
Mongo DB.
OK, so we showed you the code. Now
it's time for you to see it
running. Great,
who knows Quo?
No. The people
that know that don't know Kiro, it's
under the rocks, or?
Just joking. Quiro is the new agentic
idea from AWS.
It's an amazing tool to build
solutions. Let's open.
My
Perfect. Demo
perfect. So the reason
why we talked about Hiro is because
Hiro helped us build this demo
today. 100%,
but spec driven development, not vibe coding.
So this is a Jupiter notebook. This is not
the final demo. This is a
baby step
process. First we are going to.
Review how it works. Every of these,
uh, capabilities
that we, uh, talked previously.
This, uh, Jupiter notebook will be available
in our GitHub repo, so you later
will be able to, uh,
interact with them. Yeah, we have a QR code
for that on the next slide.
Great. That's a start. So
we are instancing
a, uh,
Olama model local host.
Notice that we are using a custom
model. A community model.
Why? Because Quant 3 is an
amazing model, but has the thinking
process and think a lot,
so thinking takes a lot of time.
For demo purposes we are using a not thinking
model to
speed the capabilities and works
very good. I mean,
accomplished all the tasks that we have in
the demo. Full disclosure here that
David is off the internet.
That's why his trends server is
not working.
So We
are using this uh model
blah blah blah. OK, perfect.
The Olama model is configured
first tool decorator.
We have here,
obviously this is mock-up data
because we don't have IOT devices here, but
imagine that you have some devices
with some data that we you can pull
in production like temperature sensors,
humidity sensors, value actuators,
etc. I am going to
create a reed sensor tool
uh sorry function but with the tool
decorator now
this function it's able to
use by the agent.
So, same as we saw on the slides,
we give the documentation
information to the agents so he knows what
those tools are going to be doing.
And how to call them.
On the other hand, we have a control device, basically
a tool that indicates a
specific
IOT device that we can interact
with to take another action.
So, I'm going to run this piece of code.
We have these 3, these 2 different
functions ready.
And we have 3
devices available temperature sensor,
humidity sensor,
and valve actor.
How we can use this tool with an agent.
So basically we create, we create
an agent,
we set
the Olama model that we previously
instanced. We inject
the tools, the two different tools that
we created before,
and in with a system pro the
LLM personality
we, uh, define
what this agent will accomplish. So
it's an IOT control agent for an
industrial facility and it's gonna help
users monitor the sensors.
I can ask to the IUT agent, what
is the current temperature of the production floor,
so we indicate what
which sensor I need to analyze.
And now
The agent is answering me. The current on the production floor, it's
24:19.
Let's control tractor.
The IOT agent will receive the open the
cooling system,
the name of the valve that needs to open.
And now it's taking action. It's
calling the
tool to take an action and open.
The
system evolve.
Another amazing capability that that agents
bring to us it's the multi-process,
uh, multi-step operations.
For instance,
in a single shot operation you send a prompt
and the LLM
response. That's all.
In the agenttic loop,
the agent receives a complex or maybe
in this case two different, um,
responsibilities or operations,
and the agent
will accomplish every task
and after that will answer you.
So with the multi-step operation,
I mean,
I ask him, check the humidity first task.
And tell me if it's in an acceptable range.
2nd task.
Reed sensor
uh the agent used the tool with sensor
uh got the storage area
humidity and then validates
with a second tool.
If it's an acceptable range.
Great, this is the first.
Let's check the demo number 2,
the structured output.
There are a lot of Scada systems integrated
in industry, but a lot of them creates
this. Let's run
this Create
these awful
responses
basically text
TXT files
without any parsing process uh
basically it's for printing and uh
human readable but the system need
to understand and get data
from this scatter response
so. We have here
different Byanic models,
sensor reading, uh, Byanic
model, alarm info, equipment
status, and production metrics.
Every of, uh, every one of
these, um, models have a specific
data definition,
uh, not only in naming
pro in the naming but in the data
type. I'm
going to run this.
So,
we are simulating a scatter response.
Basically
this
TXT file
and then
with an uh small agent
er that have a data extraction task
we can
uh get.
The structured output.
Of the Scala report.
Basically, with production metrics,
we er um extract
successfully the data
and now.
We can access individual fields
from this structured output.
We can use that structured output,
as we mentioned to send directly to other.
Systems.
Can, can we go back a little bit
on the, when we talk to the agent
when we talk to the agent here, so
when, when we say that the structure
output model is the production metrics, that's
when we're telling our agent
to use that pedantic model that we
defined and then give its
answers on that format that we are,
we are expecting.
So, the 3rd
session management. So, we talked about
tools, we talked about structured
outputs, and now how we're gonna manage
the session and the memory of the agent
between interactions.
In this example, we are defining the session
the session, the local storage
directory.
Cleaning if it's previous.
We are simulating a session ID
in this case each operator
001,
We instance the file session manager.
And then
We can start interacting with the
agent.
You're an edge device diagnostic assistant
blah blah blah, and we're giving the
session manager when we're creating
this instance of the, the agent
so we know where it should be storing
uh session information.
We have a first interaction.
A second interaction.
And a third
interaction.
Requesting the summary.
We simulate a failure.
And then
Let's recover
From that error.
We have a session ID,
the total messages that we previously have,
where are the sessions? Where are the messages.
And we can
Start talking again.
Without any
data loss.
Continue the conversation.
Operation continues until after we start and
It broke.
Do you want all the time. Do you wanna use hero to
fix it?
I don't have internet. Oh yes.
So
But the idea is that the session manager here
you could be using a SQL database,
but here we're using local file storage you're
gonna be storing those messages and then you
can restart your conversation with
the with the agent.
The last capability is the integration.
Very quick, we are going to create a.
A SQLite database edge telemetry.
2, because it's my 2nd test.
And we are including the MCP
server SQL Lite
directly as a tool.
Here Um,
the list of tools.
I will run this.
So to the agent that we are creating with
strengths that MCP
server is
another tool.
Exactly. And now we are listing the tools
that the MCP have like read query, write
query, create table, etc.
And we can start
using those tools in a new
agent.
We simply passing the tools.
In the instance of the agent.
And we're creating a database.
The agent is using the create table, the
described table
tool. And
now we can.
Insert
each device data
on this SQL lite.
With natural language we are telling the agent
to insert some data.
And the agent
It's able
To write the correct queries,
read the queries,
try to
insert.
And at the end,
5 telemetry records have been successfully
inserted.
Let's query that data that we recently
um
write. We
have an agent, the tools,
we are asking the agent, show me all the telemetry
records
in the device, telemetry table.
And we use the read quality
to tool
to review every
uh row that are
that are in the table.
Analytical query.
We're asking with natural language to calculate
the average value for each device ID
in the device elementary table.
So if I don't remember what's the SQL
query to get the average of
something, 2 years ago I wrote my
last query line code.
So the MCP server
was capable to read the
structure of the table,
create the specific
uh query that we need to run to accomplish the
task, and that's all
we have the results.
Ready to use.
This Jupiter notebook is available in our
GitHub repo, but
we also have in the GitHub repo.
Our edge operator agent,
so that was the demo for learning purposes.
Now we have, uh,
another demo that's more interactive.
Oh, it's using my same session so it's
recovering the data from the last session.
OK, at least here we're able to show the session
management in in action.
So
I will ask
I opened a new session ID
check this.
So I can start a new conversation.
So the agent answered me that the
temperature sensor
value is 426 C
and the time that was recorded was actually
now. So
we can. Ask about
Some other.
The state
Let's close
some valves.
And in the back.
This agent
It's, it's calling tools basically.
But on the front end
we are interacting with
a natural language.
What else we have?
Perfect. The humidity sensor.
So we are running locally
with Olama, but let's check.
Perfect, we recovered the the the Internet.
What happens if we
open a new session
or no, the same session?
Only New check,
we're going to start working with cloth.
And now we are talking with Bertrag.
So notice the the latency.
It's very different
than the local ulama capabilities.
So let's
ask again.
Which
devices.
You have.
So it has access to exactly the
same tools. It's the same agent
with a different model.
Before we were running it locally on the VS
computer and now we are running a
remote agent uh through through
Bedrock in the cloud.
And basically it's a single
uh change of line. So
instead of uh calling uh the Olama
model we are calling the default
er bedrock agenter
LLM. So
This is the demo that we have for for
attendees,
but.
We have for you
This repository
not only the Jupiter notebook
but the but the full
streamlet UI and the agent
running on on the edge.
So
what else Anna?
I think it's
since some of you don't know Kiro, I think
it's a good opportunity to give a brief
overview of Kiro for sure if you feel
comfortable doing that 100%.
He don't have to to have the capability
of accomplished that.
So
Are we in the demo?
I think one of the first things that we
wanna talk to you about,
um, usually when there's less Zoom
you can see a little ghost here that's hero.
And same as we're using some of you might be
using MCP servers
with cloud desktop or
you're coding agents,
we can connect at different MCP servers
to to hero
and there's an MCP server for
strengths.
So usually we have this problem when a
library is too new or
when it has constant updates
if we talk to the models that have a cutoff
date on their training.
They're not gonna give us
up to date or accurate coding
recommendations for the library,
so the strands agents MCP
server really helped us in this 100%.
In fact, without this strand agents
MCP server,
Quiro will be unable to accomplish the
task. Yes, so most likely
when the model that Kiro's using was trained,
there wasn't strengths SDK information available.
So highly recommend you to use it.
You can enable and disable them so the
model knows better what to do and not to do,
and you can just ask questions about the,
the strengths documentations for sure and not
only for strength documentation, but for AWS
AWS have more than 40 MCP
servers. One of my favorite,
it's the AWS documentation MCP.
So basically we have
the 100%
docs
available in our LLM Agentic
uh ID.
So we don't need to review the documentation
because really it's up to date. It's query
the the real time documentation.
And I don't know if you use steering here,
but steering docs we can create a steering
dock just telling Kiro whenever you're creating
strengths code, please check the
up to-date documentation on strengths
using the MCP server.
So it's instructions that the agents
are going to use whenever we
make a request. It's
directing Kiro on what to do.
I have here some.
Uh, steering
This was for the road to bring the hackathon.
So basically I prepare three different
steerings to define
what uh we are going to do,
what kind of technology, the structure of
the,
um,
my whole project,
the technology that I want to use in this case
I opt to use strand agents, of
course, strand tools, agent SOPs,
the MCP
SDKs.
And all the AWS services that I try,
I, I'll try to, to use on
that project. So similar as
we were saying that our agents in the edge
need session management and memory.
This is the way of giving memory to your
coding assistant so it knows what your project
is about, the folder structure
that you're using, the technologies.
So just wanted to give them that quick uh
hero intro
since some of them didn't know and really really
powerful agent hooks another capability.
I always for every change that Quiro
uh creates
I am commit creating a commit automatically
because Quiro handle all these uh capabilities
that creates a kid commit,
uh, in every
uh in every task that Quiro
a complete.
So I think.
We can return to our
Session here.
And as a wrap up,
Download the uh ripple.
Check the ripple if you have
ideas, if you have uh some
uh challenges that you are facing. Contact
us. We are more than happy to help you.
We are more than happy to, uh,
describe these challenges for you and help
to, uh,
find the best way
to create agents not only in
the edge
for, uh, uh, but in the cloud
too. So
Don't wait for your cloud
to think, but
Use the cloud to think bigger.
Thank you so much, Tim.