- [James] All right, let's
go ahead and get started.
Welcome everyone.
Thanks so much for coming
over here for this code talk.
My name is James Hood.
I'm a principal software
engineer at Amazon.
I know it's kind of late
in the day on day one.
We are, we're gonna make sure
to keep it interesting for you.
You'll definitely wanna stay for my part,
I have a very ambitious code exercise
that I'm gonna do for you all.
So we'll see how it goes.
But first I wanna hand off to Maish.
- [Maish] Thank you very much James.
Firstly, thank you all for
choosing us over the expo hall.
There's more swag tomorrow.
Don't worry, there's more than
enough for everybody else.
My name is Maish Saidel-Keesing
and I'm a senior developer
advocate with AWS.
I work in the marketing organization.
And before we start, there's
a couple of things I'd like
to get off, or clear.
Firstly, I have two hearing
aids, so if you have a question,
please put up your hand.
I can see not very well, but we can see,
put up your question
and please speak loudly
so I can hear properly
because we don't have
a mic running around the room.
That's number one.
Number two, we are working
with code assistance,
which means the code is whatever,
when you work with the code assistance,
it's non-deterministic
and James will give you the
actual good way we use that,
works perfectly, how we try
to use it at least internally.
And number three, because
I'm gonna be typing
and James is gonna be typing,
a part of this, James,
this talk is gonna be done
sitting down over here in front
of the laptop 'cause it's
pretty difficult to do that
while we're standing up.
So how did this come about,
which is actually quite interesting,
because I was watching a recording
of a video that James did
for an internal, what we call
principle engineers that
give, on a regular basis,
they give talks internally in Amazon.
And I was looking at one
of the videos and I said,
This is something that
we have to talk about
at re:Invent.
And I said, James, you
wanna come into a session?
He said, yeah, why not?
So the reason we did
this is because I think
the story that we have to tell is,
in Amazon itself or in AWS
specifically, we have kind
of adopted generative AI
tooling with open arms.
We use it all day every day,
anywhere and everywhere.
And we are here to share a
bit about how our story goes,
how we do this internally inside Amazon.
We're not gonna be
giving any trade secrets.
A lot of it is common sense,
but it's good to see it's like
written out in a proper way
so you can understand how that works.
And what we did internally in Amazon,
we use a something called a mechanism.
Has anybody heard of an
AWS and Amazon mechanism?
Mechanism is a tool which we
do where when something works,
we like to share that with
the rest of the company
and we take it and we codify
it or put it into a tool
and put into we call it a mechanism.
And this mechanism works
very, very well with one
of our leadership principles,
which is invent and simplify,
where we take a virtuous cycle
and it reinforces the behavior
for other teams that can use it.
So instead of everybody
having to reinvent the wheel,
one team does it, gives
it to everybody else
and everybody starts contributing, sorry,
starts contributing
directly back into the tool
to make everything better.
So should we start jumping in?
First things first, can we move over?
Yeah. Yep.
Thank you very much.
The code that is being used
here today is on a GitHub repo.
If you want to take a screenshot of that
and follow along, you're
more than welcome.
Some of it, for example, the
examples that I'm gonna give
are available here as an open source repo
that you can use and catch them later,
and also some of the work that
James is gonna do afterwards
of how we use this also in Strand.
So let's first go to how
we use this internally.
And forgive me, I'm gonna go and sit down.
So when we are talking to
an LLM, we have something
that we call zero shot, one shot,
and a few shot prompts.
When you talk to an LLM,
there's a number of ways you
can do that in different means
and different interactions.
The first one is a what
we call a simple shot.
In other words, you
ask the LLM a question.
And this of course is I'm working
over here in the Kiro CLI,
can be done in any coding system,
but we are gonna be doing
everything over here in Kiro.
So asking a coding assistant a question
will give you an answer
and not necessarily always
the answer you want.
So in this case, for me it
is creating code because,
and it does it all in Python,
which is based on whatever
the LLM has been trained.
And slowly but surely will gimme the code
that I want and will give me,
shat I asked in this
case was a script which
will validate an IAM policy,
and this is working very, very slowly,
but we'll have to deal with it.
Okay, so it gives me the
code that I want to create
and that is one way of
interacting with an LLM.
But we have found that there's
better ways to do this.
Here, it gives me the word,
exactly what I asked you to do,
what the function does,
and what it will return.
But that is a zero shot.
In other words, to just ask an
LLM to do something for you.
But if you provide more context
to the LLM, for example,
I know how to write a function
which does in this case
a validation of an email.
This is what I know and
I ask it to continue
to do the same question.
In this case things are gonna change,
because firstly, it
understands I didn't want to,
the code that I wanted to
be generated would not be
in Python because I gave an example
in this case of JavaScript,
and it gave me the answer.
So we said the first is zero
shot, you just ask a question.
The second one is a one
shot. You give it an example.
And when we have a few shot prompting,
you can give multiple examples
which gives even more context.
In this case, this is what I
know, create the same function
and we'll see that the LLM,
when it answers a question,
because you've provided
more information to it,
it'll give you a slightly
different answer.
In this case, there is a
very, very slight difference.
In other words, it did remove
the example policy usage
or the usage for the
example, which I wanted it
to explain to me because it understood
that I'm pretty much,
I know what I'm doing
so I don't have to generate extra code.
When do we use this?
This is what, our best
practice for this kind
of work is when you
have a very simple task,
use zero shot, just ask a question.
But when you have more complex task
and that needs to follow
more of a specific pattern,
like we'll see further on,
use few shot prompting in order
to provide more context
to give you more something
which is more relevant to you.
Another way we use this as
well is something which we call
providing more information to the LLM,
is what we call when you
start prompting to an LLM,
you use the system prompt,
a contextual prompt,
or a role prompting, and
how does that actually look?
So let's have a look at that here.
A system prompt again is a question.
In this case I ask the LLM to
create an EC2 script for me
with a specific tag and give
it to me as a batch function.
So LLM will go and start thinking,
create pretty much what
I asked for it to do,
a batch function with everything inside.
And this is fine, this will work.
You can run the batch, this batch function
or this batch script and it will,
and we'll start querying
all your EC2 instances
with the specific tag.
But I can provide also in
this case some context.
And in this case I'm
giving the LLM as part
of the same question, more
context of how I would
like to think.
In this case I'm saying IRT
managers multiple instances
across multiple accounts and we give
and the way we organize our project.
So I would like you to create a script
that will also be suitable for this.
I could have given that same prompt,
but when we use this
actual context prompt,
we start giving the LLM more information
about how we would like to work
and it'll create the best script for me
with the examples and whatever else it is.
And so this will currently go through
and print them out screen by screen.
The last one we have is role prompting.
Role prompting is okay,
it's pretty much the same
as what we call context prompt.
But in this case we say, okay, you are A.
A lot of people use this.
And when you start prompting
for, you are a specialist
in nuclear technology, please
create something for me,
or you are a radiologist that knows how
to diagnose different MRI things.
So you give the LLM
which you're working
with different context.
And in this case I'm asking you are an AWS
senior solutions architect
or solutions architect
and you manage infrastructure
and start creating a script for me.
So in this case, probably
the script will be very,
very similar to the first one,
but there might be extra nuances
because it has already some
kind of idea of what kind
of information you're looking for
and perhaps how to cater
that information directly
for the person for you.
Any questions so far?
No question? No question?
Perfect.
Okay.
The best practice that we have
for this is of course is to use this,
is to combine these techniques
when you're talking about complex tasks,
start with the context,
then define the role
and then specify the task and
the desired output format.
In other words, be as specific
as you can when interacting with some kind
of coding assistance so you
can get the most benefit out
from these tools as well.
The next thing I would like
to show you is something which
we call self-consistency prompting.
This is a powerful technique
that improves Kiro CLI,
or in this case, in our
case, some kind of reasoning
by generating multiple
different independent scenarios
or solutions to the same
question and same problem
and asking you to select
that same behavior.
Let's have a look at an example.
Self consistency.
I ask you a question, I need to design
a complex architecture for multi-region,
highly available applications.
I would like it to explore
three different approaches
to this problem, and these are the factors
it has to take into account,
in this case cost, operational
complexity, latency,
and after it's considered
these three different options
to select one of those and
give me a recommendation.
So assuming this works and
we'll see if it does it or not
because it had some problems
before, it'll start going
through the scenario, okay,
you want to build something,
an active, there's three
different ways of doing it.
Active-active, active-passive,
and active with read replicas.
And it's asking me to give more details.
I could of course get,
I want this as a frontend
application, whatever else it is.
In this case I'm just gonna say there
are no more details, go.
It'll start building whatever
application it decides.
But now it'll start going through the 3D.
There's three different
multi-region deployments,
three ways of doing it.
Active-active, active
with a global database,
active-active with the
primary rights balanced,
and it'll give me, these
are your recommendations.
The way we use this enables
us, the way that works
is because the technique
encourages the LLM,
in this case, Kiro,
to generate diverse reasoning
paths for the same problem
by exploring multiple perspectives.
Kiro, in this case, can
identify more of our solutions.
And the final answer that we get from it,
because I asked you to choose one
of the three out whatever it is
will probably more consistent based on
if I do this more than multiple times>
When do we use the self-consistency model,
when we have complex
architecture decisions
or problems we're trying
to solve troubleshooting
with difficult root causes,
some kind of security analysis,
and of course where we have
like performance optimizations,
we'll see that example
in a second that need
to be considered when we think
very, very specifically how,
what the options are and how
we have to address the problem.
And the best practice here is
of course always ask the LLM
to generate more than one answer
so it can give you more options.
Firstly, because you don't
have to always trust,
you will start thinking for itself
and provide you multiple solutions
and ask it to choose out of the three.
Giving things more options,
more than one option will be
very, very beneficial for you.
Another way we use this as
part of self consistency
is what we call a tree of thought,
also for solving problems.
So a tree of thought is essentially
asking the LLM to solve a problem for me
by giving it explicit directions
how I wanted it solved.
In this case, I wanted
to consider in this case
three possible bottlenecks for my problem,
which are cold starts, memory constraints,
and external API calls.
For each of those bottlenecks,
give me three different possible solutions
and for each of those solutions,
evaluate the pros and cons.
I'm going from, I have a lambda problem,
these could be my different
issues which I'm trying to,
these what I think could be the problem.
For each of them, start
looking at different options,
how I would solve them.
And in the end, bring this all together
to give me some kind of a recommendation.
So when doing this, of course
it allows Kiro to start
working and trying to
actually solve a very,
very big problem.
You define a structured
exploration with multiple branches.
Each of the branch who
represents a different aspect
or approach to the problem.
And Kiro explores each of these branches
and eventually it comes out
with some kind of recommendation
to identify an optimal solution.
When do we use this again
with complex problems,
with multiple variables, and of course,
decision making with numerous
interactions and factors
which we have to take into account.
And the best practice
here for tree of thought
is of course you have
to structure your prompt
with very clear branches
and evaluation criteria.
You say, okay, just do a tree of thought
and figure it out for
me, it won't really help.
You have to give it
very direct instructions
how you want this to work,
and it will give you a much
more comprehensive analysis.
And you can actually combine the two.
So you can combine tree of
thought and self consistency.
In this case it's even more complex.
I want to design a
disaster recovery solution,
a tree of thought to explore
three different ways for each
of those to start analysis.
So in other words, we are
combining in even more
of a complex way, but we
are doing, letting all,
what we love to call the
undifferentiated heavy lifting
is over to the LLM and it
provides me with an option
or a solution.
So here it goes to the different
options as you can see.
And the way we use this, of course,
is designing multiple when we use
for mission critical system design
or we have architectural
decisions that we have to take
and we know that they have high risks
on one way or the other.
So at least we can get the information.
And from here it starts
giving me an implementation
and gives me the different
kind of approach.
Before the last time I did this,
it actually gave me a matrix,
but now I see it doesn't.
So that's the wonderful thing about LLMs.
It's not consistent.
But still when combining these techniques,
be very explicit against how you want Kiro
to follow this kind of trail of thought,
providing clear guidance
in how you want to organize
the explorations.
And although this will give you
a full, a full clear picture
of what you would like to get.
Expanding these tools with context.
So we've been talking about,
I've been talking about
context a lot over here.
The more information you provide,
the more, the better answers you'll get.
And of course with Kiro for example,
almost in every other
tool you can add context.
So in my case I'm going to,
in Amazon we have a kind
of peculiar way of writing stuff.
Okay, we have a writing style internally,
and in my case of course,
and it'll be the same thing.
Usually these things have
been documented up the wazoo
and everything is working correctly
and you have a knowledge
base of how that works.
So if you add that into your
LLM, you can use that as part
of the way you can use it to help you.
So in this case, I've added
the way we write narratives,
one pagers, six pagers,
PR, FAQs into the context.
And I'm going to ask Kiro
to write me a narrative.
And of course this is not a real product,
so please don't shoot the
messenger, whatever it is.
But I would like to start
how it helps tadpoles
to grow into frogs.
But because I've already
loaded all the context
and the way we write documents,
it knows exactly how to structure it.
It knows exactly what
questions to ask me in order
to help me fill in the
way to make more clear
and concise and comprehensive document
which I need in order to help me.
So in this case, the success
metrics I need to add in
and there is recommendations
and the market opportunity,
everything we know
how we usually write a document.
But using these kind of tools in order
to help you do these kind of,
to write these documents makes things
a lot, lot easier.
The last thing I would like to share just
before I hand it over to
James is one more technique
which we use, which we call
explore, plan, code and commit.
So.
One thing which LLMs are very, very good
is their understanding
what you've written.
So you can provide it the code
and in this case tell it to,
I've got a code base
over here, in this case,
three different JavaScript
files where I've written codes,
what my code is.
And you can do this on large
code bases if you would like.
And it'll start reading all the documents
and understand all the
different dependencies.
And I remember James
showed me a an example
of how you can do this to
create all the documentation
and the diagrams and
the flows and the APIs
and you might even show that later on.
So in this case,
I've got three different
files over here which does
a authentication mechanism
for some application.
So the LLM now understands
what I have in my code base.
I can ask, as we said, the
first one was to explore,
then I would like it to
plan based on what you've
already understood from my code base,
please implement a password reset feature.
So again, the style is already there.
The way I write my code
in the same kind of style
as well is also over there.
So I can go in to see, and I
gave you some more instructions
to take in security considerations,
that has to be robust,
et cetera, et cetera.
And it gives me a plan of how I'm going
to implement this feature.
And then of course, we plan,
plan, sorry, explore, plan.
I'm going to ask it to
now create the code for me
because it already has,
and of course I can iterate on this plan
and make it more robust
to add in more information
according to what I would like.
But based on what it already
knows in this specific example,
I'm going to ask it to
try write the code for me
and make the changes.
So this is a way which
we use this mechanism
of what we say, explain, explore, plan,
explore, plan, code, which
is generating the code
in this case and it'll
be already over here
at computer function.
And of course commit, we can also use.
In this case, I can ask
it to commit the code
for me if I would like,
but in this case I'm not
connected to a production system.
So I'm just gonna ask it
to use my internal style
that I have of the way we write code,
commit messages with the best practices,
links to whatever documentation to it is.
And I could also say, also
commit and submit the PR
if I would like to, but it's
not connected to a repository.
But here in this case there's no changes.
But in other words, this
would be the implementation,
this would be how you would do
it, and et cetera, et cetera.
These are some of the
techniques which we actually use
internally every day, all day.
And the good thing is we've
codified a lot of it as well.
And in the repository, which
we have shared in the beginning
of the session, and if you
want at the end of the session,
and didn't take this QR
code, we'll put it up again.
Or actually, you know what,
I'll actually put it up now.
Easier.
Whoever hasn't taken a picture
of the QR code can use it.
Now the actual code that
I just with all explaining
all of these examples
today is up there as part
of the the open source that
you can actually use it
and see how you can of course
implement it internally
in your organization or
expand on it and add whatever
kind of best practice that you have
that you have learned from your things.
And with that, I'm gonna
hand it over to James
to talk to us a little
about Strands, Agent SOPs.
- [James] Alright, thank you.
Do you mind me grabbing this?
All right, for those of
you who came in late,
my name's James Hood, I'm a
principal engineer at Amazon.
I've been with the company 16 years,
most of that time in AWS.
I spent about five years in
retail fulfillment software
in the middle there.
And I am also a former AI skeptic.
My previous experience with AI
before this year was trying out a bunch
of flashy demos on real world
code and watching it crash
and burn and feeling very
skeptical and not very satisfied.
That changed for me this
year early in February
where I realized that
some of these techniques
that Maish was talking about,
it's really the combination
of the tools, you know,
reasoning models got better,
MCP became much more popular.
And then, but my big AHA moment
was around the techniques that we use.
So today I'm gonna spend,
I have a very ambitious code talk for you.
I'm gonna talk to you about Agent SOP,
which stands for Agent
Standard Operating Procedures.
And this is something we just open sourced
less than two weeks ago.
It's something that was actually
an innovation internally
by our builder community.
And I'm gonna show you
why they're so cool.
They're a deceptively simple concept
that is incredibly
powerful when you use them.
Maish was just showing you a lot
of great prompt engineering
techniques and to use these LLMs
and be successful with them,
prompt engineering is an
important skill to have.
However, did you notice he was copying
and pasting a lot of prompts, right?
Earlier this year that was
happening around Amazon,
people copying and pasting these kind
of magic incantations,
and we decided there had
to be something better.
And that's what Agent SOPs,
that's where they came from.
So SOP stands for Standard
Operating Procedure.
A standard operating
procedure is a document
that gives a detailed step,
step-by-step list of how
to accomplish some routine task.
So I'm going to start out with,
I actually have the Agent SOP,
lemme see if this is the right window.
Nope.
All right, so I'm in the
Agent SOP directory right now
and I have the, as part of
this open source offering,
we released the
strands-agent's SOP MCP server.
And this MCP server includes
some prompts by default.
And one of these prompts is
called code-based summary.
And I'm gonna go ahead and run it.
What this does, this is an
MCP prompt, and Agent SOPs
you can think of as kind of
a super prompt for an agent.
I'll get this one started
and then I'll break it down for you.
So this one is going to help
me summarize my code base.
Code base path is a required parameter
and it set all default
to my current directory,
which is what I want.
I also want to consolidate it
or I want to generate a consolidated file.
And the default is agents.md.
So I'm just gonna say consolidated true.
Okay, and then it's gonna get going.
Alright, so now let's take a closer look
at this code base summary.
This is the Agent SOP repository.
And if I pull up the actual
code base summary, SOP,
what you'll see is it's
actually just marked down
and it has a title, it has an
overview of what the SOP does.
It says it analyzes a code base,
generates comprehensive documentation.
It does support this
parameter section with some
of them optional and
some of them required,
the optional ones having defaults.
And then it's a list of steps.
It just says step one, set
up and directory structure.
So initialize the analysis environment
and create necessary directory structure.
But this is where the magic happens.
So step one is set up
and directory structure.
Step two is analyze code-based structure.
Step three is generate documentation file.
But what you'll notice is
that on each of these steps,
not only does it give a
one-liner of what that step is,
it has this list of constraints.
And these constraints use
this RFC 2119 style keywords
like must all in caps or
should or must not or may.
And it constrains the
behavior of this step.
It adds these constraints
saying you must validate
that the code base path
exists and is accessible.
You must create the output
directory if it doesn't exist.
If we look further down,
you can see here you
must use mermaid diagrams
for all visual representations.
So what these, what we've found, so again,
Agent SOP, title, overview,
parameters, optionally,
and then steps with constraints.
Finally examples, because
LLMs work very well
when you give them examples.
And then troubleshooting steps as well.
Let me, these are still examples.
Yeah.
And then troubleshooting steps.
What we have found is that agents
and models are extremely good
at following these instructions.
This took us from kind of models going off
the rails all over the place.
Like I could just prompt it
and say explore this code base
and write up some documentation for me,
and I could run that 20 times
and get very differing results.
But with this SOP
format, I've been talking
and showing you this, in the meantime,
it's been generating these files.
So code base info, this gives
an overview of the code base,
it gives a description,
gives the technology stack,
it gives the project structure.
And it will do this every
time, every time you run it,
this document will contain these sections.
There'll be some variance
in what it describes,
but it'll have your code
base info, your architecture,
which if you remember I said
to use mermaid diagrams.
So it draws up these
mermaid diagrams of kind
of the architectural
structure of this code base.
And you can see that.
It does components.
Oh, it just added interfaces.
So it's running and then it's gonna
generate all of these summary files.
And then from that, because
I said consolidate, true,
it's going to generate a
consolidated agents.md file
for my coding assistant
that is made up of all
of this information that it found.
So now my agent is gonna be ready to go.
I'm a principal engineer.
We have these principal tenets
at Amazon like have resounding impact.
One of them is called
technically fearless.
And I can tell you that thanks to AI
and these Agent SOPs, my level
of technical fearlessness
has grown orders of magnitude this year
because I can go into any code base
and I can run this and
then my agent has it,
I can read it, obviously,
I can read what the code base is like,
and then my agent is also
geared up at that point
to then help me navigate that code base
and even implement
features and changes in it.
Maish showed you that context feature.
Yeah, Maish had showed
you that context feature.
I actually wrote that.
I went from concept to PR in two days.
It was in a code base that
I, I wasn't on that team,
it was a code base that
I wasn't familiar with
in a language that I didn't know.
And it went from concept,
I thought I was building
a proof of concept.
It went concept to PR in two days
and then concept to
production in seven days,
which was wild.
And that was kind of my
mind blowing Aha moment
from earlier this year.
Okay, so you may be
looking at this Agent SOP,
and first off, like these,
we've made these four Agent SOPs
available to use because they're really
from internal Amazon.
Like we actually use these internally.
These are by far the most popular ones.
Now looking at this
code-based summary, SOP,
you may be thinking, boy, that
looks like a pain to write.
It's very long and arduous
and I don't recommend
you write 'em by hand.
I write them with my AI agent.
So what we've done is we've
created a steering file.
And so we've created a rule,
a steering file that defines
this SOP format for the agent.
You don't need to worry
too much about this,
but when you install the Agent SOPs,
so we have this Strands Agent SOPs CLI,
that you can use it to run the MCP server.
You can use it to convert SOPs over
to agent skills from Anthropic,
if you've heard of those.
And then there's this rule command as well
where you can say rule and
then it outputs that rule.
And there are instructions
in the README on how to put
that into a cursor rule
if you like using cursor
or put it into a Kiro steering file, or,
the nice thing with Agent SOP is that
it's even tool-agnostic.
Any LLM, right, any AI
agent that can take an SOP
can work with this.
So I wanna show you
really quickly authoring
what it looks like to author Agent SOP.
So I'm going to add, I already copied
that rule into my Kiro steering files.
And so now you can see
that this just pins this format file
into the conversation context.
So even if I run clear at this point,
so I've cleared my conversation history,
the context command makes
sure that this stays pinned.
So I can say create an Agent SOP that,
given a person's name,
outputs a short, fun poem
incorporating their name.
And then over here I'm gonna open up...
So I've pre-configured
now that that MCP server
can take an additional parameter
where you can specify different
folders for it to look
for SOPs in.
And so I'm authoring this
into one of these SOPs.
So now I have this like name poem, SOP.
And so if I start up
another session of Kiro CLI
with that MCP server loaded,
and then I check the prompts.
All right, you'll see that now
my name poem prompt is here.
So I can run my name poem prompt,
and it'll say, okay, I
need the person's name,
so I'll put my name.
Oh wow, it's confirming the
spelling. You gotta love LLMs.
(audience laughing)
That's awesome.
All right, so here's my poem.
Okay, so create a poem.
Now let's say, so we
can take a look at the,
we can take a look at
what it generated, right?
So it generated, it's
following the same format.
This title overview parameter,
person's name is required, right,
and then it just has
these steps in an example.
But let's say I wanna change
it, let's say I wanna say,
update to include an
optional hometown param.
And yeah, I'll just say
that. Let's see what happens.
And then I'm gonna have
to reload this after.
Okay, so it has the hometown,
and then hopefully it'll know
I mean to incorporate it.
Okay, should incorporate
the hometown if provided.
So it's making those updates,
because it knows the format,
it's making those updates
to the constraints.
So you can just chat back and forth.
You can try out your SOP
and then if you see it
behaving in kind of an odd way
or a way that you don't
expect, you can go back
to your authoring chat and
say, Hey, I want this to behave
this different way.
It's doing this right now.
And it'll add constraints,
which the model then mostly respects.
Yeah, these are still agents
and so I'm gonna say name, poem.
Now you can pass in user input.
I don't know, if you're
kind of eagle-eyed,
you saw that this parameter is
actually called person_name.
When I pass in the parameters,
I'm passing it to the LLM.
So I don't have to be exact,
I could put, I'm from
Tucson, Arizona originally,
but I could have put, my name is James
and I'm from Tucson, Arizona,
and that could have been my
input and it will figure it out.
Okay.
So now I get a little poem
that talks about the desert
and saguaros and stuff like that.
Okay, alright.
So I, as a former AI skeptic,
cute stuff like this is fun,
but I like real world stuff, right?
That's what's most convincing to me.
I just wanted to give you a simple example
so you could understand the SOP format,
but why don't we create another SOP
that you might find slightly
more useful for your job?
How about create an Agent SOP
that triages GitHub issues
for given repo URL?
Let's try that.
Now, keep in mind I have the
GitHub MCP server loaded up
in my agent's context.
So as it's authoring that SOP,
it knows what tools are available to it,
and it can, so that's, you
need to have the MCP servers
that are relevant to what
you're trying to do in here.
Anyone else wanna poem about
them while we're waiting?
Any questions at this point?
- [Attendee] I have one.
- [James] Hand before yours.
(attendee speaking faintly off mic)
- [Attendee] You're
providing code to an LLM,
how do you, what are your
recommendations for making sure
that sensitive information
isn't included in them
in the source code?
- [James] Yeah, so the question was,
when you're providing code
to the LLM, how do you make sure
that there isn't sensitive
information in the code
that you provide in your prompt or-
- [Attendee] Yeah, like what
would you consider information
that you want to not
have provided to the LLM?
Like obviously, you know,
usernames, passwords,
things like that, but anything
else that you recommend?
- [James] Yeah, yeah.
So the question was, is there anything
that you would be careful about
having provided to the LLM?
I do have to say that internally
we use Amazon Bedrock,
which essentially provides you this
like account level privacy
and is not sending your,
it's not sending your request
to like third party model providers.
So I would say internally
we're a little less,
we worry a little bit less about that,
about like sending that
kind of information.
I still, just as an engineer,
I don't have passwords or
credentials in source code.
Like that's just a general security don't,
so I don't generally,
like that's not gonna go
to the large language
model because of that.
- [Attendee] So would you
say it's heavily dependent
on the LLM that you're using, right?
- [James] Yeah, yeah, so
I'd say that, I guess,
the main thing I would
say is with Amazon Bedrock
it's much less of a worry because AWS
is very concerned about
that privacy and about
just like all of our AWS
services where you have
to explicitly give permissions,
and IAM permissions
for any of your, you know,
resources or data to be touched.
So similarly, Bedrock
follows the same paradigm.
- [Attendee] I think that's
important to point out,
Bedrock guarantees that.
- [James] Yes.
- [Attendee] With like a separate entity
from the model provider so
they don't share (indistinct).
Same as running local.
If you're running local, assuming
the model, not, you know,
running code (indistinct).
You've got a level of guarantee there.
- [James] That's right.
(attendee speaking faintly off mic)
All right, so I have my
GitHub issue triage SOP here.
It takes a repo URL like I said,
and then it retrieves open
issues, analyzes each issue,
recommends labels and then
generates a triage report
that it's looking like it's
gonna write it to a file.
That's not exactly what I want here.
I'm gonna say for triage,
search for issues with no labels,
those are the ones to triage.
I also want you to comment
a triage comment in each issue
and apply relevant labels.
Don't rate the report to a file,
just output it and also add a dry run flag
that won't actually make the comments
and just print them out.
All right. That dry run's
just for demo purposes.
Okay. So you can see it's
adding the dry run option.
Defaults to false.
Close this out.
And, sorry to rush along
here, I am, like I said,
I have a very ambitious, I'm going to see
how far I can get coding an actual feature
in front of you all.
All right, so it just
updated my issue triage.
I'm gonna start this up again
and I'm going to use it.
Poetry's fun and all.
But how many of you would benefit
from automated GitHub issue triaging?
Yeah, maybe?
No, nobody triages tickets here?
Wow. (laughing)
Okay.
So we can see this prompt has appeared,
GitHub issue triage,
and I'm going to run it.
It's going to ask me for my parameters
and I will say my repo URL
is this and dry run, true.
And now again, since the
GitHub MCP server is loaded,
it's searching through issues, you can see
that it's searching for
no label, specifically.
It's looking for, it's listing the labels
associated with my repo
and then it's found,
admittedly this is a relatively new repo,
so there's not that many
issues, but you can see
that it gives me this
summary where it says, okay,
recommended labels, bug, documentation,
and then for this issue,
this is a feature request
or enhancement and then this
one, documentation or bug.
Alright, okay, so this one
stands out to me a bit,
this issue number 22,
'cause I read it earlier.
This is, I didn't open this.
This is a real issue where
they're saying these MCP prompts
are really nice, but it'd
be really cool if we could
have a list SOPs tool and
a use SOP tool, right?
That then the model can
automatically try to use it.
So let's implement it.
Let's see, am I in the right directory?
Okay, so at this point, if you remember,
we'd run that code based summary.
And so if I look at my context here,
I now have this agents.md
that was generated
by that code base summary.
I'm gonna go ahead and
clear my context here
and I'm going to run this
Agent SOP called PDD,
which stands for prop driven development,
which was an internal predecessor
to Kiro's spec driven
development that we came up with.
So it takes a rough idea
and then it takes you through
requirements, clarification,
and research and everything in order to,
and then comes up with a
design and implementation plan.
So it says, what's your rough idea?
I'm just putting a link
directly to this issue.
Okay?
And then we're gonna see,
we've got 20 minutes, we're
gonna see how far we can get.
All right.
So it's gonna do some bookkeeping first,
it creates this directory
structure of these folders
that are under this planning folder,
and one's called research,
one's called design,
one's called implementation.
Then it creates this rough-idea.md
file where it writes,
it just wrote what it read from
the GitHub issue into here.
And then it creates this idea-honing file,
which, and then gives me this instruction
to add this expression to my context.
So basically anything that gets written
into that directory structure
will auto-add to my context.
So it says, okay, do you want to start out
with requirements clarification,
which is the default,
or do you wanna start with
some preliminary research
or do you wanna provide
additional context?
I'll just say requirements clarification.
Okay, at this point it
turns into a requirements
coding partner where it
starts asking me questions
one at a time, saying,
it starts asking me clarifying questions.
So it says, what specific functionality
should each tool provide.
For list SOPs, should
it return just SOP names
or descriptions or parameters.
For a use SOP should it
return the full SOP content?
So I'll say list SOPs,
return name and description,
and entire parameters content.
So I'll say that.
And then use SOP,
I'll say take, this is because
I wrote this so I know.
So take a look at the
MCP prompt implementation
and use the same XML output format,
but without the run-this part.
So I told it to take a look
at the MCP prompt implementation.
So hopefully it should, let's see.
Oh, maybe not.
The agents.md probably
has that information.
Okay, so next question, agent
autonomy and invocation.
How should agents decide when to use SOPs?
Should the tool be available at all times?
These are MCP tools.
They'll be in context at all times.
All right, external SOP support.
So should the new tool
support external SOPs,
which is this flag that we support?
Yes.
Yeah.
So this may not make for, I'm like the,
I'm like the anti-flashy demo person
and so I love doing like
real software development
in front of here, and you may
see some like thinking time
being spent and stuff like that.
But this is real software development.
Like this is how it actually works, right,
where you do requirements clarification.
It says tool parameter and return format,
return structured format or plain text.
List SOPs can return JSON output.
Use SOP...
Yeah.
(attendee speaking faintly off mic)
I am on the auto model right now
and I think by default it tends
to use the like Claude 200K versions,
Claude Sonnet 200K tokens.
But we do have the 1 million
token on here as well,
Claude Opus, I just am
not explicitly using it.
Let's see, use SOP
should take the SOP name.
And I think that's it. Good enough.
This is one of those features that's kind
of in the middle ground
where I do wanna clarify
some requirements, but I'm not like,
it's kind of a smallish feature.
So yeah, occasionally I'll
come in and just say like,
Hey, why don't you just ask and answer
like all the questions you have first
and then I'll tell you what I think of it.
I'll do that on occasion.
Error handling, list SOPs
should just return empty list.
Use SOP can return a
helpful error message.
Alright, so it's saying,
I think I've captured core requirements.
Again, I'm not usually under like
the 20 minute time deadline.
I am here.
So sometimes I'll say, actually,
it does have another question.
Let's see. Integration with existing...
How should these new tools integrate
with existing MCP Prompt system?
Yes, both prompts and
tools should be available.
Sometimes when it says
it'll kind of decide
like I think we have requirements
and sometimes I'll say, well gimme a list
of questions you might have asked,
and then he'll give me maybe
like eight or 10 questions.
And, okay, so that said,
we've covered the essential requirements.
Okay, I think we're good.
So now I'm gonna say, research fast MCP
and how tools are implemented.
Or, I'll just say,
research how tools are
implemented in FastMCP,
the library we're using,
and write a doc to the research folder.
Okay, so it's gonna do a web search.
Yeah, so I can have it do this research.
There are things where, you know,
large language models are
very good at pattern matching.
I happen to know in this code base
that we just have MCP prompts in here.
We don't have any tools.
If we did, if we had tools already,
I probably wouldn't tell
it to research this.
I just, 'cause it's really good at kind
of like exploring the code base,
and then just copying what it's sees.
But I want to hopefully
ensure some success here.
And so I had to do some research
on the web to understand,
like read the documentation
and understand how adding tools works.
But we'll see if it works.
So this PDD script will write findings
to this research folder.
So you can see this whole
time, we have this kind
of planning folder that was created.
My rough idea ended up in there.
The idea honing, this is the documentation
of all these questions and answers
and then research, well,
there will be something
in research soon, in design.
Okay, so now research,
it just wrote this research
document on FastMCP,
and again, part of that
Agent SOP I've written
that it needs to, let me, yeah,
it needs to include references,
and the links of where it found all
of its information in here.
So all of those details, like,
that's not something you would want
to repeat over and over again,
and manually writing prompts.
That's something that you can
encode right into that SOP,
and then it works.
Let's see.
So in the interest of time,
I'm gonna have it move on to design.
In the real world, like
real world scenarios,
I would spend much more time reading,
like reading the research information,
especially when it comes to design.
For this one, I'm gonna do
like a really quick skim,
which is very common when
you look at AI demos.
It's like, yeah, this looks
good, and then move on.
I spend, like when, I used a form of this,
this was before we invented Agent SOP,
but I used a form of this with
manual prompting to implement
that context feature way back in March.
And if it were really as
simple as just, I don't care
what you wrote, I'm just
gonna keep saying yes
and move on, I wouldn't have
gone concept to PR in two days.
It would've been concept
to PR in two hours, right?
But I was, and this is
where I really distinguish
what's going on here from vibe coating,
which is a very popular
term from back in February.
For me, vibe coding is, I'm
not even looking at the code.
I don't, you know, I'm just kind of
letting the agent do its thing
and I'm kind of manually testing,
and my experience with vibe
coating is it's amazing
for prototypes, amazing for
little games I wanna make
for myself, not very
good for production code.
'Cause in production
code we wanna make sure
that there's high quality,
we wanna make sure that
the design makes sense,
and it's, vibe coding,
it's very easy to code yourself
into a corner like really,
really quickly and get to a
point where you're telling it
to fix something and it fixes
it and breaks something else
and then you like tell it to fix that
and you just code yourself into a corner.
All right, so I have this
detailed design at this point
and I'm gonna have it keep going.
But its next step is it's gonna create
a implementation plan,
but you can see it creates
this detailed requirements
and then it creates kind of
this architecture overview
of what it's going to do.
And again, normally I would spend
a lot of time reading this.
This is a big part of
teaching AI fluency internally
in Amazon is teaching these practices,
especially to people who are newer
to this technology or newer
to software development
in general.
Like I said, when I built
that context feature,
yes, I didn't know the code base,
and yes, I didn't know the language,
but I've also been
programming for over 20 years,
which means that while I couldn't
write the language easily,
I could still read it, I
could still read roughly
what it was doing and what was going on.
And so I was there with it as it was,
as it was, you know, implementing this.
Okay, so I'm gonna just cancel it.
It was just gonna create
a little project summary
to wrap up.
But this SOP, this is a very involved
and interactive SOP, so
you can see how powerful
these can be.
But it went ahead and created this
like implementation checklist,
which 10 steps is way
overkill for this. (laughing)
So I think what I'm gonna do instead
is I'm actually just gonna remove that,
and I am going to run this other Agent SOP
called Code Task Generator.
And this is another one that
we use internally all the time.
Alright, so input is, create
code tasks for implementing
the design in your context
and output directory.
Yeah, I guess I'll just say,
implementation folder since I had it.
Okay, so what this one
does, this one's really good
for like kind of smaller tasks
where you don't need this
like really huge involved one.
This one kind of prompts you first
and says, okay, here's my
proposed task breakdown.
So I read everything
that you have in context
and here's create this SOP registry
and metadata extraction,
implement list SOPs,
and use SOP tools, integrate
tools with existing MCP server.
Let's do it in one step. I'm
giving a demo. (laughing)
(attendee speaking faintly off mic)
So this one, there's kind of mixed,
that's an area we're still exploring.
In general, we're seeing things
head toward that direction
where you end up committing,
there's kind of two levels of context,
and you'll see it's really
useful for agents to kind
of like write a bunch of stuff down,
and if you need to
clear the context window
and then it's still there,
and kind of like when there are documents
that are more durable over time,
like design documents that
stick around for a long time,
those absolutely should
go in the source code.
But then there's more
ephemeral kind of like notes
as you implement.
And you'll see when I get
to this implementation.
All right, this one created this code task
and the file it created looks like this
and Code Task Generator SOP,
it basically creates
like, like if any of you
have an issue tracker,
it's like the issue you
wish everybody wrote.
It's like this very detailed
issue with description,
background reference documentation,
technical requirements,
dependencies, implementation
approach, you know,
acceptance criteria.
It's like if only, right?
Well guess what, with AI we can do that.
All right, so now that I have
that, now I'm going to run
this Agent SOP called Code
Assist, which is fantastic.
Code Assist, again, these
are like super prompts.
Okay, so it said proposed parameters.
Oh wow, I actually already
found my test description. Nice.
I'm going to say yeah,
yeah, this all looks good.
So Code Assist takes the task description,
which can be a file path or it can be,
you can manually type what you want,
and then a task name and then a mode.
So it can either be interactive or auto.
I'm going to go auto for this one.
And then a documentation directory.
Oh actually I'm gonna adjust
documentation directory.
Oops. All right.
I'm gonna adjust it to be that.
And then, yeah, and then the repo route
and your current director
is the root default.
So the code assist SOP leads the agent
through a much more opinionated
way to implement code well.
It uses test driven
development best practices.
So it breaks it up into a
red phase, a green phase,
and refactor phase.
Red phase, meaning it
writes the test first
and then verifies that they fail.
And then the green phase is it implements
the functional logic
until those tests pass.
And then the refactor
phase is where it runs
the other tests, make sure
it didn't break anything
and then refactors the code to
kind of more concisely match
the style of the existing
code and do any cleanups.
And then it commits it using
conventional commit messages.
And yeah, so all of
that rolled into an SOP
for anything other than
like a trivial one-liner,
this is the only way I code now.
I use this Agent SOP, it's fantastic.
Yeah.
(attendee speaking faintly off mic)
So the question is kind of
how do you differentiate
between like greenfield
versus brownfield, right,
like existing code base.
This is an existing code base,
although admittedly it's a fairly
simple code base right now.
It's not, like I spent my last five years
working on AWS Cloudformation,
that's an over 10-year-old,
you know, code base.
It's highly complex,
highly asynchronous, right?
Running code based summary on that,
definitely more challenging.
That's generally
internally when we're doing
any AI tools that that code base tends
to be my stress test for any of them.
So the code base summary does
help with existing code bases.
And I will say that there
is a limit to like how well
these AI systems can do,
depending on how complex
and how large the code base is.
If there is a massive amount
of cognitive load that
you need to have in head to
make like a one line change,
not gonna help you as much.
So an analogy that I like
to give is that like,
you can think of a commercial plumber
who spends three days walking
around a big industrial building
and then tightens one bolt
and is like, Fixed your problem,
and that'll be a thousand dollars.
And they're like, a thousand dollars?
You tightened one bolt.
And they say, well, okay, $1 for the bolt,
$999 for knowing which bolt to tighten.
So there is code that we have
that's very much like that
where the actual change itself is not big,
but all the knowledge and cognitive load
that you need to make that change,
that's where kind of the scale comes in.
I've found that I tend to
use AI for that walking
around the building for three days part.
I can cut that down, that time down
and then still make kind of
the manual code change myself.
Yeah. So when you start using Agent SOP,
like I know this is a code
talk and I'm doing coding.
Hey look, all my tests
failed. That's good, right?
We know we're good on that.
So when we do these,
so once you realize
that these SOPs basically
just automate an agent
to do things with MCP tools
that it has, you start realizing
how many different applications there are.
One of the reasons I was so
excited to open source this
is because we, there
are literally thousands
of these SOPs internally in Amazon
and we are using them all over the place
because you saw how easy
they are to author and use,
and people are using them
to automate operations.
They're using 'em to automate
coding, as you can see,
even productivity, if you
have like Outlook MCP,
and Slack MCP, and if you have
like the right MCPs in place,
you can start, like I
have a productivity agent
where I can give it a
recording of a meeting
and say, Hey, transcribe this,
add a meeting notes document
to my Obsidian Vault
that has the task breakdown for everybody.
And then it creates like separate
documents for each person
and maps the tasks over.
So I can click on that person
and say, oh yeah, those
are the tasks I'm tracking
for that person, right.
And AI helps me do all of that.
So it's pretty wild.
(attendee speaking faintly off mic)
Yeah, the tasks I've shown
are like a user story.
Is that your question? Yeah, yeah.
The code task is like user story.
(attendee speaking faintly off mic)
Oh yeah, yeah, using,
yeah, so MCP is the way
to connect your agent to
various different systems.
GitHub has their own MCP server
and you can also look at
MCP servers elsewhere.
Another thing we look at is,
Anthropic launched this thing
called Skills, which with Skills you can,
if a tool has, even if a tool
doesn't have great MCP support,
but they have a really
good CLI, for example,
you can write a skill that
gives it all the CLI commands
and tells it how to use it.
And then that's another way
that you can connect it.
(attendee speaking faintly off mic)
Yeah. Yeah, absolutely.
All right. Well, I was really
hoping to get to a point
where I could actually like
show you that this works
for real, but I think we're out of time.
- [Maish] We're outta time.
- [James] Maybe I'm saved by
the bell I guess. (laughing)
But anyway, you can see, so
it's implementing this code,
the tests are now passing.
Yeah, it just passed with 97% coverage.
It's gonna update this progress document
that it's been keeping and
then it's gonna do a commit.
Yeah. Cool.
So that's all the time we have,
but hopefully that gives you some insight
into how we use Agent SOPs.
I really encourage you to
check out the Agent SOP GitHub,
and if you wouldn't mind giving us a star,
I'd really appreciate it as well.
But thanks so much for your time today.
(audience applauding)