- Well, hello, everyone,
and welcome on the session DEV 308.
My name is Oleksii Ivanchenko,
I'm Solution Architect here in AWS,
and with me, Vadym Kazulkin,
he is Head of Development in IP Labs,
and as well, AWS Serverless Hero.
And for me, as the Solution Architect,
main goal is to help my customer
for scaling their business,
and help them modernize their workload
without them spending
too much time and effort
on these processes.
So, today, we are going to talk about
how to build modern application
with the help of Aurora DSQL.
For that, we are going to dive deep
into building blocks of this
database and its architecture.
We will go through few code samples,
because this is 300-level session.
And we will go through the
performance and challenges
that you can see within the DSQL.
And of course, we'll do the prop up
on what we have learned today.
And with that, I'm
passing the word to Vadym.
Vadym?
- So, the question is
why we need another serverless database?
We have already several offerings on AWS,
the list is not complete,
you see Amazon, DynamoDB,
RDS, Aurora Provisioned,
and Amazon Aurora Serverless v2.
I would like to talk
about these databases,
but especially in terms how they fit
for the serverless workflows.
And I'm working a lot with AWS Lambda,
so just how these
databases can be approached
and talked to from AWS Lambda.
So let's start with DynamoDB.
It's really the ideal fit
for serverless workloads.
You don't have any
infrastructure management here,
it's the database,
it scales up and down for you,
and if it scales down,
it scales up without any
cold start of the database,
so it's not noticeable for you.
You have single millisecond
digit performance,
so that's really cool database.
Also in terms of other
things, I really prefer it,
but there are also challenges around that,
so everything is a trade off.
So, for example, it's NoSQL database,
and with that,
there's another mindset comparing
to relational databases,
how you design those tables,
how you involve the schema afterwards.
Yeah? It's not very easy.
And there are also
challenges on certain things,
like by default, DynamoDB
is eventually consistent,
you can turn various things
to be strong consistent,
and pay more for it,
but for example, there are restrictions,
global secondary indices
cannot be strong consistent,
for example.
And there are also limitations
in term of transaction,
how many items can be
put in one transaction,
so there are certain
limitations with that.
Now moving to other databases,
they're all relational
databases, and we love them.
I personally come
from working 10 or more
years with Postgres,
and I like these joins, and many tables,
and all that stuff, and
it has its benefits.
But especially in terms of how RDS fits
into serverless stack roles,
there are certain limitations.
For example, there is a lot
of infrastructure work to do.
For example, you need to
file VPC security groups,
and you need to define the size
and the family of the instance,
and so on.
And also, with that,
you cannot scale compute and
storage with this database,
so you have the certain size,
and then you need to increase the size,
we can have multi-AZ,
just that you don't
have kind of the outage
by increasing one side,
and then the next side will
be increased automatically.
And there are also challenges
around connection management
if you talk from her RDS
database from Lambda,
the number of connection to the database
is a factor of the database,
of the family size.
And if you have a lot of Lambda function,
they scale simultaneously,
you can run out of connections
talking to RDS database.
There are solutions how to mitigate it,
for example RDS proxy,
by providing something in
between, like for multiplexing.
But of course, it's another component,
it's a managed one,
but it also has a cost
associated with that,
there can be even latency, and so on.
So there are other challenges with RDS.
Now moving to Amazon
Aurora, provisioned one,
it's mainly the same
advantages and disadvantages
as with RDS,
the only one exception,
you can scale their storage
independently of compute
with that database.
Now moving to Amazon Aurora Serverless v2,
we are kind of approaching this world
where the relational
database are more suitable
for the serverless world.
Here, you can scale compute
and storage automatically.
You don't need VPC.
You might have VPC
if you would like to have private traffic,
but you're not required to do that.
You'll also not define the instance sizes,
this is more Aurora capacity
units, and you can say,
I would like to scale within
this ACU and that ACU.
You can scale to zero, this database,
which is not possible for
RDS and Aurora provisioned,
and it's sometimes very important,
because on your store
and testing environments,
you would like to,
if you don't use it,
you don't want to pay it.
So that's why, especially
for RDS and Aurora,
you provision the smaller
instances for those
test staging environments.
For Amazon Aurora Serverless v2,
you can specify scaling down to zero,
but then you have the disadvantages.
It might take up to 15 minutes,
15 seconds, sorry, to scale up
in case you specify it
to scale down to zero.
By default, it scales to 0.5 ACUs.
And also, if you scale down to zero,
you will lose the cache
right near the instance,
and by scaling up the
performance of the first queries,
might be slower,
because yeah, the cache needs to build up.
So you see here different challenges,
and Aurora Serverless v2,
two you can use RDS proxy with that,
but they also offer data API
so you can talk to the
Aurora Serverless v2
like you talk to DynamoDB via HTTP.
This is this kind of solution,
in parallel to RDS proxy,
you can decide,
you can use still RDS proxy, or data API.
But data API is complete separate API,
so you need to rewrite your code,
in case you would like to adjust,
and RDS proxy,
you need only to change the endpoint.
So the question that is
kind of being asked is,
can we have AWS database offering
which is as serverless as DynamoDB,
in terms of not having to
deal with the infrastructure,
or scale up and down very quickly
without cold starts of the database,
but provides the benefits
of the relational databases
like these ACID things.
And with that,
I will pass the word to Oleksii.
- Thank you.
Yeah.
So, for that, to address these questions,
we have introduced Aurora
DSQL last re:Invent,
and we made it generally available
in the middle of this year.
So what is the DSQL?
DSQL is the Serverless database,
which means that you don't need to have
any infrastructure to manage,
you don't need to bring your database down
for patching or updating.
It's handled by us.
It's proud of five nines of availability,
and you get scaling, compute,
and storage separately.
You scale the reads and write separately,
which provides you
virtually endless scale.
And through all the scale,
with all the scale,
you get strongly consistency all the time.
So when you would like
to look for the DSQL?
First of all you would
like to look for DSQL
If you are searching for a database
that supports ACID transactions.
Through multi-region.
You want to feed the database
for your serverless architecture
or microservice design,
or you have the application
that is following event-driven approach,
or you don't know how spiky
will be your traffic tomorrow,
or the day after tomorrow.
And of course, if you want
to continue to utilize
already existing tooling and
continue to work with SQL.
And now this all sounds
pretty interesting,
but how exactly we achieving all this?
For that, let's dive into
the design of the DSQL.
And we will start with
single region cluster.
Single region cluster is active-active,
multi-writer cluster,
distributed across multiple
availability zones.
The data is replicated across three zones.
You have one endpoint
for reads and writes,
it supports simultaneously
and concurrently.
And you don't have any
instances to provision.
You can send just
requests to the database,
and everything else is
handled by it underneath.
With no instances to provision,
you don't have anything to
stop for patching or updating,
we also do it by ourself.
And with the single-region set up,
you are getting four
nines of availability.
In the same time with the,
sorry, but behind the single endpoint,
you have not only,
not just one, or multiple
Postgres instances
that are hidden and running,
no, instead of that,
what's really powers DSQL
is the distributed
disaggregated architecture.
We took critical components
of monolithic OTP database,
and separated them into separate services.
We separated them into
the connection management,
we separated into the query processing,
isolation enforcement, transaction
journaling, and storage.
Each of these components
works independently,
and are tuned for each specific role.
Each of these components
is working with the fleet
of the computer resources
that can scale independently,
and can adjust to the workloads.
Yeah, you get one end point
for both reads and writes,
so that means that your reads
and writes are always local,
and the only thing which
is traveling across AZ
is transaction commit.
And also, as I said,
you are getting four nines of availability
with the single endpoint.
In the same time,
with multi-regional cluster,
you are getting five
nines of availability,
and multi-regional consistent writes.
It provides two regional endpoints,
both of these endpoints
support concurrency reads and writes,
and together it's represented
as the single logical database.
There is also the third region
there, called witness region.
Witness region participates
in the write quorum,
and works as the tiebreaker
to decide which region
can continue to write
in case of the network partitioning.
The witness region receives the data
from the regional cluster.
It also hold limited amount
of the encrypted transaction log,
but it doesn't have any
cluster or any end points.
So if we will look on the
high-level architecture,
or building blocks, of DSQL,
you will find their front-end,
you will find Query Processor,
Adjudicator, Journal,
Crossbar, and the storage.
Query processor does most
of the SQL processing job,
it acts as the dedicated Postgres engine
for each transaction.
And there can be as many query processors
as there are concurrent
connections to the database.
Adjudicator determines
whether the transaction can be committed
while following the isolation rules.
Each shard key in database is owned
exactly by the one adjudicator
at any given moment of time.
Journal makes all the
transactions durable,
and replicates the data
between availability zones
and regions.
Each transaction, always
assigned to the single journal.
Crossbar merge the data streams
and direct them into the storage nodes.
Storage nodes,
storage nodes provide access to your data,
storage nodes hold the
replicas, multiple replicas,
and each storage node
contains the specific range
of the data based on the database key.
It may looks little bit overwhelming,
or sounds a little bit overwhelming,
but let's take a look,
how does all these
components works together?
Let's start with the
standard read transaction
and basic select statement.
Let's imagine that we are
the user in the us-west-1,
and we are willing to order
food from a local Pizza service,
and somewhere here in the Las Vegas.
So what's happening there?
We're deciding that we
want to get the restaurants
that have the rating four or higher,
so we're executing the query for
select * from restaurants
where rating equals
or higher than 4.0.
So what happens behind the scenes?
Your application making the
connection to the DSQL frontend.
Frontend allocates the query processor,
and pass your statement
to the query processor.
Query processor reads the local clock
and sets the transaction
start time, tau start.
Sorry. (coughs)
Now your read-only transaction begins.
The storage is automatically,
and what's important, transparent to you,
are partitioned according
to the database key.
That's why Query Processor
consult with the shard map
to understand where your data,
in which storage node it is located.
And because this is read-only transaction,
Query Processor doesn't need
to follow the writer path,
it doesn't need to go through
the Adjudicator or Journal,
it can go straight to the
storage to retrieve your data.
Storage nodes doesn't return pages,
it returns rows.
Storage nodes also can
process predicated push downs,
filtering, aggregation of the rows
before sending them
back to Query Processor.
Together, all this stuff
significantly decreases
the amount of the data
that need to travel across the network,
and decrease the amount of work
that needs to be done
by the Query Processor.
So, and comparing to traditional database,
we don't have any monolithic
cache sitting aside.
So when query processor
needs to get the data,
it goes to the storage node,
which is located in the same region,
in the same availability zone
where the query processor
is located as well.
So your reads are always local,
so then Query Processor return,
then Query Processor return the results
from the storage node,
they all merge together,
and return it to you.
So, what's happening next?
Next, at this point,
if you continue to
interact with the frontend,
you are building the
interactive transaction.
You start the transaction,
you do some work with database,
you do some work with the client,
you maybe go back and
forth multiple times,
and eventually, you commit.
How does it look?
How does it look, for
example, in our case,
when you decided order the pizza?
You select the restaurant,
you browse the menu,
you choose the item,
you add the item into your order,
you place the order,
and basically, that's hitting the commit.
So what, in traditional database,
how it will look in traditional database?
Most probably, you will
have to place some logs
and do some checks,
potentially across the region,
for each statement in your transaction.
These add latency to your operation.
Query Processor acts differently.
It acts as the holding tongue
for all your statements
in your transaction.
It reads data from the local storage nodes
and saves it into the local memory.
When it needs to write the data,
it's already writing the data,
it changed the data of the
local saved data in the memory,
and it accumulates all the
changes within this local memory
and waits for the commit.
And then, when it needs to commit it,
just follow the writing pass,
and sends the data to the Adjudicator
to check the full transaction,
to the Adjudicator to check the data.
So, as you can see,
Query Processor do a lot of heavy lifting,
it's basically the heart
of the DSQL architecture.
And Query Processor is
running in Firecracker,
lightweight virtual machines,
called also micro VMs,
and they are running on the
bare metal Query Processor host.
And we can run thousands of
pre-provisioned micro VMs
on the single host.
So every time when you connect to the DSQL
and start to use it,
we are making sure that there
is enough micro VMs running
to handle your workloads,
and we can scale them
automatically as it is needed.
Each Query Processor is fully
independent and isolated,
so they never communicate to each other.
And talking about the isolation,
in DSQL, we are supporting
transaction-level isolation
called snapshot isolation.
Each transaction operates
on the consistent snapshot of the database
as it was at the beginning,
at the start of the transaction.
Your transaction begins
and proceeds through
the SQL execution paths,
where all the reads are happening
always with the consistent snapshot.
At the storage level,
these reads are implemented
using the technical multi-versioning
concurrency control,
or multi-versioning.
The storage engine keeps multiple
versions of the same row,
and allowing access to the
older versions of the row
while not blocking of
creating newer versions.
And when, basically,
write operation occurs,
like insert or update,
it's not immediately
written to the storage,
applied to the storage.
Query Processor spools all the changes
into the local storage,
into the local memory,
and creates a private workspace for it,
a private workspace for this transaction.
And this approach basically enables you
read your write's capabilities.
So for all subsequent reads
within the same transaction,
you're working with the pending changes,
your read transactions
see the pending changes
that you already applied
through the writes.
So when when your transaction
issues the commit,
DSQL needs to understand
whether all the changes that were applied
within the transaction and spooled locally
can be applied to the storage,
can be written to the storage.
And that's where the
Adjudicator comes into the play.
It sits in the writer path of DSQLs,
and decides will the transaction
be committed and written.
Its job to detect and
resolve the conflicts
that are happening
between the transactions
to ensure the consistent writes.
Yeah.
So, to do this,
the Query Processor forms the payload,
creates the payload,
to send it to the Adjudicator,
and this payload contains
all the necessary information
to make this decision.
We have the write set there,
which contains all the items
modified by transaction.
We have the post image set
which contains the copy of the table rows
after applying transaction changes,
and we also have the start
time of the transaction,
tau start,
which plays the crucial, critical role
in deciding which will be
transaction committed or aborted.
And we will talk about this
part a little bit later.
So now, when two transactions comes,
what basically happens?
Here we have two transactions, A and B.
They started almost at
the same moment of time,
but Transaction A was committed
slightly before Transaction B.
So what happened in this case?
In this case, Adjudicator
will analyze the payload
of both of the transactions,
examining their writer set and start time.
It'll look for the all the changes
that were made after the
start time, tau start,
and it will look for overlapping
or matching rows that was changed.
And it sees that both of the transactions
are trying to change the same row,
and because they cannot both
of them change the same row
at the same time,
because Transaction A was applied,
committed slightly before
Transaction B, need to be aborted.
At that moment of time,
Transaction A is allowed to proceed
and decide the commit
timestamp, tau commit.
If there is two transactions
which have different writer sets,
or these writer sets
contains the not overlapping,
or not collapsing, not
conflicting writes, or rows,
in this case, both
transactions can be committed,
can be allowed to proceed,
and both transactions will
be assigned the tau commit.
So, once Adjudicator decides
that your transaction's able to proceed,
what exactly makes it durable?
In traditional database,
durability happens on the storage level.
Transaction is considered committed
only when it's written
durably to the storage.
The storage layer is then responsible
for recovering your committed transaction
in case of failure.
But these things comes with a price,
for that, you need to
have the checkpoint in,
you have to have the logging,
you need to carefully coordinate
between the memory and the
storage synchronization
to be able to recover
in case of the failure.
And all this adds lots of latency
and lots of complexity to the system.
So DSQL manages this complexity
by using the journal.
Journal is independent,
sorry, internal component that
was written for the decade,
and was optimized for ordered
replication of the data
between multiple AZs and
between multiple regions.
It scales horizontally,
so transaction can come
into any of the instances
of this journal.
Journal coordinate to
maintain ordered streams
of communication of
committed transactions,
and then Crossbar, which
is pulling the changes,
pulling the transactions from the journal,
routing this transaction to the storage,
and using this order to ensure
that all the transactions
are written to the storage
in the proper sequence.
So once Adjudicator decides
that your transaction is committed,
it sends the payload and commit
timestamp to the journal.
Once the journal acknowledge the write,
acknowledges your transaction,
your transaction is durable
and atomically committed.
The journal sends success code
back to the Query Processor,
and Crossbar, at this moment,
begins to pull the data from the journal
and draw it to the storage.
The Query Processor, at this moment,
sends success code back
to you, to the user,
and for you, from this perspective,
the transaction is successfully committed.
And now I want to draw your attention
to two components that are
crucial in all the workflow.
Remember that tau start and tau commit.
This is the time.
This is crucial because you
cannot get strongly consistency
without synchronizing on the time.
You cannot coordinate them
if you don't have the reference
clock which you can trust,
and you know that you can trust
to this tau start and tau commit.
For that for solving this issue
and achieving this reference
clock which we can trust,
we have introduced
Amazon Time Sync Service.
With Time Sync Service,
with dedicated timing hardware
that are located across AWS
and AWS Nitro system,
we having the direct GPS
dictated reference clock
that are located on the EC2s.
In DSQL, it effectively allows us
to have globally-synchronized clock
with the microseconds accuracy time.
With all of this,
I'm passing the word to Vadym
to talk about identification
and authorization,
how it's happening.
Thank you.
- Yeah so, let's look
into Aurora DSQL more
from developer's perspective.
The slides are not switching.
Something?
Oh?
Okay, now it's working.
So, thanks.
So now let's talk about authentication,
how we normally authenticate
to the relational database.
Okay, it's now not working once again.
Okay, now.
So, normally we use user and password,
and with that it might happen
that somebody can get access
to this password and misuse it.
So, normally we need to
rotate this password,
which we sometimes forget,
and this offers the attack vector there.
So DSQL doesn't use any password,
but what does it use instead?
It uses tokens to authenticate.
And the tokens are generated by AWS SDK,
and is fast, and what's very important,
the local cryptography.
And this is more or less the same
that is used behind the scenes
if we talk to S3 DynamoDB,
but these tokens will be generated for us,
we don't deal with that.
In case of DSQL, we will
probably need to deal with that.
What's important is
they're very short lived.
If somebody intercepts a token,
it's probably already expired,
which is a good start.
So now let's look how
to generate this token.
This is one of the examples
we use here, AWS CLI request,
we send here aws dsql
generate-db-connect-admin-auth-token,
give the hostname, and
how much time to expire.
As short as possible is also okay.
What we'll get back here
is basically the response,
and the response is the whole token,
and we can use this token to authenticate
instead of the password.
So, for example,
you can use that to
authenticate using psql.
Yeah? This is how we talk
to the Postgres database.
psql, we simply export it
to the environment variable
called PGPASSWORD,
and then if we do psql -quiet connect,
then this token will be
used instead of password.
In case you use something like the DBeaver
or some other tool to authenticate,
you simply grab this token and
use it instead of password.
Yeah, this is how it works.
The cool thing is that DSQL team released
the integrated query editor, SQL editor,
in the browser several weeks ago.
So you can simply go to the DSQL page,
and then you can simply do all
the SQL stuff in the browser,
and this token thing will be done for you
basically behind the scenes,
so you don't need to bother with that.
But, of course,
sometimes we would like to have
powerful tools like DBeaver,
and use that.
What I would like to show you
is how easy it is to
create Aurora DSQL cluster,
especially single-region cluster.
You see we don't have any scrollbar here,
which is surprising.
If you created RDS,
then you probably know how many
choices do you need to make.
Here's the only thing more
or less that you need to do,
is just more or less give
the cluster the name.
And everything else is already there,
yeah, there is enabled
deletion protection,
which is a good stuff, you can remove it.
You can customize encryption settings.
And you can add the text.
That's basically it.
Of course, for the multi-region cluster,
it's a bit more complicated,
because you need another region
just to select another region,
then select the witness region.
But, basically, the
settings will be the same,
so, really, really easy.
I would like to show you code examples.
Please raise your hands who
can understand the Java code?
Okay, lots of people, which is good,
because I'm the Java guy,
and I feel understood myself.
So now let's take this
subset of application
that Oleksii showed you.
And this will be kind of
only the ordering part.
So you see API gateway and
a bunch of Lambda functions,
how to create order, get order by ID,
or get orders by created range.
Like give me all the orders
from the 1st of November
until the 13th of November.
And we store that in the Aurora DSQL.
I will show you example with AWS SAM,
but you can use SDK, you can
use CloudFormation Terraform.
Basically this is a very generic example,
you can reuse it for all applications,
especially if you talk
from Lambda to Aurora DSQL.
First of all,
you need to pass the Aurora
DSQL cluster a variable,
environment variable.
This is the cluster ID.
You create the Aurora
cluster, DSQL cluster,
and then you can grab the cluster id,
you can just provide
as a default value
environment variable here.
And then you can pass it
to create Aurora DSQL cluster endpoint,
which is kind of, you
can use this variable,
it always follows the same
pattern here to create this.
And I export that as
an environment variable
for all Lambda functions
of my application.
And as you see below,
this is the Java code.
I simply grab it by System getenv,
and then I use it to create this JDBC,
or LJDBC as a protocol for
Java to talk to database,
to relational database.
So there already DSQL cluster endpoint
that I passed as environment variable
as a kind of substring of that.
And what I need to decide also to give
is the authorization stuff.
So, here, I simply allow Lambda function
to talk to the Aurora DSQL,
and here I need to provide resource ARN
in this Aurora cluster,
and cluster ID is also kind of
used as a variable for that.
So, pretty generic logic.
Now let's look into the Java example.
So basically it's a good practice
to use and instantiate
the so-called server-side
connection pooling.
And just not only for Java,
there are solutions for Python,
for all programming languages.
The reason that it still makes sense,
because the creating of the
connection is still not free,
and the connection might expire
and may be kind of fetched once again.
So it's still a good practice to use that,
and I use it for Java
Hikari data source pool,
and I create that and
say how many connections,
you can even say one
connection in the pool,
because basically it's a single thread,
or single-process application,
and that's why Lambda only needs
one connection just a time,
and then it does the thing sequentially.
So I create this here,
and this is the logic
to get the connection.
Yeah, you see here,
in both places what we are doing here,
we are fetching the token,
and set it as a password.
And there is Aurora DSQL SDK,
which does the same what
I showed you with AWS CLI.
This is basically you need this
to create this generated
auth token request,
provide endpoint, time to live,
and then this token will be
generated for you each time,
and you need to pass it.
What you already see here,
we need to fetch this token in two places.
First, creating the connection pooling,
and second, each time
that we get the connection
to talk to the database.
And it seems like a boilerplate code,
and that's why AWS team improved that,
they started with Java,
but now also for other languages
they released the code connectors.
And these connectors help you
to handle this token generation
automatically for you,
so you don't need that.
And if you looked in the previous slide,
that was the only dependency to AWS SDK,
is to fetch this token.
All other code is simple JDBC code.
So simply, you can reuse
that what you already had,
for example, if you
migrate to the database.
There was no dependency to DSQL.
And by removing that,
we can remove all dependencies to DSQL,
so there is no password management,
and now it works since
last week also for Python,
for Python, from PG, and PG2,
and also for Node.js,
there is Node.js, Postgres,
and Postgres JS driver.
So how does it look?
We need to add the dependency
to this connector there in
our dependency management,
but now our code doesn't
have any dependency to DSQL,
it's a pure JDBC, pure Java code
how we talk to the application.
You see we simply,
we don't have this get
authenticated auth token,
and we don't have set of token.
But how our application understands
that this connector should be used?
The whole magic is in this red line.
We additionally say it's
AWS DSQL in the path,
and with that, this
connector will be triggered,
instead of pure JDBC Postgres driver.
So this is kind of the only dependency,
this explicit dependency in the string
which says that this
connector should do the work,
and it will fetch the auth token
and place it instead
of the password for us.
So, huge improvement of, I would say,
readability of the code.
So what are other benefits of DSQL?
It works really well
with familiar object
relation mapping frameworks.
You probably all use them,
you have some entity, like order,
you can annotate them the properties,
like order ID with the
column in the database,
and simply save the stuff.
And it works with all of them,
for example, for Java, the
Hibernate is a popular one.
For Python developers,
SQLAlchemy, or Django.
Yeah, and it will all works with them,
so we don't need to change our code.
Let's talk briefly about
performance of this database,
because Oleksii explained
the architecture,
and it could sound like a magic.
So the question is,
just is it performant database,
or it's all this magic
may impact performance?
So first of all,
my goal was to measure
performance from Lambda function.
Yeah so, I measured performance
of the Lambda function
which talks to the DSQL so
the SQL time is kind of there.
I used Java as a programming language,
I only focus on measuring
warm start times,
I didn't focus on the cold
start time of the runtime,
like Java, it has implications,
but it wasn't the goal.
That's why I only also
focused on 99th percentile,
just to exclude the impact
of the programming language.
And I did the performance measurement
for single and multi-region cluster.
What was not the goal?
That's very important.
I didn't want to compare the
performance of the databases
that we talked about.
RDS, DynamoDB, Aurora
Provisioned, Serverless v2,
because it deserves the whole talk,
and sometimes you cannot compare
like DynamoDB with relational databases.
And I didn't want to test
the performance at scale,
just not putting 10,000
transaction per second,
or just queries per second,
and I didn't want to test
performance when scaling,
I don't have an impact
how storage is scaled,
Query Processor, Adjudicator,
it all happens behind the scenes.
So my goal was just to do some basic stuff
and see how quick that is.
So, I showed you this
application with ordering.
The database structure is very simple,
I only have two tables,
order, and order items.
And order has order id as a primary key,
it has created timestamp
values, and such a thing,
and order items has product id, and so on.
And I have two indexes on the items table,
like order id,
because I fetch items by order id,
and also I have one
index on the order table,
on the timestamp, because
I fetch the results,
like timestamp between
one day and another day.
So, very simple structure,
I don't have user table,
I don't have product table,
only two tables.
But the first measurement was,
I am doing like, creation of
one order containing two items.
So, basically, these are
three inserts in there
in one transaction,
one insert into order,
and two inserts into order item.
If you see the results,
let's look into this Lila one, it's p90.
90% of the cases, we have that result
that is not kind of worse than that.
And you see, it's just for
p90, for single-region cluster,
20 milliseconds or something around,
and for-multi region cluster,
40 milliseconds for three selects.
So, considering a single-region cluster,
it's kind of seven
milliseconds per insert,
which is, I would say okay,
it's comparable to DynamoDB.
For multi-region cluster,
it needs to commit in another region,
so the performance is
kind of twice as slow,
which is normal,
in case you need multi-region.
Another measurement was get order by id,
and then get two items.
I can do it with one join, no problem,
I wanted just to do two joins,
without joins, like
getting the order by ID,
and with that ID,
then getting two items
with another select.
So, there are two selects,
and you see then, p90, Lila 1,
12 milliseconds for two
selects by using primary key
for getting the order,
and then index for
getting the order items.
You see that the performance is the same
for single and multi-region cluster
because it's the read operation.
And the read operation is always local,
it always uses the local endpoint,
so the performance of all reads
is the same for single
and multi-region cluster.
So I would say two
selects, 12 milliseconds,
a good use case.
This is a more sophisticated,
just get orders by created date range,
and I intentionally limited the query
that it returns only 100 orders maximum,
and then for each order,
it gets the items,
and I have only two
different items for each row.
So, basic for each order.
So, basically, I have 101 selects,
one select for order,
and then for each of 100
orders, I get two items.
And you see, 100 selects,
p90, 200 milliseconds, or 250
milliseconds for 101 selects.
I think it's a very compatible result.
Another thing I wanted to test,
because the specification says
there is no cold start of the database.
And you can measure it.
I did that, so my goal was I did not,
I created single multi-region cluster,
and did some operations,
and then I didn't touch it for three days.
And then I did the first select
via the console just,
not via the Lambda function
because it has performance implication,
I simply just used psql and
said, select order by ID,
and some existing order.
And I just did it four
or five times the same,
just three days, pause, and then select.
What you see here,
the medium latency in this case
was for single-region
cluster, 165 milliseconds,
for multi-region cluster,
169 milliseconds.
So, of course there is a small latency,
because things needs to be warmed up
if I don't use something.
Something needs to be persisted,
but it's not noticeable.
It's not 15 seconds like
Aurora Serverless v2,
it's just one time for the first select,
or first operation, 160 milliseconds.
So I would say no cold
starts of the database,
it's simply not there.
So now let's talk about
there are also constraints,
and you need to understand them
because that might have
certain implications.
So let's first start with quotas.
Each AWS service has its quotas.
And there is even service,
an AWS service called Service Quotas,
where you can go there,
select the service,
and you can see these
quotas or constraints.
Yeah? And DSQL is no exception.
So there are some important ones
that I would like to raise the attention.
Maximum number of connections,
it's by default 10,000.
It's a huge number,
and you can even adjust it.
Yeah, all other databases,
relational that we talked
about, don't have that value,
and you cannot raise it.
So it scales beautifully.
Yeah, there is no problem
just to have 10,000 Lambda functions
talking to it in parallel
to this database,
it's just due to the
architecture of querying process,
it just scales beautifully.
Maximum transaction time
is five minutes, maximum.
Oleksii will be talking why
those limits are as they are,
but you need to think of it
as just mostly for the
microservice application.
So in case you have some analytics job
that needs to run more than five minutes,
probably it's not the best
fit for this database.
But for certain normal
microservice type of things,
five minutes for transaction
seems to be okay.
Maximum connection duration is 60 minutes,
so one hour.
In the case you designed a
server-side connection pool,
you define the time to
live of the connection,
please define it no
longer than 60 minutes.
Because you will be disconnected,
and in case you define lower,
the pool will take care of this.
And the same if you're
talking through the database
through psql, after one hour
you will be disconnected
and need another token.
Yeah, you need to grab another token,
then you are in for one hour.
Maximum number of rows
change in the transaction,
in one transaction, is only 3,000 rows.
And by changing, I mean delete and update.
So in case you have such a use case,
like I would like to have
to delete one time per year
all orders and items
older than five years,
because I don't need them from
the accounting point of view,
you need to think about how
to divide the job into parts
so that no more than 3,000
rows will be changed.
That brings you just to think
from the backend perspective
how to divide it.
Yeah, because normally you would say,
delete from timestamp,
you will get an exception
if the number of rows
will be more than 3,000.
The same for update.
Maximum size of modified data
in one transaction, 10 MiB,
so you need to think,
just if it's normal data,
then you probably will not hit that limit.
There are also other things
that are currently not supported,
and I will stress that "currently,"
there are no reason why
it cannot be supported,
it might come every day,
but until today, it's the case.
No support for JSON and JSONB.
Yeah, so it's not 100%,
it's Postgres-compatible,
but DSQL doesn't support all features.
There are no columns with default values.
There are no temporary tables.
There are no triggers currently.
Personally, I used them a lot previously,
but now it just brings the
business logic to the trigger,
it's difficult to refactor.
But I use for example triggers
to set the timestamps to now,
as a default value.
It was kind of one of
my favorite use cases.
I can do it in the backend
as well, but anyway.
There are no sequences,
that's unusual.
You can use time-based UUID
version 7 instead of this,
this is 36-digit number,
and version seven, it supports
that you can order by time.
And sometimes it's okay,
for example, you can design
order item IDs like your UID,
because you don't expose
them, that's fine.
But for the things like order ID
that you would like to expose via email,
and somebody can call
the call center and say,
"Something is wrong with my order,"
they probably don't want
to say a 36-digit number.
So you need to think how to
map in this rare situation
to the normal value, yeah?
Maybe they will be support later.
There are no partitions,
in case you have multi-tenant application,
it might be interesting, yeah?
In case not, probably you don't use it.
And you can use only
functions written in SQL,
which is probably fine.
Yeah, you can use probably C++,
but it's not supported.
But I think SQL is okay.
And other things that are not supported,
constraints or commands.
Foreign keys, that's something
really unusual probably.
You can do your joins,
but there is no foreign key support
which will ensure the data integrity.
And that might be crucial,
because I like foreign keys,
and I sometimes, or nearly
always, I would say,
define something on delete cascade there.
For example, if I delete the order,
I would like that all order items
will be deleted automatically,
and I can do this with
foreign key on delete cascade.
It's not supported.
Another way to do it
is to do it via trigger,
which is also not supported.
Yeah?
So this is then up to you to think
and write this in the business logic,
that you delete the order,
and you delete all order
items in the business logic,
not relying on foreign key on cascade.
Currently, yeah?
There is no truncate,
like we can delete the
whole data in the table,
and there is no vacuum,
but the architecture of DSQL
just doesn't require vacuum
because of the limitations and constraints
that we talked about.
There is also no PGVector support
in case you would like to use some like,
something for embeddings and so on,
this database is currently
not for this use case.
You can use other
Postgres-compatible databases,
RDS, Aurora, or OpenSearch
that support that.
So this is for normal
microservice applications.
And with that, we have
some final thoughts.
Oleksii?
So, once again, these
features might come, yes?
But now, you need to think about it.
- Yeah, with all of that,
let's see what we have
learned today on this session.
So first thing which is very important,
that thanks to the Query Processor running
into the Firecracker microVM,
we are getting virtually endless scale.
We are not only able to
scale it to whatever size,
we can do it fast,
and these results from the tests,
the cold start is almost nothing.
And thanks to the architecture,
we can adjust different
components of the system
very dynamically, depends on the workload,
and clean up resources
after us very effectively.
And, as in any serverless service,
we currently have some
constraints that are needed
to get the better performance
and get the better results.
So here, for example,
five-minute length of the transaction
allows us to get the
better write consistency,
and get the better performance from them
when the adjudicators need to decide
and resolve the conflicts.
It also helps us to clean up the resources
using the garbage collector,
which resulting in the fact that
now we don't need vacuum by design,
because all the reference
will be just cleared.
And with the 3,000 rows
that can be changed
within the transaction,
we have the stable performance
with only one flush of
the buffered memory.
And to get the best of your usage of DSQL,
you should create many
connections to your front end,
to parallel concurrent connections,
which will result in the
a lot of Query Processors,
which will basically do
the horizontal scaling.
You should consider to use small rows
and small transactions,
so it will decrease the
load to the Adjudicator
for deciding which
transactions are in conflict,
and to resolve this conflict.
For the same reason,
you may consider to use separate clusters
for each of your microservices,
again, to have less conflict,
and to have less aborted transactions.
And if you will find any bottlenecks,
or you would like to know
like, where the money goes,
Explain Analyze will help you with this.
And, of course,
don't forget about client-side
connection pooling,
this also will help you
with your performance.
And with that, I'm passing
the mic to Vadym to wrap up.
- So, one benefit of Explain Analyze,
you can use Explain Analyze Verbose,
and it will also display
you the price, the DPUs now,
and you can do it in this browser editor.
We didn't touch about pricing,
but it helps you just to understand
how much does it cost to
run that and that query,
by the way.
So, okay, I go back.
So yeah, to wrap up,
DSQL is very easy to
set up and get started.
Nearly no infrastructure management,
multi-region out of support
right from the beginning.
ACID support is there
completely, as we like,
especially no eventually
consistency at any scale,
which is very important,
any scale for single and
multi-region cluster.
And high availability is also there.
Now I will provide you
opinionated comparison
of the databases that we talked about,
DynamoDB, RDS, Aurora,
Aurora Serverless v2,
and now DSQL, but only for
the serverless workload.
Please understand,
three stars doesn't mean
it's three times better than one star,
but three stars means
it's just a better fit
for the serverless workload,
or solves the problem
better than two stars,
and two stars solves the
problem better than one star.
So, set-up experience,
Aurora DSQL, brilliant, like DynamoDB.
Simply is just quick, and you are there.
Auto-scaling experience,
up and down, automatically,
you don't need to do anything
to decide how much to scale,
and how much to scale down,
it's just no cold starts.
Beautiful.
ACID support, completely there,
like for all relational databases.
No need for connection-side pooling.
You don't need RDS proxy,
there is no data API,
it scales beautifully,
we can have tens of
thousand Lambda functions
talking to a database, and it works.
And yeah, it works with familiar drivers
and object-relational mapping
framework, as we like.
But of course, yeah, it looks beautiful,
like Aurora DSQL kind of
supports every use case.
There are challenges you
need to be aware of there.
The first one, as we talked,
the feature gap to be
100% Postgres-compatible
is currently quite big.
Yeah, you need to follow,
especially if you start now from scratch
with your application,
if you know that you can
adopt to this, I think,
but if you would like to say,
"I would like to migrate
your application,"
you will probably run into situation
that you need sequences,
you need foreign keys.
Yeah? You run into this 3,000
updates in one transaction.
You need to rewrite code.
And it poses the question,
is it the right time to migrate?
Yeah?
But if you start from scratch,
and you know that you can start,
and I'm pretty confident
that the features will come with time.
And, of course, the service quota
are a bit restrictive for
serverless database users,
like five minutes
transaction time, 3,000 rows.
We know these quotas from DynamoDB,
and we appreciate them,
because they are there for a reason,
to get the best performance.
But for relational database users,
more or less would like to do
everything with the database
without any limitations,
which is sometimes also not a good thing,
because the query
performance will be worse
if you will join how you would like,
it just also doesn't work like this.
And these limitation also are there
to just deliver the best experience.
But anyway, you need to know them,
you need to understand them
when you design or migrate.
So this is the QR code
of my GitHub repository
with the examples,
yeah, with the code that I have shown you,
with connectors and without connectors.
So you can scan,
or you can write to me,
you can find me, like on LinkedIn,
and I will give you the link
to the repository if you wish.
And for that, thank you very much.
Don't forget to rate the session.
- It's very important for us.
- Yeah.
To receive the feedback.
And we are here to answer your questions,
I think it's kind of the silent sessions,
but we are here.
Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
(audience applauding)