Morning, morning.
how's everyone going?
So my name's Craig Johnson. I am a principal
solution architect at Forward Networks.
Um, so quick show of hands, who here
would consider themselves a network
engineer, network guy, something like that.
OK. Who here has
taken down a production network before?
Awesome, awesome.
Everyone has, um, so what I wanna
talk today about is introducing
a little bit of chaos into your
networks
in an effort to build more resiliency, an
idea that we've taken from on-prem
data center networks. I wanna apply the
same kind of logic into our
AWS networks.
So a little bit about me. Most of my career
has actually been on the data center
side. I spent many, many years at Cisco's got the
CCIEs. They're, they're all expired these
days.
Most of what I do is on the CLI.
I'm gonna apply a lot of those same principles
here. Um, also, if you're interested in a
community builder program, uh, definitely,
um, you know, reach me afterwards. It's a great
program. It's probably the best thing I've done in my career in the last 5
years. Um, and I also run a
local networking group. If you're, uh, anyone in the
Dallas area, feel free to come, uh, talk to me
about that.
So, let's call a little ground
rules. Like I said, I'm a CLI junkie.
Most of what we're gonna do is going to be
using the CLI and actually
putting these ideas into practice.
So. Being an engineer,
network engineer is hard.
It's always the network. That's what the shirt is.
It's always and everyone always blames the
network, and that's the mindset we're going to go
into. It's natural that they blame the
network. The network is the glue of
everything inside your, your environment.
So when something doesn't work, you know,
I can't say it's the database. Can't say it's the
application. The network is the thing that connects all of
those things together,
so that's the kind of mindset you have to take. You're always
having to disprove it's the
network, and I'm gonna show you how to do
a little bit of that to give you some of that confidence
and to give you the way to say, hey, I
definitely can show management and everyone else
the network is not the problem here.
Like I mentioned, we're not gonna do, I'm gonna show you
some screenshots, and that'll be some useful, but I'm going
to show you mostly what we do either via pipelines,
CLI infrastructure is code.
Um, this is gonna come from a repo that I
have that I've created that'll actually, you'll be able to
download. At the end, you'll have a QR code for
it. You can see the code that I've done to create
this and actually run some of the scripts
that I've done to be able to actually
introduce some of this chaos into your environment.
And of course,
What I don't like about doing things,
you know, in the cloud is a lot of my traditional
network engineer tools don't really work
anymore, you know, I used to be able to,
you know, log into a router. I SSH into
my Cisco router, run a few show commands,
show some routes, do some pings.
I can't really SSH into a transit gateway
to look at its routes. I can go to that screen
and kind of see it, but I can't really look
at a routing table. The time there really isn't
a routing table to look at.
I don't have access to the same level
of functionality.
Now. Some people will say, well, just turn on things like
flow logs, and you get that. I'll explain why
that's not a great idea in a second.
But as I said, all of the code that I'm gonna use
today and what is available at the end of this presentation.
You'll be able to go to my repo, download it, play
with it. It's an environment you can set up, but
you can also take the concepts into your own
environment. OK.
So today, the game plan, what we're going to do.
I'm gonna talk about breaking your network for fun
and profit. This is going to be showing how I'm going
to introduce some of this controlled chaos
into your environment.
But first we have to gather a baseline. So
before you make your change, you know, if
you've ever done any network changes, before you
go to your change control board,
you have to have a baseline of what your environment
looks like and to verify everything
works before that.
How do we do that and how do we prove that out?
Do I actually
trust. What my applications are saying,
and this is always the disconnect
between the network team and the rest of
the IT crowd is that, well, the
network sees the flows, but you know you
don't always really know if the application is actually
working as it is. I'm going to show you why we don't
necessarily need to trust those, but we can get our own
metrics on this.
I want to introduce you to the idea
of verifying my network based on
intent.
So when I do a change, I've got, I've got a mop,
and I'm like, OK, I'm going to make these route
changes, these attachment changes, these changes
to an ALB.
I don't want you to think about it that way. I want you to
think about what is the intent of
my change, like what flows do
I want? Where's my source, my destination,
ports and protocols?
Is that actually working? Whatever
I change in the middle doesn't matter so much
because oftentimes I'm not the only one making the
change. I can verify that my change
was done correctly. I implemented it
the way I meant to.
That doesn't mean the intent was right. So I
want to give you a, a,
a view on that.
We're going to iterate on this a little bit, so I want
to show you how we can take this and actually
iterate through your environment, so you're not just
saying, OK, do this one time, do it for one
flow. We can do this in a more automated
way so that we're not doing this manually. Now, a lot of
people still do the click-offs manually,
but this will let you integrate it into
your pipelines. My code has examples of that too.
So it turns out there's actually quite a
few network engineer tools
um in AWS that a lot of people don't know
about, and I'm, it, it kind of makes me sad that people
don't really understand some of these tools that
we can use
are in lieu of me SSHing into
a device. I can use AWS
Network Manager to get a good view
of my entire environment. If you are in one
or more VPCs,
you've got transit gateways, you've got uh
transit gateway connects, you've got direct
connects, VPNs, lots of tools that
I wanna show you here.
The main thrust I want to really focus on
is using the reachability analyzers. This
will help me look at the intent of my
environment and help me figure out what's
going on here.
So it turns out you can actually have
quite a bit here that honestly, I don't
see many people using because you just
kind of assume the network works, but when it doesn't,
you kind of, you know, rush to some of these
to figure things out.
I want to give you an idea of how to use this today
to figure these things out.
So. The first thing you
want to do, and I rarely see people do
this, is get a good visualization of
your network.
Now if this was a data center network, this
would be me either, you know, opening
up Visio or Dryo, connecting
my routers together. Maybe I've got an
automated tool to do this,
but generally it's just
doing those things and connecting them. Way back in the day, getting
one of those really big plotters and making my
nice network map with all of my
top of rack switches and everything together.
I fortunately don't have to do that on. AWS.
I can use AWS Network
Manager
to visualize all of my AWS
components, my transit gateways,
my direct connects, my VPNs,
my transit gateway connects just
by registering in Network Man doesn't
cost you anything, and it's a way
for you to pull up all of this environment
together. So it's super, super easy to
do. All you really need to do, and of course you
can do this via the GUI, but like I said, CLI,
you create a global network and network manager.
You create the sites that you're going to
do. So it's not even just your AWS components.
Obviously, you're gonna have direct connects, VPNs,
things that are gonna connect to external. I
can create sites and actually show you where
those things are connected to,
to create this kind of picture of your environment.
Reference the same ID. You could even
put locations because this will give you a global
map to show you where these things are at, so
I can say, hey, here's all of my
end to end network, not just AWS
but everything else with it.
I can create devices, so obviously I don't
manage those devices, but I can add like my Cisco
routers, my on-prem firewalls into
this,
same thing there,
and then create links to show how they connect
them and even put bandwidth on those links.
Now, once I've done that,
I can actually even do this across accounts
too. So many people don't have only one account. You
can do this across multiple accounts as long as
you give the right level of IAM access,
you can create the entire
environment no matter how big or small this
has to look like.
So once I have created this, this
creates a dynamic map of
my environment. So I can show, and it also
updates whether things are up or down.
So you see the purple links are my transit gateway
connection, the green links are my
VPN connectivity or direct connection.
Everything, including my VPCs, transit
gateway connects,
everything that I have in this environment is
gonna show up in this environment. As things
get updated, as you add new VPC
attachments, as you add firewalls, as you add
anything to this,
it's going to update. So you can always say, hey, I
know before I make any of my changes,
this is a visual representation of my
network so that you can go to your change control board and
say, the network is in a good state,
at least from a high macro level,
to show me how my entire global
network is set up.
OK, now that you've done that,
let's move on to actually doing a
couple of guardrails here.
So a lot of people say, well, I
can just turn on flow logs, or I can use
synthetic transactions. There's a lot of
good observability tools to do that.
It doesn't really help on a network site.
They are super useful though.
The giddiest steady state of what the traffic
of my network looks like. So before I've made
the change, I can get an idea of, OK, here are
the traffic that's going on in my environment.
Here's what it looks like.
What does that mean for the rest of the environment though?
Now, if I have no idea, now as a network
guy, I often don't know what my applications are
doing. Things are deploying, spinning up, spinning
down all the time.
This gives me a really great, great way to
say, OK, here's the traffic in my environment.
They are kind of pricey to leave on all the time. Turning
on flow logs, if you have a lot of traffic
that generates synthetic data, tells
me source, destination, 5 tuple
data for all that.
Kind of expensive to leave on all the time, so
not something you may not want to do
if you don't need that level of data analysis.
For outages, and we are actually trying
to figure out what's wrong,
they're not so useful. And the reason is, is
these are things that are looking at the
state of the network, looking at the traffic.
If I've broken something and it's down,
the traffic's not flowing. It doesn't tell me
where something's going on.
And it also has a lot of different places to look.
I've got more than a few VPCs. I've
got to look at flow logs in multiple places.
There's some good AI tools that'll help you figure this
out, but kind of not very useful here.
But definitely have them when you need
them, turn them on. You've got a good monitor of
what the network looks like if you have transactions
down, ALDs, things like that.
OK, so let's talk about intent
checks. So intent checks are how we're going
to build this model of the environment.
Provides a way to ensure changes I
make never break the network. The
idea is that whenever I make a change,
I want to make sure I exit that change window,
never having had a broken network. And I
need a way to prove it not just to myself,
but to all the other stakeholders.
So network changes are by far the
largest source of outages that you will
see in an environment. Now,
network changes can encompass a lot of different things,
but the reason that is, is back to my original
point, the network touches everything,
so they're going to cause the most outages. We need
to provide a way to prevent that.
I should know all my critical flows. This
gives me
back to the previous slide. It gives me an idea of what
my critical flows are, or at least I
know what my applications care about, you know, this
source goes to this destination through
this load balancer, whatever it happens to
be. Like I said, flow logs only check
for actual traffic. They don't help me when things
are down.
I need a way to make sure the network
is performing like I expect it
to pre and post change, and
that's really the key, pre and post.
How can I do that though without relying
on a bunch of application verifiers
on the phone and say, yep, my app looks good, my app
looks good, you know, any size environment
that could be 100 people on a call checking
for these things. I need to be able to do this
myself and as a network guy, I don't
necessarily have visibility in those applications.
This is where Reachability Analyzer comes in. It
is absolutely your best friend in making
network changes, and I highly recommend you
start using it.
What this means is we're going to introduce a
little bit of chaos into our environment, but
we're going to use Reachability Analyzer
to help me figure out
if the, the what I've done actually
breaks the environment.
Now, the simulated change we're going to make here,
we can make an actual real change.
My. Environment here is actually going to show more
of a simulated level change.
I want to make sure any change that I
make doesn't infect
the intent of the network though.
Now what kind of change could it? Could be a messed up route.
I could mess up a security group,
network ACL. Maybe I screwed up a
whole attachment.
It doesn't really matter.
You can use this for a macro viewed
transit gateway analyzer if I want to go across
regions or even more of a micro view.
Look at, you know, connectivity between instances
in a VPC or a lambda or whatever.
So let's go ahead and break something.
We're gonna go ahead and create some chaos
inside our network. So there's lots of fun things we
could do. I could block something in a security
group, misconfigure an attachment
somewhere, maybe create a black hole route,
change ALB targets, really,
you know, or even just kind of ruin my entire network fireball
policy. Lots of things I could do
that in just in the course of making changes
is pretty common and super
normal that you'll see in an environment.
Now, before you start doing this, you might not want to
do this on your production network. It's, it's your career, you,
you handle it how you want to, but you might want to do
this in a twin of environment or use
my repo to actually practice some of
this. Once you get a little better at this, you can
start to introduce some of this control
chaos, but maybe not just yet.
So let's go ahead and run our pre pre-flight
uh intent checks.
OK, so this is reachability analyzer.
Notice what I've done here is I have a
series of checks that are here.
These are all point in time checks
though. So every time that I, I
do this on a baseline, I do this before and
after my change,
I get a point in time that says, yes, the
network is functioning correctly.
And when I say the network is functioning correctly,
what that means is I've specified a
source interface, source port, source IP
address, destination,
ports and protocols that I'm trying to get to,
and. Going to tell me the exact path
it takes through my AWS environment.
It goes from the instance I'm going from, the ENI
that it's attached to, any security groups
and network ACLs you pass through,
the routing table that it's configured with,
all the way till it finally gets to its destination.
This is what I mean by intent. I have
source, destination,
everything in between, and really all I care
about is a yes no. Does this pass? Does
this fail?
From the previous slide, you saw that all of those
were successful.
So I run these checks. I
give this to my change
review board and say, yes, every one of my
intent checks are passing before I make
the change.
I make my change, and then I run them again afterwards
and see what happens.
So let's do that.
We'll go ahead and make our change that
breaks something in the environment.
The reason this is useful is if I'm
making a change and I don't know the effect of it,
trying to get all of my applications
to check, that could take a long time.
I only
So much time in my maintenance window
to do this though.
Like I said, I can, and I could run my pings
and trace routes and things like that.
That's only going to give me basic connectivity. That's
not going to tell me,
you know, going through a firewall or going
through a security group, am I actually hitting the right
ports.
And it's extremely limited in time, you know, if I
have a change window and I have 4 hours to do it,
if I mess up something and I
don't know necessarily what it was or
where I need to pinpoint,
getting all my application people to tell me,
oh, this app works, this app doesn't work, but
it works in this region but not in this region, this
is a way that you can use this to
tell you right away what things work, what
things don't work.
OK, so I've made my bed
change. I've run my analyzer afterwards.
You can see it shows up as not reachable.
Now I quickly can say, OK, not reachable.
Well, I need to troubleshoot what's going on with this.
Or if it's near the end of the change window,
I back out of the change.
Going inside, you can see exactly
what's going on here.
Fourth line down, it says you've got an attachment
misconfigured on this
particular VPC.
That's the issue you need to go to. It may not
be that simple to tell you. Exactly what the
issue is, but you at least have that past
fail to know
that change that you made.
Here is the pinpoint, and you can
know, you know, you're not guessing what the state
of the network is. You have a good intent because
you've run this before and after you've made the
change. You've got actionable data.
If the change goes bad, you know exactly
what to do for next time, and you're not saying,
I'll back out the change, revert everything, and you're
still blind because you don't exactly know what happened.
You've got the forensic data to figure this out.
Now, I want you to think about setting this up in a pipeline. This
is what my, so this manual changes are
just fine.
And you can use this for all sorts of things,
attachments, transit gateways, VPC
endpoints, even VPN connectivity all the
way to your on-prem side.
Set this up in a pipeline. The idea is, is
the tagline I want you to walk away with is exit,
never exit a change with the broken
network. This is great for point in time
stuff, but you can automate this a little bit too.
The code that I have does this via terraform.
You can do this via cloud formation, where I
actually have a pre and post to say
before I make the change, run my reachability
checks, give me a pass,
execute the change via the same pipeline,
run those same checks again gives me a
pass fail. If I get any fails, I
can have a human intervention or I can
optionally back out of the change entirely. You've
created some chaos to give you an idea, but
to give you a way to really narrow down to
figure out what's going on.
Now,
what a lot of people say is my network is super,
super complex. You've shown me just a few
flows here.
I have thousands of applications
that are going on. I don't really know what
they look like.
How do I create all of those intent checks?
That's where those observability tools I had
before come in. Those flow logs that
you had, those synthetic transactions.
This is where you can look at all of the top
talkers. On your network you get obviously you gather
this data from your applications,
but I look at the top talkers and I
say, OK, here is my critical application. Just
because they're sending this much traffic gives
me source, destination, IP address,
all things I can easily plug into
reachability analyzer.
Firewall rules either from a physical or
virtual or AWS network firewall
will tell you which ones are getting the most hits,
so you can also see that data too.
You can update these intent checks over
time in an automated way. This is a super
easy thing to do. In my code, I
actually have these flow logs running
and Sagemaker dashboards, so you can
actually start to pull them out and queries
it, so you'll be able to see that kind of data too.
It's a very, very good use case for AI
to keep this in a continually updated pipeline.
So that's the code. That's the link that I have
there. It'll be a QR code pop up. But what
I want you to think about,
schedule your first sort of chaos
hour. This is something you should do, kind of
like a DAA, something that you do
monthly, quarterly. Do something
that, you know, is going to, you don't
necessarily know what the change is.
Different person breaking the network is
one that's fixing it. Now my code does
this too. It has a randomized break on there
so you can practice this on your own.
But you want to blend these kind of tools together,
you know, the observability tools are great for
pulling the data in.
This kind of, you know, thought
process that people have, getting people to really
think about,
hey, when I make my change, I need to have
these checks, not because they're going to make, you
know, they'll take a little more time, sure,
but it really saves me because I can
prove out to people
network is the problem,
network is not the problem.
Use the repo and the run book to go for it.
And if you'd like, submit some PR improvements,
and I'll be here in the, in the
theater expo.
There's the QR code for it as well if you'd like to
link to the repo for it.
So feel free to come up with the, ask any questions,
and uh I appreciate everyone.