- Thank you all so much
for coming this early in the morning.
I really appreciate it.
And how many of you,
or for how many of you,
this is the very first session
of their very first re:Invent ever?
Wow.
A lot of first timers here.
Well, you are in for a treat
and quite a bit of walking
as you might have already noticed.
Right.
Imagine that you have built this
simple serverless
architecture in the cloud.
You've picked the
services you want to use,
you connect them together,
and everything just works like magic.
So my show that you, of course,
decide to go to production with it,
and all of a sudden hell breaks loose
and things start to fail in
all possible shapes and forms.
Now you are convinced that you personally
have that absolutely nothing wrong
except for maybe not reading
all the extensive documentation
about all the services
and all the components that you are using.
But let's be real, who does
that nowadays anyway, right?
So what's the next logical step?
Maybe you swear off using the architecture
or services ever again because
well, they just don't work.
And honestly, what's wrong with the cloud?
Why doesn't it work?
Maybe serverless is just
another expensive fad.
Maybe we should just all go back on-prem
and use good old monoliths.
But then again, purely
statistically speaking,
we should consider that maybe
the problem not in the cloud
or the cloud providers.
Maybe it's not even us or
the services that we picked,
not even the architecture.
So what is it then?
As Murphy's Law says,
"Anything that can go
wrong will go wrong,"
though I personally prefer the
more extended version of it
that says, "Anything that
can go wrong will go wrong,
and at the worst possible time."
My name is Anahit.
I'm cloud architecture and
engineering lead at F-Secure.
This is a global cybersecurity
and privacy company
with over 35 years of
experience in the field.
And I'm also an AWS Hero.
And there's a funny thing I noticed
after becoming an AWS
Hero several years back
that people started to come with me
or to me with this smirks on their faces
and saying, "So tell us now
what's wrong with the cloud?
Why doesn't it just work?"
Well, today, I'm finally
here to answer that.
Well, maybe not exactly that,
but I want us to look
together at something
that we as humans don't usually
feel comfortable looking at.
Failures.
And I hope that this talk helps you
to become a bit more aware and curious,
to spot patterns that others
don't necessarily see.
To have the tools and to ask the questions
to make conscious critical decisions
rather than believing in magic,
taking controls in your own hands,
and finally becoming
a little bit paranoid,
but in a good way,
because to borrow words
of Martin Kleppmann,
"In distributed systems,
suspicion, pessimism,
and paranoia pay off."
Now, before we start talking
about distributed systems
and failures any further,
let's briefly go back
to our fictional story
about failing serverless architecture.
It actually had a prequel to it.
So once upon a time,
you were a developer who
started developing software
that was probably supposed
to run on a single machine
somewhere in non-prem data center.
So all you cared about were the so-called
functional requirements
so that your code works,
that's exactly what it's supposed to,
and of course, has as little
box and failures as possible.
That was your definition of reliability.
Now, there could have been
some occasional hardware failures,
but usually they didn't
worry about them too much.
Things either worked or they didn't.
Everything was nicely deterministic.
Next thing you know, you
find yourself in the cloud
maybe using virtual machines
and maybe also start developing software
that requires you to
think about certain levels
of so-called non-functional requirements.
So certain levels of
availability and scalability,
also reliability and resilience
get a whole new meaning.
Now, you still need to take care
of your functional requirements,
make sure that your code works
and has as little failures as possible.
But the complexity level
just went up a notch,
and now you need to
worry about so much more.
And failures are also
becoming a bit more pronounced
and a bit less deterministic.
Welcome to the dark side,
the wonderful world of distributed systems
where with great power
comes great responsibility.
But things didn't stop there.
And before you know it,
you jump over to the serverless world,
their things start to look simple again,
you just pick services,
you connect them together,
and everything works like magic.
You don't really see any
machines around anymore.
And the term serverless actually suggests
that you don't need to be
looking for any machines,
you don't need to be
caring about any machines
and the cloud providers take
care of this ilities for you.
So reliability, scalability, availability,
and you are back to just
worrying about your own code,
working properly and not
having a worry in the world.
Of course, we do know that's
not exactly how things went,
because everything that
can go wrong will go wrong.
So what is it that can go wrong exactly?
To set the stage,
let's talk about cloud
distributed systems,
serverless in very simplified terms.
And if the things I'm gonna cover
for the next couple of
minutes are obvious to you,
just bear with me and
maybe enjoy the animations.
But in really simplified terms,
this is the distributed system
is just a bunch of machines
connected by a network.
And while it provides a lot of new
and exciting ways to build
solutions and solve problems,
it also provides a lot of new
and exciting ways for things to go wrong.
Because resources you
are using are not limited
to a single machine anymore.
They're spread around multiple
servers, data centers,
maybe even geolocations.
And then instead of just
one machine that can fail,
now you have plenty.
And all those failures can
happen on different levels.
It can be operating system,
maybe the CPU, GPU, memory,
I know load balancers, you name it.
And all of those failures
can happen completely
independently from each other
in a most non-deterministic way possible.
But the worst thing here is that,
those machines are talking to
each other over the network.
The network is known for
one thing in particular,
wherever any communication
happens over the network,
it will eventually fail.
Now any cloud is built on top
of such distributed systems.
That's where their superpowers come from.
The cloud providers take care
of the most difficult part
of handling the underlying complexity
of the distributed architecture,
obstructing that complexity away from you
while giving you access to
this fast pool of resources
that no individual user
could ever achieve.
But especially on the bigger scale,
if something has a tiny
little chance of happening,
it most certainly will.
Now, serverless managed
services are a step up
in the obstruction ladder.
They make the underlying infrastructure
seem almost invisible,
almost magical,
so much so that we might
even forget it's there.
But by using the serverless services
and fully managed services,
we didn't just magically
teleport to a different reality.
We are still living in a very
same messy physical world
with all its underlying complexities.
And this higher level of
abstraction with serverless
definitely makes a lot of things easier,
just like a higher level
programming language does.
But it also comes with a danger.
Being seemingly simple to use,
it can also give us this
false sense of security,
which will make spotting
those potential issues
that much harder
because after all, they're
also abstracted away from us.
And the reality is, those
failures didn't go anywhere.
They are still there embedded
in the very same distributed system,
underlying distributed system
just waiting to show up.
And as Leslie Lamport
said, it already, 1987,
"But the distributed system
is one in which the failure
of a computer you didn't even know existed
can render your own computer unusable."
And we could rephrase it for serverless.
So a serverless architecture
is one in which the failure
of the computer you definitely
didn't know was there
can render your entire
architecture unusable.
But with serverless,
rather than seeing
those hardware failures,
maybe blue screens,
we see failures manifest in a different
somewhat less obvious ways.
Now let's climb one last step
in our obstruction ladder
and let's focus on building
distributed applications
on top of serverless and
fully managed services.
So in essence, we are
splitting the problem
that we are fixing into smaller pieces.
For each piece, we're picking
a service or a resource,
and then we're connecting all of them
with things like events,
messages, HTTP requests,
all of which are using the
network in some shape or form.
So in essence, distributed architectures
are actually mirroring the
underlying distributed systems.
They also give us this great power
of building applications in
a completely different ways.
But just like the underlying
distributed systems,
they are susceptible to
various same trade-offs.
The architectures that you're gonna build
are likely gonna be complex.
Every piece can fail at any given moment
in a completely non-deterministic way.
And whenever there is any communication
happening over the network,
it will eventually fail.
Now a special case of these
distributed architectures
are so-called data applications.
With data applications,
we are basically dealing
with large volumes of
data we want to store,
collect, and process them.
And the data itself
can really be anything.
Log data, website
clickstreams, gaming data,
and you name it.
The volume is what matters.
And on one hand, that volume
makes it somewhat easier
to spot those issues,
after all, on a bigger scale,
if things have a chance
of happening, they will.
But also with data applications,
usually the failures are
somewhat less obvious
than let's say with
cloud basic applications.
And quite often if there is a failure
we processing the incoming data,
nowadays is probably gonna
resent that data to you.
Once it's gone, it's gone.
So how do we deal with all that failures
in distributed architectures?
How do we make our architectures
such as data applications more resilient?
Now we are mirroring the
underlying distributed systems.
So let's take a look at
how the cloud providers
are dealing with all those
failures of distributed systems.
Now of course, there's a
lot of complex algorithms
and mechanisms at play
when we talk about the cloud resilience,
but surprisingly, two of
the most effective tools
for better resilience are
also seemingly simple.
They are timeouts and retries.
And those are also the things
that we absolutely need to be aware
when we are building our
distributed applications.
I call them these hidden superpowers,
because while they can
be extremely powerful
with helping us with the resiliency,
they can also backfire
if we are not careful of how we use them.
And we'll soon see what I mean.
Now you might have noticed
that so far I haven't been
mentioning any cloud providers,
any services at all
because those things are
universal to all of them.
But now it's time to finally move on
from our fictional service
about failing serverless architecture.
And it's also time for me to confess
that the story wasn't
that fictional after all.
It's actually something
that happened to me,
at least to some extent several years ago.
So I was working on this simple
powerful data architecture
for near real time data
streaming or pretty large scale.
So there we had a producer
that received our data
that we wanted to store and collect.
And for that purpose, we took
Amazon Kinesis Data Streams.
On one end, we connected
it to our producer,
and on the other end, we
connected AWS Lambda to it.
Just like that, we got ourselves simple,
powerful data processing pipeline.
We're extremely happy with it.
It was working perfectly.
Until one day we realized
that we were actually losing
data in that pipeline.
And the best part was we had
no idea it was happening,
thanks to the higher level of obstruction.
So what exactly was going on there?
Now, briefly, what is
Amazon Kinesis Data Streams?
It's a fully managed and
massively scalable service
to stream data on AWS.
After you write your data to the stream,
it appears there within milliseconds,
and it's available for you
to read for up to 24 hours
or up to a year if you
configure it to be so.
And during that time, you
can read process the data,
replayed in any way that you want,
as many times as you want,
but you cannot delete
the data from the stream.
Once it gets there, it stays
there for at least 24 hours.
Now Kinesis is a very powerful tool.
It doesn't have any servers
or clusters for you to manage
and also scales massively.
And to achieve that massive scalability,
Kinesis used as a concept of a shard.
And you can just think
of it as a ordered queue
within your stream.
And then your stream will be composed
of multiple such queues, multiple shards,
and the chart will come
with capacity limitations.
So you can only write one megabyte
or 1,000 records of data
per second in each shard.
Though each shard comes
with limited capacity,
but the number of shards
you can have in the stream
is virtually unlimited.
So you can add as many shard as you want
to stream as much data as you need.
Now to get all that data to Kinesis,
there are essentially
two different API calls.
You can either write individual records
or you can batch up to 500 records
and send them as an individual
put records request.
And batching in general is a more powerful
and more resource effective
way of making API calls,
especially in this data
intensive applications
where the number of individual requests
can get really high really quickly.
Well, once again, with great power
comes great responsibility,
and we will see very soon what it means
in the context of batching.
Now, we have established by now
those that failures in distributed systems
and architectures are
pretty much inevitable,
especially at a bigger scale.
But how do those failures manifest
at this higher level of obstruction
with services like Kinesis, for example?
it's actually pretty straightforward.
When you interact with the
service from your code,
you're usually making API calls,
and every API call can fail.
Now the good news is that,
if you are using AWS SDK
to make those API calls,
it will take care of most
of those failures for you.
Of course, AWS knows firsthand
that the failures will happen.
So they have built into
the SDK this essential tool
for better resiliency or
superpower as we know it,
the retries.
Now, the trouble with
the retries in general
is that they have a potential of turning
small intermittent problem
like a network glitch
into a massive one,
because retries can have
unexpected blast radius.
They can cause this ripple
effect of cascading failure
through your system
and ultimately bring
the entire system down,
because retries are inherently selfish,
just like hitting that
refresh button in a browser,
we all know we shouldn't do
that, but we do that anyway.
Retries implied that our
request is more valuable,
more important than anything else,
and we are willing to put
resources to use extra capacity
to maybe incorrect the cost
on the downstream system
just to make sure that
our request goes through.
But the retries are not
even always effective,
neither are they safe.
To start with, which failures
are we even retrying?
If the downstream system
is under a lot of load
and for example, it's an API or a database
that is heavily overloaded
and that's what causing the failure,
well, retrying might
just make matters worse.
Or if there was a timeout,
but you are not really ready to wait
for the retry to complete,
for example, you have
your own SLA requirements,
then retrying is plain selfish.
It's just like hitting
that refresh button,
closing your window altogether.
You just wasted resources for nothing.
And what if the underlying
system also has retries built in,
maybe even on various
levels of the architecture?
Well, that can amplify
and multiply the retries
and make things even more dangerous,
especially if the underlying
system is under a lot of load
and you are starting to retry right away
without giving it the
chance to recover first.
And what if the operation
that you're retrying
has side effects like database update?
Well, then retry can have
unexpected side effects
and unexpected results.
So there are many different
considerations here,
but the bottom line is,
we need to be very mindful
about how we use this
superpower, the retries.
Now AWS SDK comes with this
built-in safety measures.
So if I request to a service like Kinesis
or other services fails, for some reason,
AWS SDK will handle only the
so-called retryable errors,
transient failures like
service unavailable,
other 500 errors timeouts.
And for those errors,
it will retry the failed
requests on your behalf
behind the scenes,
but it'll stop on after
certain number of attempts.
And in between those attempts,
it will use the so-called
exponential backoff
where the time between retry attempts
is increasing exponentially.
And those are seemingly simple things,
but they're crucial if
we want to make sure
that retries are serving us as
a tool for better resiliency
because they can actually do the opposite.
So we only want to retry if
it can help the situation,
so only the transient failures.
And when we do retry,
we want to stop when it doesn't
help the situation anymore
to avoid that ripple effect
of cascading failures
and avoid killing the underlying system.
And we also want to spread retry attempts
as uniformly as possible,
not to overwhelm the underlying system,
not to send those bursts
of retries right away.
And with AWS SDK, you are
given those safety measures,
but you also have a
possibility to configure
some of those parameters.
And here's an example
of how you would do that
with JavaScript SDK.
Now every language will
have their own ways
to configure those parameters
and different defaults,
but all of them will give
you to configure some of them
just as they will give you
just to configure the other superpower,
the timeout related values.
Now, if the timeout doesn't
sound like a superpower at all
and you think that it's not a big deal,
I have bad news for you again,
because in distributed systems,
timeouts are pretty much a given.
So let's once again briefly glance
under the hood in simplified terms.
When we interact with
services from our code,
we use API calls that are abstracted away
as SDK method calls.
And those SDK method calls
look exactly like any local
method invocation would.
But let's not let that fool us
because we know that the
network is still there.
You just abstracted away from us.
And any request that goes over the network
like API call to Kinesis
can fail for many various
different reasons.
Moreover, it's almost impossible to tell
if the request actually
went through or not,
because the failure can happen
on many different levels.
Maybe sending the request failed,
maybe receiving or processing
the request failed,
or maybe the request was processed,
but then you never got the response back.
Or maybe your request is
just waiting in the queue
because the downstream
system is overwhelmed.
In any case, the result is still the same.
You might be stuck waiting for something
that might never happen.
So this can happen to any service,
no matter how serverless or not it is.
And to prevent this from happening,
to prevent waiting forever,
AWS has built into the SDK,
this other tool for better
resiliency, the timeouts.
And the ability to
configure those timeouts
is a superpower that is given to us.
But just like with the retries,
we need to be extremely careful
of how we use this superpower,
because picking the right timeout value
is not an easy task at all.
Just like any decision
in your application,
in your architecture, it
will come with trade-offs.
If you pick two long timeouts,
they might be ineffective
and consumer resources.
Two short timeouts
might mean you are
starting to retry too early
without giving the original
request a chance to complete.
Moreover, the appropriate timeout values
will depend on the service or the API call
that you're using.
They will be different for all of them.
Now, for the longest time,
I've been scaring people
by telling that for all the requests,
AWS SDK, JavaScript SDK in particular
will wait for two entire minutes
before timing out the request.
Just think about it for a second.
We're usually dealing with low
latency systems like Kinesis
or maybe DynamoDB.
We are expecting the
response within milliseconds.
And here we are stuck for two minutes
just waiting for it to time out.
But since then things have
changed, things have evolved.
And JavaScript SDK has transitioned
from version 2 to version 3.
We have seen some changes
to the timeout default values as well.
So nowadays, the default
timeout value is infinite.
So either be prepared to be stuck
for a really long time
waiting for something that
might not actually happen
or much better take
control into your own hands
and configure those
timeout values yourself.
Now here we finally
get to the first reason
of losing data in my story,
not configuring the timeouts,
just blindly going with a default.
Waiting for too long for
the requested timeout
can actually exhaust the resources
of your producer application
and make it not being capable
to process new incoming data,
which ultimately means losing data.
And well, that's exactly
what we saw in our story.
So because of likely a
temporary glitch with a service
or a network that caused
the timeout to begin with,
we ended up with a complete system outage,
which is the opposite
from what the resilience system should be.
We need to mask the intermittent failures
instead of amplifying them,
we need to be able to recover from them.
Now obviously this doesn't sound too good,
but if your first thought is,
"Let's just set them the
timeouts to a really low value,"
well again, I have bad news for you
because in my opinion,
two short timeouts can
be even more dangerous.
Because having two short timeouts,
the request might be retried to early
before it had the chance to complete,
which inevitably will add extra load
on the underlying system,
which can cause all sorts of fun things
like increase the load,
increase the costs,
increase latencies,
but ultimately causing that
ripple effect of failures
and bringing the entire system down.
And again, if our goal is
to build a resilient system,
we should do the exact opposite.
We should recover from
individual failures.
And this is especially true
when timeouts are paired with the retries.
We need to be extremely careful.
So this is where wrongly
configured timeout
and retries value can actually
become a match made in hell.
And instead of being a better
tool for better resiliency,
they can do the exact opposite.
So once again, even though timeouts
and retries are extremely powerful,
we need to be very mindful
about how we use them,
and we should never just
blindly go with the defaults
because defaults are dangerous.
So when you go back to
your code, please go ahead,
check all the requests
that go over the network.
Maybe it's SDK calls,
maybe some other API calls.
Make sure that you know what
those timeout values are.
Make sure that you are controlling them.
Don't just blindly trust
it and go with a default,
especially if those timeouts
are paired with the retries.
Now so far I've been
talking about those failures
that are inherent to
distributed systems in general,
but there is another kind of failures
that are actually caused by
the cloud providers on purpose,
and those are failures that are related
to service limits and throttling.
So this can be especially
confusing in a serverless world
because we are promised scalability.
Somehow when we hear scalability,
we tend to assume infinite scalability.
Of course, if something
is too good to be true,
is that just that,
because no resource is scaling infinitely,
and sooner or later we
better face the reality.
And the reality is,
we don't have the entire
cloud at our disposal.
We are sharing the underlying
resources with everybody else,
which of course, has its trade offs.
So on one hand,
we do have this vast
pool of resources to use
like compute storage network,
but this also means
that an individual user
can try to monopolize resources,
and this will inevitably cause degradation
of services for others.
So service limits are actually there
to prevent that from happening.
And throttling is a tool to
enforce those service limits.
So if you remember in case of Kinesis,
we had this shard level limits,
which were one megabyte or
1,000 records per second.
And once you hit that limit,
you start get throttled.
So your requests start to fail.
And this brings us to the second reason
for losing data in my story.
So if you remember, I said that AWS SDK
takes care of the most
of the failures for you,
but of course, there's a catch.
Because in case of batch operations,
like we have put records here,
instead of just handling the
failure of the entire request,
we should also handle the
so-called partial failures.
Because you see those batch
operations, they're not atomic,
they are not either all
succeeds or all fails.
Part of your batch might go through
while the other part fails,
but you are still getting
the success response
back from the SDK.
So it's your responsibility
to detect those failures
and to handle them.
And the main reason for those failures
is exceeding service limit,
for example, because of a traffic spike.
So maybe you could ride
the start of the batch
to the stream successfully,
but then the limit was hit, and
the rest of the batch fails.
Now luckily, we already know
that there is this wonderful superpower
for better resilience that we can use
that can help us with
those transient errors
such as intermittent spike in traffic,
and that's of course, the retries.
And we also know that
when implementing retries
for any failures, we
should be very mindful,
and there are three key things
that we need to keep in mind.
So let's go over them one more time.
So we only want to be retrying
if it can actually help the situation.
We always want to set an
upper limit of retries
to stop retrying where
it doesn't help anymore.
And we want to use exponential backoff
between retry attempts.
Or even better so, use
exponential backoff and jitter.
And jitter is just this random component
that you add to the exponential backoff
to spread the retry
attempts more uniformly.
And what you're trying to achieve
is that you don't want
to put an extra load
on the underlying system,
because if you're hitting a service limit,
you're probably already
quite close to the edge,
so you don't want to be pushing
the system over the edge.
So you want to spread
those retry attempts.
And the jitter or exponential
backoff and jitter
in particular, is a very simple trick
that can actually dramatically
increase the success rate
of your retries.
And this is in fact something
that SDK uses under the hood,
I just didn't mention the
jitter in the previous slides.
So very simple trick, very powerful.
So if so far from this talk
you remember anything at all,
let it be timeout, partial
failures of batch operations,
and retries with exponential
backoff and jitter.
Those things can save
you a lot of headaches
in all sorts of unexpected situations.
And to borrow one of my favorite
quotes from Gregor Hohpe,
"Retries have brought more
distributed systems down
than all the other causes together."
Of course, this doesn't mean
that we shouldn't retry,
but again, it means that
we need to be very mindful
about how we do this,
not to kill the system
that we are trying to fix.
Speaking of which, let's now
take a look at another example
of what can happen if we
just let the matter slide
and go with the good old defaults.
And this one is from the
other end of our architecture.
So if you remember,
we had the Lambda function
there reading from our stream,
and it turns out that things
can escalate pretty quickly
on that end as well.
So let's take a look.
So Lambda itself is actually
a prime representative
or distributed architectures.
It's made of many hidden components
that work together behind the scenes
to make it so very powerful.
And one of those hidden components
is called the event source mapping.
The chances are high, you have
never heard about it before,
and the event source
mapping is hidden well under
the Lambda obstruction layer.
But when you are using Lambda
with event sources like
Kinesis for example,
or DynamoDB Streams or some others,
it's in fact event source mapping
that will be attached to that stream
and that will be reading
records from the stream
and it'll be batching those records
and invoking your Lambda
function with that batch for you.
Now the events mapping reads
records from the stream
from all the shards in
the stream in parallel.
So you would have the
same amount of Lambdas
reading concurrently from your
stream as you have shards.
Unless you are using one of the features
that event source mapping provides,
which called Parallelization Factor,
which where you can actually
have up to 10 Lambdas
reading from each shard in the stream.
Now this is a great example of the power
of parallel processing where
we can just speed things up
by throwing more Lambdas at each shard.
But of course, we all know
what comes with great power.
And we need to remember that
no resource scales infinitely,
not even Lambda.
And here, we have a chance
of hitting one such
important service limit
called Lambda concurrency limit.
And this one basically says that
or means that we can have a limited number
of Lambda invocations,
concurrent Lambda invocations
in the same account, in the same region.
And by default, this
number is set to 1,000.
Though I've heard
stories that new accounts
only get around 100, which
is extremely low for Lambda.
And this is a soft limit.
You can increase it by making a request,
but there still is going to be a limit.
And once you hit that limit,
all the new Lambda
invocations will be throttled,
you'll fail.
So imagine you have a Kinesis
stream with 100 shards
and then you set
Parallelization Factor to 10,
and here you have 1,000 Lambdas
just reading from your
stream at all times,
which probably is not a problem at all
until somewhere else in your
account, in your region,
some other Lambda that has
nothing to do with the stream
starts to fail for very unclear reasons.
And the reason is that your
stream and your stream consumer
has used the entire
Lambda concurrency limit
for that account, that region.
So this is a limit
that can actually have a blast radius
well beyond your own
architecture and your own system.
So you need to be
extremely mindful about it.
Now let's go back to reading
the records from the stream.
So what happens if Lambda fails
to read a record from your Kinesis stream?
Once again, I come with
good news and bad news.
So the good news is that
the event source mapping
comes with extensive air
handling capabilities.
Now, to use them, you
need to be aware of them
and you need to know where to look.
So the bad news is that you're very likely
to just blindly go with the defaults.
And we know by now that
defaults can be very dangerous.
Excuse me, went the other way.
So what happens by default
if Lambda fails to process
a batch of records?
Let's say there was a bad
record with some corrupted data,
Lambda could process
it, we didn't catch it.
Lambda throws an error.
What happens next?
So by default, even
though in this situation,
no amount of retries will
actually help anything
because there's a bad
record, you can't process it.
But by default, Lambda will
be retrying the bad batch
of records over and over
and over and over again
until the leader succeeds,
which again, we know is not gonna happen
or until the records in the batch expire,
which in case of Kinesis
happens in at least 24 hours.
So it's at least one day
of absolutely useless retries from Lambda.
And you can imagine all
those useless invocations,
and mind you, they are not free.
You are still paying for them.
But that's not the only problem there
because all those retries
will likely cause reprocessing
of the same data,
because you see from perspective
the event source mapping here,
either the entire batch succeeds
or the entire batch fails.
So even if the Lambda succeeded to process
some part of that batch
and then it failed,
the entire batch will be failed by default
and the entire batch will be
retried over and over again.
Like records 1, 2, 3 there,
you will probably reprocess
them a bunch of times.
But that's not it.
There's more.
Things get worse.
Because while all those
useless retries are happening,
no other records are being
processed from that shard.
That shard is technically stuck.
It's just waiting for something
that will never happen.
So because of one bad record,
now we have a shard that is
completely non-functional,
which is why it's often referred
to as a poison pill record.
Now,
after 24 hours pass,
your Lambda finally can go on.
The data is expiring from the stream,
of course, part of the batch
is leaving the stream unprocessed,
but that's life, what we can do about it.
Nothing at this point.
At least Lambda can now catch up.
It can continue processing
data from the shard.
Now the problem here is that,
by that point of time, your
shard is probably filled
with records that were
written to the stream
around the same time
as the expired records,
which means that they also
expire around the same time.
Which means that your Lambda
might not even have a chance to catch up.
The records will keep
expiring and expiring
and you will keep losing data.
So I often bring this
overflowing sink analogy.
When we pour water too quickly,
we can't drain it quick enough,
so the water just overflows.
That happens to our data.
So even though we started
with just one bad record,
we might have end up losing a lot of valid
and valuable data.
Once again, opposite
of what the resilience system should be.
And you might have guessed,
this is exactly what we saw in my story.
Just like with those
poorly configured timeouts
and retries earlier,
which are in the small localized problem,
one bad record into a full blown outage.
And in the process, we
ended up losing data,
added latencies, incurring duplicates,
incurring extra costs, spending resources,
and all of that were absolutely nothing,
leading absolutely nowhere.
And all of that because
we didn't know any better
and we just blindly went
with good old defaults.
And here again, the wonderful
quote by Gregor reminds us
to be very careful with the retries.
Luckily, there are many simple ways
to be more mindful about
failures with Lambda.
And first and foremost,
we need to configure those parameters
and those capabilities that
event source mapping comes with.
Now, we know by now that the
most important thing we can do
is to configure timeouts
and set limits for retries.
And you can actually do both of that
with event source mapping.
But both of them are set
to minus one by default,
which means no limits.
And this is precisely
what we saw in our story.
So make sure you configure those defaults.
And there are also a lot
of other very helpful,
very important settings.
I'm not gonna go through them today,
but knowing about them,
knowing how to use them
can be extremely helpful
and can save you a lot of
gray hair in the future.
And you can combine those
settings in any way that you want.
Use them in any combination that you want.
Just whatever you do, please
do not go with a default.
So we have seen today
that sometimes we can cause more problems
while trying to fix them.
And this is especially true
if we don't make conscious,
critical informed decisions
about handling failures.
And things like timeouts
and retries can be extremely powerful
if we put a thought into it.
But if we just let the matter slide,
they can turn against us
and can make our
architecture less resilient
instead of doing the opposite.
So next time you build a
distributed application,
I encourage you to be brave
to face the messy reality
of the real world,
to take control into your own hands
rather than believing in magic
because things are not magical,
and that's a good thing.
And distributed systems
and architectures are extremely powerful,
but they're also complex,
which doesn't make them neither
inherently good nor bad.
And the cloud, especially serverless
abstracts away a lot of
that complexity from us.
But that doesn't mean that
complexity is not there anymore,
which again, doesn't make
them neither good or bad.
And while we absolutely don't need to know
every single detail about
every single service,
that's pretty much impossible.
There are some fundamental things
that are inherent to the cloud
and distributed systems in general.
So things like service
limits, partial failures,
timeouts, retries, backoffs,
and those are all the fundamentals
that we absolutely need to understand.
Otherwise, we're just moving in the dark
with our eyes closed
and hoping that everything will be fine.
Now, on an even more philosophical note,
distributed systems and
architectures are hard,
but they can also teach
us a very valuable skill,
to embrace the chaos of the real world,
because each failure is an
opportunity to do things better,
to make our systems even more resilient.
And even though we can
never build something
that never fails despite our best effort,
there's one thing that we can do.
We can learn and grow from each failure.
And as that Dr. Werner
Vogels likes to remind us,
"Everything fails all the time."
That's just a reality of things.
So either in life in general
or with AWS services in particular,
I'd say that the best thing
that we can do is to keep calm
and be prepared when
those failures happen.
And that's it for me for today.
Thank you all so much for listening,
and I hope I will get
feedback from you very soon.
Thank you.
(audience applauds)