- Welcome to Dev 336 Kiro in action.
Let's talk about the problem
that we're trying to solve today.
That's the visibility gap.
When you're doing a red team engagement
or a pen testing assessment
for a large organization
with hundreds of AWS accounts,
you're gonna have hundreds
of thousands of resources
and you're gonna need to find the
vulnerabilities within those.
We're gonna show you how
to build a tool using
Kiro to do that.
Let's introduce ourselves.
I'm Nick Gilbert, the
red team manager at FICO.
I'm an AWS community
builder on the security
and identity team.
I'm also part of the AWS
Subject Matter Experts program
for the security specialty
exam and a Gen AI enthusiast.
- And what's going on
y'all, my name's Damien.
I am a senior cloud security
engineer at FICO during the day
and at night I'm the founder
of the Devsec Blueprint,
which is basically
to help people get into
DevSecOps Cloud security.
I'm an AWS community builder,
just like my buddy Nick over here.
I also produce a lot of content as well
as create courses on LinkedIn.
And then for fun, when I have the time,
whenever I have the time, I love anime,
I like cars, I play video games.
And those are just a
sumation of my hobbies.
But let's just quickly
discuss how we intend to close
that visibility gap.
And I'm gonna turn it back to Nick
so he can cover the IAM scanner
and the high level requirements.
- So we're gonna build a IAM
scan that does the following.
So first it's gonna identify
your high value attack fast.
It's gonna enumerate cross account access.
So you'll often start out in a dev account
and then wanna work your way
to those crown jewel assets
in the prod accounts.
It's gonna be able to
prioritize roles by impact.
It's gonna spot common
mistakes like wild cards
and trust policies, missing external IDs.
It'll give you specific
actionable escalation pass.
It'll provide repeatable results,
so once you report your findings,
the team will tell you
they fixed the issue
and then you can simply
run the scanner again
to confirm everything's fixed.
And then finally, we're gonna use Python
with multi-threading to
be able to scan hundreds
of accounts all at once.
- So the question that we
need to ask ourselves is
how can we solve our solution
quickly as security engineers?
So with the introduction of
AI into the industry, we know
for a fact that there are
two kinds of strategies
that we can use to be,
to make this happen.
So there's vibe coding and
there's also spec based design
or spec driven development.
And the question is, which one do we use?
So let's talk through vibe
coding, right, at a high level.
So Vibe coding essentially
is basically you
and the AI just vibe, right?
You open a chat, chatGPT,
(indistinct) code, AI,
whatever have you.
You throw some ideas at it,
you brainstorm, you refine it,
and you copy and paste the
code, you keep tweaking it
and you just keep doing
the same thing over
and over again until it actually works.
And it's great for proof of concepts,
but it is not what we need
for scalability, right?
It doesn't scale.
There's no way to understand,
there's no shared
understanding, no guarantees.
And there's definitely no
long-term maintainability
for all of that, right?
And for us in our approach,
that's not how we want
to basically build a
production scale security tool
or even guardrails for that matter
or any type of security automation, right?
But with spec based design and
or spec driven development,
it's quite different.
And when you look at it like this,
you're basically the
architect of your solution.
Before you even ask the AI to
write code, you basically have
to think about everything
from the beginning all the way
to the end, from the requirements,
have everything mapped out
and how you actually want
it to be implemented, right?
Which in a sense, is gonna help us build
that scalable maintainable
solution that updated by changes
to the spec itself.
And that's pretty much
where Kiro comes into the picture, right?
So Kiro is basically that AI powered IDE,
that basically is used to
enhance the software development
by using AI agents on the backend.
And one of the key features
of Kiro is that it supports
that spec based or spec driven development
and spec based design
that we talked about.
Not only that, but it's very
user friendly and easy to use.
If you're a developer and you
use VS code, it's very easy
because it's basically a clone of VS code.
And it also supports various different
programming languages.
So with Python being our
number one programming language
of choice and what it is
that we use to what we use
to build the IAM scanner.
So now I'm gonna turn it back
to Nick so he can talk about
how to create a spec using
the prompt framework.
- So to create your spec
files, good way to do
that is using the prompt framework.
So PROMPT is an acronym.
So the P stands for purpose.
So this is a brief description of
what you're trying to build.
Then you wanna give the requirements,
so a high level overview of your program.
Think of this like a job description.
Next is the output,
list how you wanna
receive the deliverables.
Do you want it in one single file
or do you want it
modular in several files?
Next up is the method.
This is gonna be the largest
section of the prompt.
So you wanna enumerate the very specific
details of your prompt.
And then a pro tip, this
is something I always like
to do when using Kiro is
at the end of the prompt,
I tell it to ask me clarifying
questions before it begins.
There's usually always something
important that I forgot.
And then finally testability.
So one great thing about
kiro is it can create
unit tests for you.
So anytime you make a change
to the software, simply run
the unit test to confirm
everything's working okay.
- All right, so when it comes
down to the IAM scanner,
the thing that we use
and that kiro expects
is three markdown files.
So we have the requirements,
which is basically
what we are wanting, right?
The design, which is what is needed,
and then also the task, which
is how we actually want this
to work, right?
So the step by step execution.
But the beautiful thing
about this is that as someone
who may not necessarily have
a lot of software development
or engineering experience,
you can essentially
create your own products
by just essentially creating
markdown files with a bunch
of texts, right?
And I think that's the
key thing with kiro is
that it puts you in a different part
or in a different spot of
the SDLC by allowing you to
be able to write the the specifications in
English instead of in code.
And next slide.
- So let's talk about how
the I Am scanner works.
So the first thing it's
gonna do is cache the
AWS managed policies.
There's over a thousand of 'em.
So when you're doing hundreds
of accounts, you don't want
to download 'em each time.
So it's gonna use a
caching system from that.
Next up is gonna collect the IAM data.
So this is your users, groups, roles
and customer managed policies.
Then it's gonna analyze all
those managed policies using a
policy engine, find out
which ones have high
level permissions.
Next is gonna check all the principles.
So both the managed policies
as well as the inline policies
and determine which
principles are dangerous.
Then it's gonna look at
the role trust policy.
So this is important for lateral
movement bulk (indistinct)
in the current account, as
well as cross account access.
Then it's gonna look at unused roles.
So a lot of times when
doing red team assessments,
the roles we end up using are unused ones
that were created a long time ago
with high privileges and never deleted.
And then it's gonna analyze
privilege escalation paths.
So this will go through every role,
determine if it has a
path to admin access,
and then tell you how you
get from where you're at
to admin access.
For example, it may say,
assume a certain role, then use
that role to create an EC2 instance
with the high privileged role.
We'll give you the code
for this at the end.
- All right, so now that you understand
how the IAM scanner works from
an architectural standpoint,
let's talk about the estimated
time it would take if we
attempted to do this without using AI
versus with using Kiro.
So if you take a look at
the table, you can see that
from planning and design to development,
you got touchpoint meetings, testing,
and also the rework rate.
You're looking at between 200 to 350 hours
for building out a tool
as sophisticated as that
with all those various different steps.
But with Kiro, you can see
that there's at least a 70%
reduction across the board
simply because we're
essentially passing in all the
parameters for it to be able
to build out everything with AI.
That includes unit test cases.
And the key thing is also that rework rate
because it's generating the
code and it's also going through
and testing the code as well
while it's generating it.
So you're thinking about maybe
25, 35 hours, if not a week,
for us to be able to build this tool.
So just so y'all know that
I'm not telling y'all no lie.
Let's talk about some of the results
so you can see everything
that actually happens, right?
So when you take a look
at this, this is step five
of the IAM scanner where it's
basically iterating through
and performing a role
analysis in my account.
So yes, this is my account
ID please do not steal it
or take it or do anything bad
because I'm going to
terminate the account anyway.
But ultimately you can see
that there are 40 unused roles,
and 21 of them are considered
to be dangerous, right?
And the beautiful thing about this is
that it generates two files.
It generates the JSON file,
which can be used for, you know,
some automation that you're writing,
and it also generates that
markdown report with all of
that information in those analysis points.
But the thing about this
is that with that report
that's being generated, if you need
to convince your leadership
to throw some extra money so
that you can have the additional
support to secure some
of those resources in the
cloud, you can export this
as a PDF and send it all on your way.
And basically, that'll
allow you to be able
to convince people
otherwise by basically giving
you an executive summary
of what's going on in
your account and why.
And all this, again, is maintained
by those markdown files.
So if we need to make a change to this,
we essentially update the
spec and have kiro go through
and update the code for us, right?
So some key takeaways.
Use spec driven design or
kiro to rapidly develop
and scale your security solutions.
Why?
Because you can essentially
pass in those requirements
via text to be able to make that happen.
Also, use spec files
to translate those product
requirements into a working code
and software without writing code.
Hence what I just said in
the first key takeaway.
And the last thing, if you
are a security engineer,
whether it's red team,
blue team, purple team,
whatever color you're on
the map, you wanna make sure
that you create automated tool
and to be able to find those
unlike entry points into your
cloud environment and any of
those hidden vulnerabilities
and risks so that you can
pretty much mitigate all
of those in an automated fashion.
So next steps, as we
approach the end, if you want
to check out the code,
please make sure you scan
the QR code at the very top
for the IAM scanners and
GitHub it is available for use.
And then also connect
with us on social media,
myself and also Nick.
Those are our QR codes
to our LinkedIn profiles.
Thank you guys so much for listening.