- [Erik] Hi, everyone.
Thanks for making it out this morning.
Hope you all had a good breakfast.
So we're going to be talking today
about Building AI Agents with
Kiro, MCP, and AgentCore.
So I just wanna see a show of
hands. Who has used AgentCore?
Okay, a few of you. Who has used Kiro?
Okay, a lot more.
And who has used like MCP servers?
Okay, that's probably the
most out of everyone here.
So this is a 300-level talk.
We have our laptop set up over here,
so we're gonna deep dive
into some code later.
But first, we're gonna
give a presentation.
And then I'm gonna leave
plenty of time at the end
for any of you to ask questions.
I have a microphone here
and we'll go around,
we'll run around and get
your questions answered.
I'm gonna start a few minutes early too,
just because this is a full house
and we have so much to get to.
You can see here is our agenda.
Kinda went over it a little bit already,
but we're gonna start
with what are AI agents.
Just a little refresher for some of you
who haven't seen this before.
Then we're gonna deep dive into AgentCore,
which I'm really excited about.
Didn't we see Matt Garman's talk
and mentioned some of the
new even more features
for AgentCore,
which I think is awesome that
we are continuously adding,
getting feedback from the community
and adding more things to AgentCore.
So we're gonna go talk about that,
and all the different pieces of it.
We're gonna look at
Kiro and how that works,
especially with AgentCore.
We're going to touch on MCP
and then we're gonna spend the rest
of the time looking at a demo.
And I'm gonna show you an example
of an architecture you
can use to build agents
and then how you can
use that with AgentCore.
Before I get too far though,
I just wanna introduce myself.
I'm Erik Hanchett, I'm a senior
developer advocate with AWS.
And Du'An.
- [Du'An] Yes. My name is Du'An Lightfoot.
I'm a developer advocate at
AWS focused on agentic AI.
- [Erik] Now, this talk
today is really meant
to show you how to create agents
with all these different tools on AWS.
So my goal is by the end of today,
that all of you can go back
and try these tools out,
and start building agents today.
So we're gonna go through some definitions
and how these tools all work together,
and they do really work together very well
to make it much simpler,
much more straightforward to build agents.
So let's start with some definitions.
I'm gonna hand it off to Du'An
who's going to deep dive into agents.
- [Du'An] Awesome. Thank you, Erik.
Hello, everyone.
So we're gonna talk
about what are AI agents?
How many of you are building agents today?
Oh, a couple people. All right.
That goes in line with the AgentCore talk.
So by the end of this, hopefully
you all are up to speed
to understand what agents
are, how to build an agent,
how to deploy it on AWS.
So there are many definitions
when it comes to what are agents,
but we're gonna start with level setting
from an AWS perspective.
Agents are an autonomous system
that leverages AI to reason,
plan, and take actions to achieve
goals on behalf of humans.
Now, when we think about that,
there are some key
things I wanna point out.
Reason, take actions, plan,
models are getting better.
So when you think about agent,
they are leveraging the reasoning
capabilities of a model.
The second thing is software systems.
Many of you may be developers,
architects, engineers,
and so when we start
talking building agents,
agents still need compute,
agents still need storage,
agents still need databases.
So all of the knowledge that
you have is still valuable
up until this point and beyond.
Now, there's been an evolution.
November, 2022, ChatGPT changed the world,
which is why this room is filled now
because all of us are
feeling the effects of AI.
Now,
I started my journey with
generative AI in January, 2023.
I was working at AWS
and I had this challenge
of a whole bunch of information I need
to stay up to date and stay current with.
So I said, you know what?
I'm gonna start summarizing the blogs
so I can stay current and
more efficient in my role.
Well, at that time,
context windows were
about 8,192 tokens, right?
So you couldn't fit a whole blog
into a chat bot or ChatGPT.
So what I decided to do
was chunk that information,
summarize each chunk, and
then concatenate the chunks,
and then summarize that to
have one concise summary
of the blog, right?
That was before RAG.
Come to summer, everyone's
talking about RAG.
Come the end of 2024,
now, LLMs have tool calling
and function calling, right?
And now, people start
talking about agents, 2024.
Now, we have agentic frameworks
that makes building
agents a lot more simpler.
Now, we can have it maintain
memory, that context,
which we'll talk about here in a moment.
And we can build agents
a lot more efficiently.
We're even at the point
now where we're talking
about being building
multi-agent systems, right?
And fully autonomous
agents. Is that possible?
Yes, they're being implemented today.
So taking a step back,
since all of us aren't building
agents, what's an agent?
Well, you see that agent,
that's code, right?
At the center of it is
the intelligence, the LLM.
And then from there, you
give that LLM access to APIs,
tools, to better look up the
weather, look up the date,
retrieve information from a database,
and then you give better access to memory,
short term and long term.
You need to maintain the
conversations and the state, right?
Of each session.
And then from there,
you need to be able to retrieve
things like historical facts
over those conversations
throughout the sessions.
And this is what makes
up for agents, right?
But again, this goes
back to software, right?
How many of you are developers
or write code, right?
All that knowledge that
you have is still important
when you're building agents today.
So how do we take the agents
that we're building and deploy them?
Well, there's some challenges around that.
First, how do you deploy
an agent securely, right?
In his own isolated runtime.
How do you maintain context
memory, short term, long term?
How do you identify who
can access the agent
as well as what the agent can access?
You know that machine to
machine communication.
And then from there,
you need to manage the
tools that it can use,
have some policies and
controls around that,
be able to discover those tools,
and then observe the whole entire system.
Observability.
We call these challenges
undifferentiated heavy lifting
at AWS.
And so to solve this,
we introduce AgentCore.
And I'm gonna go through AgentCore,
then we're gonna hop in some code.
But at a high level,
let's take a look at that.
So you have runtime.
When you build your agents,
you can use any framework,
whether you're using LangGraph, LangChain,
Strands Agents, client agents, SDK,
whatever framework you're using,
whatever model you are using,
you can take that agent,
launch it in the runtime.
The thing about runtime,
it also supports MCP.
So if you're building
your own MCP servers,
you can launch those
in the runtime as well.
Runtime supports workloads
up to eight hours, right?
Of course you can build an
agent and launch it in the EC2,
but then that's always running, right?
So this is serverless.
So now the agent is only
running when it's needed.
When it comes to runtime, your
agent needs access to memory.
So we have memory for that
short term and long term.
Identity. Who can access the agent?
What the agent can access. Gateways.
If you have existing APIs,
whether they're OpenAPI schema or Smithy,
or you have Lambda functions,
you can use Gateway to
create MCPs for those tools.
And then you can wrap a policy
which was announced here
at re:Invent around those tools
and what those tools can actually do.
So now you can put some more guardrails
and controls around your agents.
So they can't just explore the world
and do whatever they want to do, right?
We have browser to be
able to search the web.
Code interpreter to have this
secure isolated environment
to offload code execution, right?
You may have some compute
intensive workloads
and rather than having the resources taken
up inside of your agent's runtime,
you can offload that to code interpreter.
And then from there, you
have full observability
with gen AI observability
inside a CloudWatch.
But this also exports to (indistinct).
So if you're using something
like Lane Fuel or Datadog,
you can export that there.
And then finally, we have evaluations.
One of the things about building an agent,
when you build your agent,
start with a use case.
Start small, right?
After you have the use case,
you're building your agent.
Next thing you need to do,
build observability in from the beginning.
So that way, you can measure
things like metrics, latency,
tool use, tool cost, cost,
all these things from the beginning
because the larger your agent gets,
the harder that becomes, right?
And then evaluations,
how well is your tool,
your agent performing?
That's just some things I wanted to cover
before we hop into the code.
Kind of going through,
I'm gonna go real fast so
we can hop into the code.
AgentCore runtime, I
mentioned this already,
supports any model,
supports any framework.
There's two ways to deploy
either a Docket container,
we can use the AgentCore
starter kit, few lines of code,
get your agent into the runtime,
or you can use the zip file.
So if many of you are using Lambda,
pretty much kind of the same approach.
For AgentCore memory,
I mentioned it supports
short-term and long-term memory.
So the short-term memory is
for those chat messages, right?
In the user state.
Now, the thing about this,
the cool thing about AgentCore memory
is that once you have your
memory in the short-term memory,
now we automatically extract information.
You can create something
called a strategy,
whether it's semantic search,
user preferences, summary,
or some type of custom strategy, right?
I have an example where I wanted the agent
to remember the blogs that I searched.
So I created a custom
strategy around that.
So now, when the agent stores
those short-term memories,
it's able to extract using
the automated extraction,
the information is stored
in long-term memory.
So now across sessions,
when I talk to the agent
or you invoke the agent,
it can retrieve that information
and bring it into context
and perform the task more efficiently.
Next, when we come to Gateway,
I broke this down already,
but what this does is allow you
to have an authenticated
connection to your MCP servers.
So if we look at this, if you
are using existing APIs now,
I mentioned OpenAPI as well as Smithy,
you can integrate those
directly with AgentCore Gateway.
Then Lambda functions.
If you have those, you wanna
expose those as MCP servers,
you can put those behind a Gateway,
and then they can be
exposed as MCP servers.
Now, off, with identity,
now, you can have identity
for outbound connections.
Let's say you need to use
a third-party provider
to access some API or JWT tokens,
you can use that with Gateway
and connect to those third-party
APIs right through Gateway.
Taking it one step further, I know,
I've seen a lot of hands go out with MCP,
and I am a fan of MCP,
but there's some challenges
with that, right?
When you are leveraging MCP servers,
you are essentially giving
a whole bunch of information
and tokens to your agents,
which can one, make it slower,
confuse it, and be
extremely expensive, right?
So to cut down on that,
AgentCore Gateway offers
something called semantic search.
So rather than just giving all
of your tools to the agent,
you can use semantic search,
and now your agent only gets
access to the tools it needs
when it needs it, right?
So this is a way to save
on speed, save on costs,
as well as optimize on performance.
Finally, something we'll cover at the end
after Erik goes to the code.
But we're gonna talk about observability.
Observability is important.
I mentioned after you have your use case,
the first thing you should think about,
or the next thing you should think about,
is gonna be observability,
monitoring the sessions,
the metrics, the latency, the token use.
All of this needs to
happen from the beginning
so you can really understand
how your agent is performing
and be able to evaluate and
optimize continuously, right?
So that completes my
portion of the session.
I'm gonna give it over to Erik
and he'll take it from there.
- [Erik] Thanks, Du'An.
- [Du'An] Yeah.
- [Erik] Yeah, let's talk
a little bit about Kiro
and how this can help us today.
So Kiro is our new agentic IDE.
We released it into
preview a few months ago
and it just went into general
availability a few weeks ago.
I'm really excited. This journey
on Kiro has been amazing.
When we launched it into preview
three or four months ago,
the amount of downloads
and the amount of people just loving it
and giving us feedback was amazing.
We had hundreds of thousands of downloads
in the first few days and
we had to put up a wait list
and then people found a
way around the wait list
and then we had to have another wait list.
But right now, it's
definitely generally available
and then we can try it out.
And it's a really great
way to build your agents
'cause it has a lot of
features that make it simpler
to build not just agents,
but practically anything.
We didn't make this AWS
Kiro or Amazon Bedrock Kiro,
this is just Kiro.
So we really wanted to
separate it from the AWS brand
in some ways and just make
sure that anyone can use it.
You can even use social login,
don't need an AWS account,
but I think it really pairs well
with what we're showing off today.
That also, that little
ghost there that's bouncing
up and down, that's kind of
the mascot that we went with.
So why would you want to use this
versus any other of our
agentic IDEs out there?
Is we really built
in the spec-driven development part of it.
So as I was building the
demo for all of you today
that I'll be showing off in a little bit,
I used both of these modes,
vibe mode and spec mode.
Spec mode, if you don't know,
is a way that you can create your,
you basically tell the large
language model the requirements
that you want and it helps
build a requirements document,
a design document and a task list from it.
And it's a way you can go
back and forth with your IDE
to make sure it builds
exactly what you want.
And we found that it's much more accurate
and it's much quicker.
It saves you time when you
build it using spec mode,
although vibe mode works great as well.
Du'An, how would you describe difference
between vibe and spec?
- [Du'An] So when it
comes to vibe and spec,
think of spec as you being an architect
creating a high level validated design
that the agent will
follow to complete a goal.
When it comes to vibe coding,
you just want it to go
through, figure out what
the problem is and solve it.
You don't really need to
have specs around that,
just do what I asked you to do, right?
That's the way I kind
of approached the two.
- [Erik] Well said.
You can also just jump
into features in depth
with spec mode,
we will take a look at what
that looks like in a moment.
Going back and I saw most
people raise their hands
about MCP.
We have a Kiro, since it's an agentic IDE,
it does allow you to add in an MCP server.
And this works with local or remote MCP.
And in fact today, we
just launched Kiro powers,
which is a way to add in
not just an MCP server,
but steering files and more context.
So I'd highly recommend
everyone check that out.
If you're interested in Kiro,
Kiro powers is out today.
And we had launched with
a bunch of partners,
and one partner we
launched with is AgentCore.
So you can actually go
to one of a kiro.dev,
there'll be an AgentCore Kiro
power, you can click on it,
you have to have the
latest version of our IDE,
and it'll install it,
and it makes working
with agents even easier.
I will in the demo, I
will show you quickly,
we will move to that website
just to take a look at it.
I said it just came out today.
I'm not going to go through it,
but I'll show you guys what
it looks like if you want
to use it today while
you're building agents.
We are going to be using,
however, the AgentCore MCP server.
I don't know if you know that AWS has lots
of different MCP servers
for all different scenarios.
We have a general
documentation MCP server,
but we have one specifically
for AgentCore just
to make your LLM a little
bit smarter to grab
and to create agents.
Of course that works with not just Kiro,
but any cursor, Windsurf,
whatever else you're using.
Alright, so let's get started.
Before I jump into the code,
I just wanna give a high
level diagram architecture
of what we're building today.
Kind of encompassing this
whole diagram is observability.
So we are going to look
at that with Du'An's help.
We're gonna have a front end
and that front end is going
to connect to our food tracker agent.
And this is, so we kind of built,
I built this multi-layered
just to emphasize
that you could have agents
talk to other agents.
In this case, we have our recipe agent,
which is also an MCP server.
That's that middle box there
and that's more of our orchestrator.
It's gonna talk to two MCP servers.
One is the recipe server, MCP.
The recipe server talks
to a list of recipes.
I'll show you what that looks
like. It can retrieve them.
It has a number of tools.
I also have nutrition ingredients.
So that has a list of ingredients
and that's using our Gateway
using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway.
I know it's a mouthful.
I'm not using any semantic
search like Du'An just mentioned,
but I could have certainly
added that in there.
I only have a few tools
in our nutrition ingredients MCP server.
But you could imagine to
reiterate what Du'An was saying,
if you have like hundreds
of tools in your MCP server,
those get added in and take up tokens
and your agent or your LLM
will have to process those.
And so it is a little bit of
a problem with MCP servers,
and semantics certainly helps fix that.
Here is another diagram.
I know this is a lot of boxes
and it's kind of probably hard to see,
but let me explain what we're doing here.
We're going from the user,
which is you at the keyboard.
You're gonna be talking to
a front end, in this case,
I'm a big React and Vue.js fan.
Any Vue or React fans here?
Any front-end devs? Okay, a few.
Then that's gonna talk directly
to our food tracker agent,
and that food tracker agent,
it's really meant to be the gateway
to talk to the front-end.
So it talks in a very friendly
natural way to the front end.
And then it talks directly
to the recipe agent server,
which really takes, it's an agent,
but it just kind of
formats what it receives
from the MCP service in a certain way.
So you can think of the recipe agent
as more of an orchestrator.
And then of course we have Amazon Bedrock,
we are using some Anthropic
models and Nova models.
And then the last box there,
it says recipe server MCP,
Gateway MCP.
Those are two actual servers,
but I didn't have enough
space on the diagram
to make it more longer than it is.
And you can see a little
bit with these arrows kind
of going back and forth
of how the flow is.
So before we get to that,
let's jump into the demo.
- [Du'An] Wow, Erik is setting up.
Do we have any questions
about anything we presented?
Any questions? No questions?
We do have one. Okay, I'll take two.
I'll get her, then I'll get you.
If y'all can pass that
down, please. Thank you.
- [Attendee] So I have been using Q CLI.
- [Du'An] Yes.
- [Attendee] In the VS Code extension.
So what is the difference
between now you have renamed
the two Kiro CLI, right?
So what is the difference
between the Kiro IDE
and this extension?
Are there any added advantages
like using the separate IDE?
- [Erik] Yeah, that's a good question.
So you're asking if there's
differences between using Kiro,
the IDE, and maybe used Q
IDE in the past or Q CLI?
- [Attendee] Q CLI in VS Code.
- [Erik] Yes, Q CLI. So Q
CLI, we changed the name.
If you do an update on Q
CLI, it becomes Kiro CLI.
So that's kinda the biggest thing.
Although if you do not want to change,
you can continue to use Q CLI
and turn off your automatic updates.
Q isn't going away, but we
really are focusing on Kiro,
the IDE, Kiro CLI,
we see a lot of advantages
with the two together.
If you may have noticed two
transform has now been kind
of pushed into its own service.
So if you are using that with Q,
you can now use it without Q as well.
- [Attendee] Thank you.
- [Du'An] And we could talk offline.
A lot of you may use like cloud code,
some of you may use
cursor, some may use Kiro.
I think there's two
different like workflows
like one operating in the terminal,
one operating in the IDE.
I think it's a preference at that point.
But there's also, I find
developers like the IDE,
but then people that are like,
in operations prefer like,
the terminal 'cause it's right there.
So if you all wanna talk more about that,
I love those type of conversations.
We can talk after.
- [Attendee] How do we
set up like a long-term
and short-term memory in AgentCore,
like, can we define what is
long-term and what is short-term
and if we are setting
up long-term variables,
like, do they use more tokens?
Does the agent use more
tokens to retrieve those?
- [Du'An] So there's a
couple ways to do that.
So when it comes to setting up your agent,
you can just set up
short-term memory, right?
Or you can have long-term memory.
But let's say you're using the starter kit
when you launch it,
you can tell it then to
do the short-term memory,
and then it'll automatically
do the long-term memory, right?
But you can configure the long-term memory
to have different strategies.
So that's the most important thing,
is the strategies that you want.
Do you care about just the
summary of the conversation?
Do you care about user preferences?
Do you care about facts
from the conversation?
And so those are the
strategies you will set
up for the long-term memory.
And you can do that through photo three.
You can set up the strategies
and the memory with CDK,
that's how you can set it up.
But if you want actual
code, I can get you code.
- [Attendee] Yeah, that would be great.
- [Du'An] Alright, awesome.
Thank you for your questions.
But here, Erik.
- [Erik] Awesome, thank
you. Great questions.
We'll have more time to
answer more at the end.
I want to give you guys plenty of time.
So I have Kiro open here.
So let me give you a quick tour
of Kiro and how this works,
'cause I saw not as many
hands in the Kiro side.
So this is the IDE, it's
based off of VS Code.
So those who know and love VS Code,
it'll be right at home here.
On the left-hand side, we
have this little ghost icon
and this is where we can do
very Kiro things inside here.
So we can add in agent hooks.
So these are ways that
you can have agents run
in the Kiro IDE on certain actions.
For example, maybe you save a file
that it updates your documentation.
We even have a little
example of doing that.
Or maybe you want it to
do some localization,
and you can also have it on delete,
and a few other actions as well.
Then we have our steering files.
These are like rules files in other IDEs.
So you can set exactly what you,
these will be added to the context
and then you can tell it if
you're using AgentCore, do X, Y,
Z, in case, I actually created
an AgentCore steering file.
So this is, what I did is I told Kiro,
and someone mentioned Kiro CLI.
We can use even Kiro CLI to create a file
with the best practices
of using AgentCore.
So I have an AgentCore
Gateway CDK best practice file
that I used, I created with Kiro,
and then added it into the context
so that way, anytime we're
doing stuff with CDK,
it looks at that file.
And then what you can do
in any kind of new project,
when you open it up in Kiro,
you can tell it to generate
the Kiro steering files,
kinda looks like this.
You can either do it through the menu,
generate project steering files or those,
if you are in a brand new
project, there's a button here.
And so I did that with this project
and this kinda just tells it exactly
what's already existing.
So you have an existing project,
you can create the steering files
and then they'll be added
into the context every time you use it.
I hinted at this, I can't
get into this too much.
This probably could take the whole hour.
But here's the specter
of development flow.
It creates a requirements document
in this what we call EARS format.
And it has the introduction,
glossary, requirements,
and it has acceptance criteria.
And if I would like, I could
go through each one of these
to the design, to the task list,
and have Kiro actually
build my app for me.
In this case, I used it a little bit,
and then I went back to vibe coding.
So I kind of went back and forth.
And then finally, this is MCP,
I have four MCP servers running here.
I like Context7.
Quick tip, if you are just
trying to use MCP servers
for the first time, this is a great one,
because it has hundreds
of different docs in it
and it'll look at those docs
before it gets information for you.
There's also an AWS
documentation MCP server.
This is kind of the overall
one that a lot of people use
'cause it's kind of the biggest one.
It has all our docs in it,
and it includes some GitHub repositories.
This is the one I recommend
for everyone to use.
If you're building with
AgentCore, like I said,
you don't have to use Kiro with this,
but just these are MCP servers.
Use the Bedrock AgentCore MCP server.
That way, you can kind of
go back and forth with it
as you're building your apps.
And then use Brave Search, that way,
you can like search the web easier.
Do you have anything
to add Du'An on those?
- [Du'An] Yeah, something
I wanna call out.
How many of you use a coding assistant,
coding agent like Kiro?
Okay.
So what he's showing you,
this Kiro tool is agentic.
And so by adding it, the MCP servers,
you give it access to
additional information.
So while he's writing code for
AWS to build his application,
the agent can write the code.
But now, rather than it
making up an abstraction
or the wrong way to implement
a function or a class,
now, it can use the MCP service
to pull in the proper
way to write the code.
Does that make sense? Alright.
And so Kiro is a great tool for that.
Now, he has a whole bunch of MCP servers.
One thing I do wanna call out,
is when you're building your own agents,
you don't want to give
it that many MCP servers.
You know, I like to build
specialized agents, like,
give it the tools that it needs
so it can complete the task.
And as it needs to complete more tasks,
then you give it those
tools that it needs.
Because again,
the more tools and MCP servers
and tokens that are used,
the more expensive and the
longer it takes to process
or generate a response.
Go ahead.
- [Erik] Good point, good point.
Yeah, definitely,
this is a little bit more
of an advanced example.
Here is also that vibe and spec coding
that I was talking about
where you can just talk
to the chat.
You can also, it's multimodal,
you can put in pictures,
all sorts of great information in there.
I'm just gonna close this
little window here on the side
so we can start looking at the code.
Sounds like we have a
lot of developers here,
I'm sure you guys wanna take a look.
So here, I have it broken
down inside Kiro here
between my back end and front end.
This is the view app here.
And then I have infra and
we'll look at that in a second.
I'm using CDK.
I think the best thing
to do is we can start
with the recipe server.
So let's take a look at
that. I'm using Python.
I'd recommend if you're
using AgentCore right now
to use Python.
I think it's the most simplest
to use. This is very simple.
So we're using FastMCP, this
is a pretty popular MCP library
that you can use on Python.
And then I'm setting up tools,
and tools are kind of the
bread and butter of MCP.
I mean, there's other
things like elicitation
and a whole bunch of other things
and we'll take a look at that.
But this is kinda the way you do it.
What I'm doing here is
to keep this simple,
I have a JSON file with
a bunch of recipes in it
and each recipe has ingredients,
of course instructions,
how many calories it has.
And then I'm exposing
through the recipe server
some nice tools to grab that information.
You can imagine if this
was in a production,
that JSON file might be
in RDS or somewhere else,
an S3 bucket or, however,
though just for the simple example,
it's just hard coded on the file,
and in an AgentCore when it's deployed,
it's actually in the container.
So here it is.
I have recipes by difficulty,
get quick recipes.
One thing I like to do when
I'm working with agents
is I would like to use the Model
Context Protocol inspector.
So I'm gonna go to my recipe server,
and I'm a big fan of UV
so we're gonna use UV.
And I'm going to use run recipe.
And so now it created a new MCP server
so I can test this locally and port 8,000.
And I'm just gonna go back
up to my command here.
This is an NPX command
to run the inspector.
This is an open source tool
that the MCP foundation has
given us to test MCP servers.
So here it is. This is what it looks like.
I'm using 17.2, I'm using Streamable HTTP,
which is, 'cause it is
running on a server locally.
I'm gonna click connect,
and here's all the
different ways you can work
with an MCP server.
You have resources, prompts, tools, ping,
obviously we're gonna use tools.
And here's the ones that we
just saw on that in file,
the get recipes by type,
get recipes by cuisine.
Let's try it.
Let's try, in this case,
we're gonna say pasta.
So it's gonna get all the pasta recipes
and output it into this
schema that I defined.
So really quick, here it
is, classic spaghetti,
carbonara, beef stroganoff.
So here is the list.
So definitely working.
I always liked when I'm working
with agents and MCP servers,
I always like to test locally first
to make sure it's working.
This is a great tool to do that.
Okay, so now we see what the server is,
that remember in that previous slide,
it was those two MCP servers.
This is the one that's
run by runtime AgentCore.
So in control, see it.
- [Du'An] Erik?
- [Erik] Yep.
- [Du'An] I know a lot of you
all are using MCP servers.
How many are building MCP servers?
Okay, so do you understand,
let's take a step back.
When it comes to what Erik is showing you,
he's showing you how to
build an MCP server, right?
That tool decorator that
goes over the Python function
that lists the agent or the
LLM node that this is a tool
from the MCP server, right?
The type, listen, know the parameters,
that should be passed in.
And then the doc string is
actually what goes to an agent.
So when we talk about, or the LLM,
so when we talk about
increasing the amount of tokens,
all of this is created in a
JSON Schema that goes to LLM.
So in order for an agent to
know how to use that tool,
you need a clearly defined dock stream
inside of your function.
And oftentimes if you just
install an MCP server,
sometimes they load a
whole bunch of information
and it could be a whole lot of tools,
and all of those tokens are processed
every time you invoke the LLM, right?
He did it really efficient and strength.
And this is a kind of
simplified version of an agent.
So it's easy for the agent to understand,
but the more tools you have,
the more information you'll
need in that doc stream.
And so what he showed you is
how to build the MCP server
and then use the inspector
to test it out locally
before you actually deploy it.
- [Erik] Let me show you the
Lambda Gateway real quick.
So this is a normal
Lambda function that was,
I have a handler, I have events coming in.
Imagine this, you just
deployed this to Lambda,
and now you wanna make
this into an MCP server.
So it looks for food and a JSON object
and also serving size.
And so this returns a list of ingredients
and then I just have a quick lookup.
I also have another JSON file here,
this nutrition JSON file.
And this is, and I have
a few commented out code.
You could sell this as a demo.
And then it just returns
a JSON object back.
So this one, this is really
nice that Du'An was talking
about before, if we have existing infra,
and we want to convert it
over to MCP, we can do it.
And you're probably
thinking, is this just magic?
We just like, point it to this
and it kind of just turns it.
Well no, there is another
step you have to do.
In my infra, I have a lib folder,
and then I have an infra stack.
And inside here,
is where I defined my
AgentCore Gateway right here,
this Food Tracker Gateway.
I have to obviously put the
name, there's some auth,
we'll talk about that in a second.
And then right down
here, I define a schema.
And this schema tells basically AgentCore
how this Lambda function is.
And this is saying by the way,
we have a properties for
food and serving size.
Those are the two events
that go into that Lambda
and we just define it as a string.
This is a number, this is an object.
So that way, it knows how
to work with the MCP server.
It basically creates it using this way.
I was gonna ask Du'An, I
haven't mentioned this,
but everything that's
deployed to AgentCore runtime
is backed by IM or you can have it backed
by like Cognito using OAuth 2.
Do you have anything
to add to that, Du'An?
- [Du'An] Yeah, so the runtime that,
it's a public service, right?
So if you're trying to connect
to it, you can use Cognito,
extract the JWT token and
connect to the runtime, right?
You also can use third-party
providers with like OAuth.
You can set that up through identity
so that access inbound to the agent,
but then outbound as well
from like the Gateway,
if the Gateway needs to
access third-party APIs,
you can use AgentCore identity to set all
that up to provide the agent
with all the authentication
and needs to be able to
connect to those tools.
- [Erik] And we do have an L2 construct
with AgentCore Gateway for
you CDK fans out there.
And of course, all our libraries,
you can easily connect to AgentCore.
I wanted to show you the recipe agent now.
So this is the orchestration
tool that talks-
- [Du'An] We got a question, Erik.
- [Erik] Oh, sure.
- [Attendee] Just a small one, right?
Like, so in case we are
exposing Lambda function
via Gateway, what is the tool name?
Like, what tools do it
expose? How do I know?
- [Du'An] Oh, that's what you
listed before in the schema.
- [Erik] Yeah, this schema
here describes the tool name
and the tool definition,
the properties of each one,
and it automatically
creates a set of tools,
and I'll show you what that
looks like based on this.
And you can even be more
granular than I did here.
- [Attendee] Okay, got it.
- [Du'An] Yep. Any other
questions before we move on?
- [Erik] So this recipe agent, oh sorry.
- [Du'An] Okay.
- [Erik] All right, so yeah,
this recipe agent is going
to talk to those two MCP servers.
I have a number of tools
in here that do things.
So this is MCP server and agent together
so it's gonna take a
little bit longer to run,
but I have things for,
I have this system prompt
that it's a nutritional coach,
it's gonna filter these
different tools out.
I have different system prompts
depending on which tool you talk to.
I think the best way to
show this is just to run it,
and let's take a look at it,
instead of you guys looking at the code.
So we're gonna do, I'm
in the recipe agent,
I'm gonna UV run the recipe agent.
And since this is also an MCP tool,
it should give us port 8,000,
which means I can run my inspector again,
take a look at it and I'll connect to it.
And this time, if I go
to tools and list tools,
you can see I have lookup
ingredient nutrition,
analyze recipe nutrition,
create weekly meal prep.
So this is all the tools that
are exposed, these four tools,
it's basically taking
all the tools that came
from those two MCP servers
and it's distilling it
down to these like four higher
level ones that you can do.
So I can look up ingredient nutrition,
let's try that, pancetta,
serving size, run tool.
And this is gonna take
a little bit longer,
but if I look here,
I'm running it locally,
you could see it's calling
the Bedrock Gateway AgentCore
that we just created.
I actually have this
deployed on AgentCore,
not just running locally.
It found two tools, this X AW,
Amazon Bedrock AgentCore
search, nutrition lookup,
get nutrition info.
And now, it's invoking the agent
and getting that information back.
So it determined that I needed
to use the nutrition lookup,
get nutrition info tool.
That's what we saw in
that previous MCP server.
It looks like it retrieved it.
So now it's using its
model to kinda update it
and format it for us to display.
Lemme see if it's done.
It's still running.
It's taking a little
extra second here to run.
So let's take a look at the
tool call while it's running.
If I go back to the
recipe or the nutrition,
and we look back at the
nutrition Python file,
this is the different cool tool calls.
Well, we have find nutrition
info, find similar food.
So the one it called was,
here it is, it finished,
was nutrition lookup.
Oops.
So this one right here,
nutrition lookup function.
So it's basically using this
with these tools in the,
well, basically this is a Lambda function.
It was able to convert them into tools,
and it ran this nutrition lookup
based on that schema we saw.
So let's see if we come back
over here. Here it is, success.
So here's pancetta,
and now it kinda gave me a
detailed information about it.
Pancetta is a cured
Italian meat product made
from pork belly.
Great.
- [Du'An] Now, this did
take a little while, right?
We're building an agent,
it's not a chatbot.
You know, agents when they run,
are designed to take a little longer.
Like, if you use OpenAI, ChatGPT,
and you do deep research,
that could take up to 15,
20 minutes, and it runs
like in the background,
and notifies you when you're done.
So when you think about AgentCore runtime,
it's designed to support
workloads up to eight hours.
So if you're building
a deep research agent,
this is the type of platform
you would deploy it to.
So that way when you need
something like deep research
or some deep analysis or some
agentic function to occur,
runtime can handle
that, complete the task,
and then that session is
done, it's ephemeral, right?
- [Erik] Let's take a
look at the food tracker.
This is the agent on
top of everything else.
It calls the recipe agent that
calls those two MCP servers.
It's called NutriTracker.
So it's a friendly nutrition
and meal plan assistant.
This is the system
prompt that I passed in.
It's using Anthropic, I think
3.7, I think, right here.
Anthropic 3.7.
It's also using a few other tools.
It's using our Strands Agent,
which is an open source
tool that AWS released
to help create agents.
Like, Du'An said earlier, you
don't have to use Strands,
it works with pretty much
every other agent framework.
I'm also using the
Bedrock AgentCore library
to put this all together.
All those other ones were MCP servers.
This is gonna be the main entry point
and I'm instantiating
it here with this app,
with this Bedrock AgentCore app.
And then I have some
environmental variables,
some definitions of
where to find everything.
And if I scroll all the way to the bottom,
it's essentially connecting to everything.
It has to use this machine to
machine client authentication
because we're talking to
the, it's already deployed,
it needs to talk to the
recipe agent, MCP server.
I think the best way to
show you this is just
to jump into the demo on
the front end at this time.
So I can't get to the front
end from the back end.
Let's go to the front end,
and I'm just gonna run dev on this.
So I'm running a port 5173.
Okay, so here's the Health
Agent with Authentication.
One thing I wanna show real quick
is that we actually are using memory.
I think someone asked a
memory question earlier.
So this is using short-term memory.
It looks like this, this
is how you set it up.
This agent memory core config is part
of our Strands Agents' library.
We're telling it this retrieval.
Do you wanna talk about
this for a second, Du'An?
- [Du'An] Yes.
So this is the AgentCore
memory configuration.
And so if you see where
it says retrieval config,
that's where we're extracting
from the long-term memory,
right?
The short-term memory
is going to retrieve all the conversation,
the session information, right?
The user assistant messages
along with tool calls
and the state.
That's short-term memory.
But if we want to extract
the user preferences or facts
about the conversations and interactions,
that's what we're actually
using the semantic search
to extract from that long-term memory.
And you can see that listed here.
That's the actual implementation
of the memory abstraction config.
And so we set up the memory config,
and then we pass that into the agent.
So if you look at the session manager,
we pass that into the
session manager of the agent.
So now, when the agent has conversations
during that event loop,
if you know Strands,
Strands Agents uses something
called the event loop.
Normally when you build a chatbot
or some type of integration with an agent,
you have a user message, system message,
assistant response tool,
tool calls, tool results,
all of that needs to be managed
when you write that code.
The Strands Agent actually handles
that through the event loop, right?
And so in there with that
conversation management
or that session management is being stored
in the session manager.
Something we don't show here
is that context can get very large.
And so we handle the
conversation automatically
with a conversation manager.
There's two approaches.
There's a summarization and
then there's a sliding window.
Sliding window is the default.
So after 20 messages,
the older messages in the
conversation will be removed.
We got questions.
- [Erik] I like how
this all works together
with the Strands Agents pretty well.
- [Du'An] Yes. Okay.
- [Erik] I'm logged in here
to my Health Agent app.
I'm just gonna say hello.
And what I like to do is
also up on my inspect,
and then I go to the network
tab just to see it working.
It's a little slow just
basing on the network
that we're on and the models
we're using just for our demo.
But here it is.
Hello, Erik.
I'm still here and ready to
help you with your nutrition
or meal planning questions you might have.
I actually gave it my name
before we started this demo today.
But I wanna show you
just that AgentCore memory
working real quickly
before we have it kind
of do some other things.
So I'm gonna sign out here.
I built this using,
this is a Cognito login.
This is something called
the Authenticator.
It's just a real quick
boilerplate I added to it
to add in a way to log in.
And so now I'm logged in here,
and I'll say hello, my name is Erik.
And so now this is a new session
basically with a new user.
So it should talk back to me
as if it was the first time
I was logged in with a different user,
the first time when I just said hello.
And I could see it's
running the invocation here,
and I can even take a look at the stream.
So hello, Erik, it's nice to meet you.
How can I help you with your nutrition
or meal planning today?
So if I log out and I log back in,
and I say, what is my name?
It should remember that I said it was Erik
from this new session that I created here.
And then it'll retrieve
from that short-term memory
what it saw and then bring it back here.
And it looks like it's
running this invocation here.
I always like to kind
of play around with it
and look at it to see what it's doing.
The response, you can even see-
(attendees chattering)
- [Attendee] Short-term or
would it be from long-term?
- [Du'An] From long-term.
It'll be from long term
'cause you signed out,
signed back in.
When you sign out, that ends that session.
When you sign back in, it's a new session.
So the user preferences will get stored
to the long-term memory.
So it should remember his name
and bring that back into the conversation.
A key thing to call out here
and Erik can show you
is that we designed it
so the system prompt knows that
whenever the user addresses
or has some type of
personalized interaction,
that it should address you by name.
So that way, you'll see,
and have this personalized user
experience in your app, so.
- [Attendee] Was that the LLM
that decided (indistinct)
in the long-term there?
- [Du'An] Yes, so that's all
the LLM, but the retrieval,
you saw the memory config,
that's actually extracting automatically
from the long-term memory
and appended it to the prompt
so that way when the
prompt goes into the LLM,
it has the information
it needs to know, okay,
the related information
related to the name,
let me retrieve that,
append it to the prompt,
and then invoke the model.
No problem. I got one back here.
- [Erik] While you're
answering questions, Du'An,
I asked it, can you create
meal prep plan for a week
for 1500 calories or under?
So now, it's going to use these agents
that are connected to it.
It's gonna go back and forth,
run that loop a few times,
and return back and answer for me.
- [Du'An] Oh, we got one question.
- [Attendee] I have a question here.
So basically this agent memory,
whatever system parameters
that are in the,
like, is there some set
of system parameters
that it knows to store itself
and some kind of customizable parameters
or it's just basically
all up to how you code it?
- [Du'An] Erik, you mind going back
to the memory slide real quick?
- [Erik] The memory
slide or the memory code?
- [Du'An] The memory slide.
- [Erik] Okay.
- [Du'An] Yes. Is that possible?
- [Erik] Yeah, gimme a
sec while that's working.
- [Du'An] So we'll go
back to the memory slide
and I'll show you here what it looks like.
- [Erik] Let's see here. Let's
see all the way back here.
This is observability, Gateway.
- [Du'An] I think it's before
this one. Alright, so here.
All right, so when we actually create,
you have to create a
long-term memory strategy.
And so if you look,
the short-term memory is
the chat conversations,
chat messages, the user
assistant messages,
and the session state.
That's short-term that can
last up to 30 days per session,
right?
The long-term memory, you have
to create these strategies.
So you can have a semantic
where you extracting semantic search
from the actual conversation
of the search on memory,
the user preferences where
things like your name,
your birthdate, is
actually being extracted,
the summary, episodic.
And then you can create
custom strategies as well.
So you create these with CDK or something,
you deploy it inside of memory,
and then from there, you have
the retrieve memory records.
That's a function call, right?
That you use to retrieve the records
and bring it into context for the agent.
Now the SDK or the AgentCore SDK,
when we create the memory config,
and we added it to the Strands Agent,
that's handling it all
that for us automatically.
But you can use something
called an event hook
where you can extract this
and design it however you want
and Strands Agent supports that.
- [Erik] Alright, let's
jump back to the demo.
So here, I asked it a question
to find the meal prep.
So I was able to take
those two MCP servers,
use the agents and come up with a list
of our daily meal breakdown.
So it said, I'm happy, a
weekly meal prep for you, Erik.
I'll design a balanced meal
with meals total of 1500 calories.
And it has each meal
breakdown for each day.
So I think it would be interesting,
you're probably thinking
like, how did it do this?
Let's look at the
observability real quick,
and we'll show you how it works.
So, Du'An.
- [Du'An] Yes.
- [Erik] Can we leave the
question just to the end
so we can show this observability?
- [Du'An] All right, I'll show that.
- [Erik] Yeah,
I think we're just running
a little bit outta time.
- [Du'An] 10 minutes.
Alright, so I'm gonna hop
in and show observability.
All right, so the first thing we wanna do
is open up AgentCore,
see if we can zoom in,
so we all can see this.
Now, inside of the console,
and you can get to a lot
of this from the terminal.
Like, if you are using the starter kit,
you can view a lot of the CloudWatch logs.
But a key thing, we'll
go into the runtime,
and once we're in here,
we'll go down to the agent
that is running and we have
our food tracker agent.
Notice that the versions,
so as you launch a new agent
or update the agent and
launch it into AgentCore,
it creates a new version.
And that's important to remember
because that version will become
the default version, right?
So the latest version goes to default.
So whenever you invoke the agent,
now you're invoking the latest version.
And so that's something
you have to keep in mind.
Now, once you're in here,
you see the endpoint for that agent,
you have the CloudWatch logs,
and the CloudWatch gen AI
observability for the agent.
First thing we'll do is go into the logs.
The thing I like about the logs
is that you can actually go in
and look at the log streams.
So that shows you if we go
into the latest log stream
with the inputs, with the outputs
that were actually happening
inside of the agent, right?
So if you're getting some type of mirrors,
some type of error, some
type of authentication issue,
or there's an issue with your code,
if you go into the log stream,
you can view all of that here, right?
Clearly defined line by line
what's happening in an agent,
you can see that, so you can
put your print statements.
If you use Lambda function
and you troubleshoot those,
you can pretty much do the
same thing with the runtime.
Now, the key thing that we all care
about is the gen AI observability.
And once we're in here,
this takes us into the
default agent, right?
The agent's default, the latest version.
And what you'll see when it
comes to gen AI observability,
you have the session.
Under the session, you have traces,
which is beginning to end, right?
So if you invoke, the
response is one trace.
Now, inside of a trace, you have spans.
That's every step that happens inside.
So if we go into the sessions,
we'll click the latest session
from when Erik just invoked
the agent, and then we'll
actually take a look at that.
- [Erik] It does take a few
moments to load the traces,
especially on the network we're on.
Sometimes refresh it there.
- [Du'An] Yeah, it takes a moment
for the gen AI observability to populate.
And so once we have that,
what we can actually do is go
into the agent and look at,
this is the recipe agent that's there.
We'll look at all sessions,
and we'll click on the latest session.
Notice we have three traces.
So that means he's invoked the
agent three different times.
So we'll go to the most recent one
for this particular agent.
And so here we have three different traces
and we can look at the
average trace latency,
which is something I could
have called out before,
but you can actually see if we go back
and I'll go back 'cause that's important.
But inside of here, when you
actually look at your agent,
you could look at the
observability for the agents,
the memory, the tools, the
gateways, and identity.
So what this shows you is
not just the information
about the agents, but
the runtime, the latency,
everything that you wanna know
about the invocation time,
the errors, the tokens,
you can see all of that
when it comes to the agent.
And so we'll go in here to
all sessions one more time.
We'll click on one trace.
- [Erik] I really like this detailed view
that it gives you here.
- [Du'An] And this is for
one of the MCP servers.
So you can see here we have the MCP server
and we just have one span inside of here.
So we'll have to go back and
find the actual agent session,
and we can determine that,
because it's gonna be a lot
more tokens if we look at that.
So if we come in here
and go to all sessions,
you can see the latency for this one.
So we know this actually took a long time,
so this had to be a
lot of things going on.
And there's only four different traces.
So this took about 44 seconds,
and there's four different invocations.
So what we could actually
do is narrow down, wow,
look at the latency on this
one, and there's 20 spans.
So that means there were
a lot of tool calls,
a lot of things happening from the time
that the agent was invoked to the result,
and the response from the actual model.
So we can go into this trace,
and once we're in this span,
notice that this is another MCP server.
But what we can actually do
is look at each span as we go
down and we can see, okay,
what's taking the most time?
All right, we get down here
and we see this invocation.
This took 53 seconds, right?
And we can see everything that happened
from the time we invoked to
the time that we finished.
We can see the inputs, the outputs,
and this is a summarized view over here
of all the spans that happened.
But we can see every event
that actually happened, right?
All of the telemetry is in here,
but if we come into the chat,
you can actually see, okay,
here's the system message,
here's the user message,
the assistant message, the tool calls,
and you can see all of these JSON inputs
and outputs from the model,
the agent and user prompts
that were passed in.
You can see all of that
along with the time,
the amount of tokens.
As you can see, input
tokens here, output tokens.
So if you're really trying to analyze
and get observability of your agents,
you can do that for each trace.
We got a question back there.
- [Erik] Okay, let's hold
the questions at the end.
Du'An, do you have anything more?
- [Du'An] I think it's good
point to go to questions.
- [Erik] Okay. Alright, well,
let's get a question in then.
We got a question? Okay, we got one.
- [Du'An] Yeah, he had
one in front and then-
- [Erik] I'm sorry. Yeah, go ahead.
You can go ahead now.
- [Attendee] Okay, my question
was when you were saying
that for the agent, if you
use the semantic search,
it's gonna avoid using too many tokens.
That's the part when you
are getting the memory
for the config and getting
from the long-term memory
and pass it to the agent
or it's a different thing?
- [Du'An] So when we talk
about using too many tokens,
there's a lot of variables in that, right?
What you'll have to do is actually look
at the observability.
And so what this will allow
you to do to look at each span
to see how many tokens were used, right?
So right now we're in the span
for the chat with the agent
and we can see exactly
how long this span took,
meaning the time we
invoked the actual model,
the input tokens, how many
tokens were passed in,
and how many tokens were output.
Now, what we could actually
do is go in here and look at,
okay, when it comes to the
tokens that were passed in,
well, we know the system prompt.
How many tokens did that take, right?
We can actually look at
that, the user message.
How many tokens did that take?
The tool calls, the tool messages,
how many tokens was that?
And we can actually analyze
and get very granular at that point.
That's what we can do in observability.
- [Attendee] Okay.
- [Erik] Alright. All right.
- [Du'An] We got one more in the back.
- [Erik] I could, let's, yeah,
we only got two minutes left.
- [Du'An] Okay.
- [Erik] So maybe we can,
let's switch it over to the,
then we can answer some questions,
submission over to the PowerPoint.
So I just wanted to say
if you need to contact us,
our email addresses are here.
We'd love to talk to you
guys. Thank you so much.