- And welcome to today's session.
And you know now agentic AI has emerged
as one of the most exciting topics
in today's gen AI landscape.
So as forward-thinking developers,
I know you are looking to go beyond
just understanding the series
or concepts or terminologies.
So you want to see the real scenarios
or real innovations in action
and then how to, maybe, you want to build
your own AI agents
applications from ground up.
So that's exactly what we
are here to deliver today.
I'm Haowen Huang, a
Senior Developer Advocate
at AWS based in Hong Kong.
And I'm honored to join
my colleague, Jacky Wu,
who is Senior Solutions
Architect, also from Hong Kong.
Yeah, take it, yeah.
- Thanks for joining the session.
Hope you enjoy it.
- So today, we will take you through
how to build agentic AI on AWS in practice
using Nova Act and Strands Agents.
So, we will bring you a
lot of demonstrations.
From my side,
I will put two hands-on
demonstrations of AI agents.
Yes, one is interactive
weather information agent
and the other is educational
video creation agent.
And Jacky will bring more multi-agents,
he will use in some
financial scenarios later.
And here is our agenda for today.
First, we will start
with some fundamentals,
like explore how AI agents concept
to ensure we're all on the same page.
Then next, I will provide a
hands-on demonstration showing
you how to build a real agent application
for Hong Kong weather information
using MCP and the Nova Act.
Then, we will dive into
real-world applications
by exploring how to build enterprise
agentic AI solutions from the ground up,
using open-source Strands Agents.
You know, open-source Strands Agents
is AWS' recently opened contribution
to the open-source communities.
Following up, Jacky will
bring some valuable experience
from the capital markets.
He will introduce you to four multi-agent
collaboration patterns and tools
with open source Strands Agents SDK.
And he will also
demonstrate these concepts
through two practical financial use cases.
And finally, we will wrap up
with a comprehensive overview
of AWS' complete agentic AI portfolio.
Let's begin by examining the future trend
of agentic AI first.
So, if we dive deep into the
evolution of generative AI,
you will see that it has
followed a clear progression,
so each phase brings new priorities
and challenges for business.
So, on the left, you'll see the low agency
and the more human oversight
which are rule-based
and require high human oversight.
So, on the right, we
see high agency systems
and can operate independently
and even make some strategic
decisions by themselves,
by the agent themselves.
But in reality,
actually we are still at
the very beginning stage
of the agentic AI.
So, reaching higher agency request,
not just about technologies,
but also maybe some
governance, maybe some trust,
and some organization readiness.
We will dip into that topic later.
So, although we are still
in the very early stage
of agentic AI that has a
version of future world
powered by AI agents.
I would like to recommend
this Sequoia Capital's
keynote address at AI Ascent
2025 in San Francisco,
which is also referenced here.
So, Sequoia Capital predicts
that future AI systems
will go beyond the current
tool-like attributes
and evolve into autonomously
operating intelligent agents.
So, these intelligent
agents will have capability
for reasoning, for planning,
for collaboration, and
high autonomous operation.
So the most striking aspect of
Sequoia Capital's prediction,
on the right is their vision
for the 2030s agent economy.
It will operate like a
global neural network,
composed of numerous agent operations
and forming a interconnected network,
as illustrated on the right.
So put simply, if in the future,
if the AI agent you designed is adopted
by the majority people,
for example, in Hong Kong,
you make enough money to buy
a house in Hong Kong, right?
And if the AI agents
you designed are adopted
by most people worldwide,
then congratulations,
you will have the excellent chance
to become a very rich man.
So, I think the right is the forecast
of Sequoia Capital for the 2030s.
So it's very important
because I think it'll make
everyone know what we should do,
make every developer know what
we should do in the future.
Okay, Sequoia Capital also have some bold
prediction in their keynote address.
The upcoming emergence of
the first one-person unicorn,
means a company will be created
and operated by a single individual
with a valuation of 1
billion U.S. dollars.
So this shift in labor structure
has given rise to entire
new organization models.
This means a business that
can be run by a single person
while he or she can do or perform
all the functional capabilities
in the scale of a complete startup.
So, additionally, if you
look close to the right
for the stochastic mindset,
which is my favorite here.
So the emerging world
of AI agents requires us
to adopt an entire
different way of thinking.
So, I know when we work
with large language models,
many developers, they
complain that the output
are not very accurate or fails to meet
our human being expectations, right?
So, when facing these frustrations,
I would encourage you to consider
a completely different perspective,
perhaps it's our way to connect
with large language models
or connect with AIs lead to adjustment.
So this is why in 2025,
forward-thinking AI
IDE like Kiro, K-I-R-O,
features crucial capabilities,
which is a spec-driven development.
So, this is another topic.
I'm not going to dive deep into it
because my time is limited, but, however,
I hope you understand this.
To succeed in the new era of agentic AI,
you must prepare mentally in areas
you may not well considered,
not only in the technology,
but also in some, maybe,
we'll call some changes
in the organizations
and future organization structure
and your mental frameworks as well.
Okay, so in 2025,
we see that much of the
foundational infrastructure
for the future world of agentic AI
is already under construction.
For example, communication protocols,
so during the development of internet,
the TCP-IP protocol laid the foundation
for network interconnections.
So, similarly, in the
emergence of the agentic AI.
AI agents also require interoperability,
both with their own tools
and also they want to connect
with other AI agents as well.
So some emergence such as MCP and A2A
are addressing these challenges.
So here, I am not going to
dive deep into MCP and A2A,
but what I want to focus is now AWS
is actively participating
in the Strands communities
for both MCP and A2A projects
to contribute Amazon's
decades of experience
in distributing systems and to enhance
these future protocols.
So this is the complete
AWS agentic AI portfolio
comprised of comprehensive architecture
with some supporting services.
So from the bottom to the top,
you will see these services are
organized into three layers,
infra layers, the AI the agent,
software layers and
the application layers.
And each layer contains more
specific service categories.
And today, we will focus on
the AI and agent development,
software and services.
And for the SDKs, for agents part,
Nova Act and Strands Agents.
And Jacky will dive deep into more detail
or more scenarios into these
SDKs for agents part as well.
Yes, we have discussed extensively
for the future of agentic AI.
So, next, I will showcase
practical agentic AI applications
that automatically retrieve
local weather information in Hong Kong.
But I think, since this,
maybe you just need to change the URL,
you can make these agentic AI applications
easy to use in your country as well.
So, here's a practical AI agent scenario
to demonstrate the local
weather application development
using the MCP protocol, Amazon Nova Act,
and the Hong Kong Observatory website.
Let's play the video first.
Yes.
Yeah, in this video demonstration,
we simply provided our agent
built with Amazon Nova Act
with a special website URL,
then we just directed
it to interact with it
using natural language English,
or you can use do it in
Spanish or Chinese as well,
such as what's the current
weather in Hong Kong?
So, next, we will observe that amazement
as the agent can begin to
function like a human being,
a web-scraping engineer.
So, it autonomously located
where the information
from the Hong Kong website
and saved a screenshot file
in my computer for verification.
Yes, the screenshot here.
So, if you are a web-scraping engineer,
this video might be somewhat shocking
because whether you embrace it or not,
the era of agentic AI has arrived.
So, you may want to
prepare for your future
and AWS services like the Nova Act
and later the Strands
Agents and the agent call.
Actually, we announced more
of the agent call features
in the keynote yesterday,
so may help you in the huge transition.
Okay, so you may want to know the detail
about how to implement the AI
agent using Amazon Nova Act.
It's straightforward.
So the left screenshot shows
the Nova Act forecast functions,
which guide the Amazon Nova Act
on which specific web pages to capture
and what actions to perform.
And notably, we directly
use natural language
to assign like the read and extract
the complete nine-days
weather forecast information
visible on this page.
And we provided the URL,
which is the Hong Kong Observatory website
with the starting page.
And the right screenshot demonstrates
a typical MCP call in the MCP decorator
and the process of running
Nova Act in a separate thread.
The function here is the same.
On the right, we just
run Nova Act forecast.
Yes, if you are interested
in the detail about how
we implement the hook,
the code repo is on the right side, yeah.
So, if you are curious
about the technical details
about how we implemented this AI agent,
you can read two technical blog post
we wrote specifically on this topic.
And the first part of the post
primarily introduces how to independently,
so just design the AI agent application
using Amazon Nova Act.
And the second part
demonstrates how to implement
an AI agent with MCP and Amazon Nova Act.
And if you want use some outside source,
you list maybe your own data.
So, you want to build them together
then you can refer to the part two
or to the second blog post.
You can scan the QR code on
the right to access detail.
Okay, so in the previous example,
we demonstrated how to
rapidly build an AI agent
using Nova Act.
However, I understand
many of the developers,
they won't stop there.
They have even greater ambitions, right?
Some developers in Hong Kong and China,
they told me they want to
build their own agentic AI
applications from scratch,
and they want to maintain
complete source code level control.
So, they want to control
every line of their code.
So, in such cases,
open-source Strands Agents
can help you to achieve this
goal that I will discuss later.
If you're like me and have spoken
with many pioneer
developers of agentic AI,
you will share my insight into
the numerous challenges here
when the developers want to build
their own custom agent at this moment.
So, on the input side, left,
we need connectors that enable agents
to interact with diverse
enterprise systems.
So that's where the tools and MCP come in,
so they orchestrate access to this input.
So, the agent isn't just
answering questions,
but actually executing workflows,
like maybe booking hotel, maybe
updating some information,
or maybe trigger some processes.
So, in the top sections, we
need another important component
for building customized
AI agent systems, memory,
including short-term memory
and long-term memory.
So, short-term memory allows the agent
to maintain context within a session.
And the long-term memory enables them
to learn and improve over time.
So on the right side, you have the brain,
the large language models,
but instead of treating
it as a standalone,
so sometimes you need to
extend it to be a reason,
to be a more complex frameworks
using like the React,
like the Reflexion and a chain of thought.
So, these techniques
allow the model to plan,
reflect on the reasoning step-by-step.
And the bottom section shows
we still need to consider
additional elements.
So because every agent needs a persona,
so like a set rules or
instructions that define the agent
is and how it should behave.
And this differentiates an HR agent
from maybe a DevOps agent or
maybe a custom support agent.
And Jacky will also discuss
some specific implementation
of this aspect in detail when you want
to do some multi-agent orchestration.
So finally, we need to
customize all the AI agents
to provide the
observabilities and guardrails
to keep the agent safe,
the budget, and aligned with our goals.
So based on all the custom
needs outlined here,
you may have already
realized that building
a truly functional AI agent
requires substantial work
and maybe potentially over 80%
or even 90% of the effort being unrelated
to your unique business
logic and the processes.
So, you may have questions.
So, how to make AI agent
development more efficient?
That is AWS provides
the framework for you.
Yeah, this is Strands Agents.
So, what is Strands Agents?
Strands Agents is the
Amazon's recent contribution
to the global open-source community.
It's the SDK that enables developers
to build AI agents with minimal code.
And the framework simplified development
by eliminating complex
agent orchestrations
and help us to leverage
state-of-art large language models
to handle planning, channel
sort, tool callings and others.
Next, let me show you how to rapidly build
a complex, real-world
agentic AI application
using the open-source Strands Agent.
Yeah, here's a demo.
So in the second demonstration,
I will showcase the creation
of a mathematic animation using Manim.
So, it's a present library
designed specifically
for high-quality mathematic visualization.
And the Strands Agents
will process a user prompt
and write a precise Manim script
and generate a polished
animation like this
to demonstrate the powerful capabilities
to combine with Strands Agents
and some Python libraries,
or some open-source projects together.
And let's dive deep
into a detailed analysis
of the core implementation
code for this demo.
It's very straightforward,
so I can show here.
So the initial code segment
imports the agent class
from the Strands module
and MCP client class
for the Strands tools, MCP,
to establish essential components
for a system to utilize agent
and the message control
protocols within the framework.
And, yes, and the following code segment
sets up a connection to a Manim MCP server
using input and output at
the transport mechanism.
Yes.
And next, the code establish a connection
for interaction with the Manim MCP server.
It chooses available
tools from the MCP server
and using the MCP client and
the agent with their tools
preparing for the upcoming task,
maybe like the chat loop or like that,
or if you want to design
for more other task.
Yeah.
Finally, it's very simple.
It's very important, but it's very simple
if you use Strands Agents.
The code use the agent to
process a natural language prompt
requesting Manim animation.
The prompt is asking for a visualization
of some specific cubic function graph,
functions from X = -3 to X = 3.
This video, let me play it first.
And this video demonstrate
a complete process
of building agentic AI applications
using Strands Agents SDK
to perform mathematic visualization.
So, in VS Studio, two
terminal windows are utilized.
The left one is runs MCP server,
which connect to the Manim MCP server,
while the STDIO transport
and the right terminal
runs MCP client programs,
which launches the window
generation chat interface.
And through this interface,
users can input your
natural language comment.
Like for example, create a Manim scene
that draw cubic functions
from maybe X ranges
in nine seconds.
And after submission,
the right terminal will
show the agent processing
the natural language request.
And interesting, yes.
When I develop this is,
you see that there is
detecting some issues,
some combination issues
in my local environment.
The agent intelligently
created a simplified version
to complete the task to demonstrate
its adaptive problem-solving capabilities.
And the agent already
successfully completed the task
and provided output summaries.
And the final MP4 video file generated
by the AI agent is here.
Yes.
So now, it's easy, very easy
to design educational videos now, right?
You just need to use some natural language
as an input and the agent
can help you with this.
Yeah, I want to introduce this
because I think it's the future.
The educational AI agent in the future.
It's very simple because it's only...
I designed this program
just maybe in 30 minutes.
So, maybe you can use
three days or one week
to make a real enterprise-level AI agent.
Yeah.
Okay, so this completes the whole process
of building an agentic
AI application for this.
So, if you are interested in this case,
you can scan the QR code here.
Left is to re-watch the video
and the right is to get to
access a complete demo code
for these examples.
And this concludes my
presentation for today,
and thank you all for listening.
Next, I will hand over and
the time over to Jacky.
Thank you.
- Thank you, Haowen.
So, I hope you enjoyed so far.
So, thanks, Haowen
introducing about Nova Act
and also about the Strands Agents.
So, first, I do a quick survey.
If you are developer,
raise your hands, please.
Okay, so how many of you use
the VS Code to write the code?
Okay, few of them. That's great.
So, how many of you have already written
the agent by yourself?
Okay, good, good. Still a few of them.
So, to my part, so I introduce myself.
So, this is Jacky.
So, I also come from Hong Kong,
and I am a Solutions Architect,
mainly servicing the
financial service industries.
And in the coming almost
25 or half an hour,
I will talk about
multi-agent collaborations.
As we are developer, right?
So, I'm also a developer.
So people knows nowadays,
you can have the monolithic
and you also have the
containerized microservices.
So, why multi-agent?
The concept is very similar.
So, for agent, you can let
lots of actions, tools,
you can let huge monolithic
agents, but why multi-agent?
First, specialization, right?
If you have a specialized agent,
so it'll work in the space for domains,
so it increase precision
and so that you can have
more precise answers.
And all combine those specialized agents,
you can achieve the superior outcome.
Scalability.
So, because you have those
agents and those sub-agents,
so during the work life, you
can add or remove the agents
without impacting the whole system.
So, this is how it can be scalable.
Maintainability.
So, just as a quick survey.
Most of us are developers here
so questions are very simple.
If you debug 100 lines of code,
and another debug 10,000 lines of code,
the difficulty is very,
very different, right?
So, with the small agent
it's easier to control,
to monitoring, to debug,
test, all these things.
Finally, about cost, right?
So, as AWS, even in the
yesterday, Matt Garman,
our CEO's keynotes, right?
Choice matters, right?
Because you have the typical model
has three different scenarios, right?
One is about specialization,
the reasoning capacity.
Two is about speed, how
fast can this bounce?
The third one is about cost, right?
How cost efficient it is.
So if you use the multi-agent,
which means for one specific agent,
you can match your task complexity
with the right model, right?
Can be fast, can be very performance,
can be very cost efficient.
In short, I will use the single agent
for specialized, skilled solo work,
while the multi-agent system
is like a well-coordinated team.
As I work in hedge fund before
the monolithic agents is like a trader,
like manage a portfolio all by himself.
But multi-agent is like a team, right?
You can have the analyst
do the market research,
you can have the quants
doing the modeling,
you can have choice, extra choice,
you can have risk manager
manage portfolio risk,
you can have IT maintain the
underlying infrastructure.
So when they can combine together,
they can achieve the superior performance.
But the condition here is
they can work together, right?
So how can they work together?
The patterns.
So Strands Agents can support
multi-agent collaboration patterns, right?
Agents as tools, Swarm, graph, workflow.
And in the coming session,
I will talk about those
patterns one-by-one
and first I will introduce what they are
and then I will use real-life examples
to showcase how the pattern can help you.
Let's start with agent as tools.
For the agent as tools,
you always have a so-called
orchestrator agents.
So which will receive
the user requirements,
understand the intent,
and then it'll call the specialized agent
to perform the specific task.
Take this as example.
Here, we have the orchestrator agents.
When the user sends the requirements
he want to travel a lot, right?
So for example, if I
travel to Las Vegas...
By the way, this is my first time here.
I'm very honored to share
this session with you.
So first the orchestrator agent
will receive the requirements
and then pass to the
research agents, it'll search
where you can play like Antelope Canyon,
all these things and then it'll go pass
to the product recommendation assistant.
So which means the input
of the orchestrator agents
will make it as...
Sorry. The output of research assistant,
the orchestrator agent
will make that input
to the next agent.
Okay, that's the theory.
Now, I will make a real-life example.
In the quantitative hedge fund nowadays,
so the quantitative
methodology is very important,
especially for those quant researchers.
They need to verify their
trading idea very fast.
So when they fail fast,
that means they can find the
right trading strategy faster.
So, for example, they say,
" Is the moving average
crossover a good trading strategy?"
They may have different ideas, right?
So how the agentic AI help them?
I come from Hong Kong and I make this demo
with my Hong Kong colleague Charlie Chu.
Yeah. So here is the
sample input you can input,
like the stock that you are
interested in like the Amazon,
okay, backtesting window,
which means you use historical market data
to verify your ideas and
then you can get some metrics
like the profit and the loss,
like the stop ratio
so which means how much risk you take
and how much profit you get.
And then you can also get a buy condition
and sell condition when
you want to buy the stock
or when you wanna sell the stock.
And then you can run the backtest.
And in our sample it will
give the backtest results
how much you make and as well
it will give you suggestions
for your trading strategies,
whether it's good or not,
how to improve the trading strategy,
what's the risk behind and any alert.
So that's sample input output
so you may understand what's
behind this stuff, right?
I think developers or architects,
you like the architecture diagrams.
So here we got the
orchestration agents here
which will call different
tools and agents.
So here we've got two tools,
which is market data tools,
another one is backtest tools.
And we also got two agents here.
So strategy generation agents
and results summary agents.
And the orchestrator agents,
the quantum research agents
is orchestrator agents
will call the sub-agents.
In the coming slides,
I will focus the three components here.
So first I will show you how
to use agent called Gateway
to build the tools and then
it can be used in the agents.
And second one I will show
you the AgentCore Runtime,
how to host the strategy generation agents
and make the agent as a tool
which will be used by the
quant research agents.
Let's start with the tools.
Amazon SageMaker AgentCore Gateway,
it provides an easy and secure way
for developers to build tools for agents.
So you can capture the
API or Lambda functions
for existing services
into MCP compatible tools.
Here, I will use the Lambda function
as a backend Gateway target.
So I store the historical
market data in the S3 table
and then this is the function
I will define the catalog.
After I lock in the catalog,
I can start to search the market data
I will use in the Gateway.
After I define the Lambda function,
I will make the Lambda function
as the target of the Gateway.
I will create a Gateway first.
Okay, it's very simple with
AgentCore starter toolkits.
So AgentCore Gateway create Gateway,
you give the name and then in the console
you will find the agent,
the gateway is created.
After the gateway is created,
you will also notice that
inbound identity here,
which is Cognito by default.
So that when your agents orchestrator
tries to call this tool,
you need to authenticate
so you can get a secure environment.
And then as a tool, the
agents will always know
you should define a clear input and output
of the Lambda functions.
That's why here I say the
name is get_market_data, okay?
And then in future when
the quant research agent
tries to call this tool,
it will trigger the tool get_market_data
and you also get the
input parameters here.
Now I have the gateway ready there.
So I will make the gateway a tool
to the quant research agents.
First, Haowen just
mentioned like you can call
the tool later to make the tool
and then you can give the
okay to define what it is,
what's the arguments, what's returned.
And then you mentioned, the
gateway will use Cognito
by default to do the authentication.
And then I will, after the
Cognito authentication,
I will call the Gateway
using the HTTPS client
and then I am able to get
historical market data
to do my backtesting.
That's about Gateway.
After we define the market data tools
and then we will define
the strategy agents.
And for our agents we will
deploy to AgentCore Runtime.
So AgentCore Runtime provides
a secure and fast way
and specialized tools to host your agents.
Here, I define the
strategy from the Strands,
I import agent and then I
define the instructions,
so it's a trading strategy code generator,
I use the backtrader framework,
So please generate the code for me, okay?
Just give me the Python code
because this code will be executed later.
And then I define, give the name,
give the system prompt,
give the model to use.
And by the way,
you can notice that in the
strategy generation agent,
I use the Claude Sonnet
coding capacity, right?
And later you will find
for another agents I use Nova model,
which is good in summarization.
So this is also the benefits
I just talked at the beginning, right?
You can use different language models
for different sub-agents.
And once I have it,
how do I deploy the agent to the runtime?
So first I will form the Bedrock agent,
import the Bedrock AgentCore apps.
So after import apps,
what you need is you give
the app the entry points.
So to specify once the agent is triggered,
which way it will be triggered
and then I have to run, okay?
By default it'll listen to port 8080.
And once the code is ready
I will deploy it to AgentCore Runtime.
It's quite simple actually, right?
For the AgentCore Runtime you
can just use agentcore config
to specify the files and also
the requirement files, right?
You can have the dependents,
lots of dependents,
so that AgentCore Runtime
will install for you
and build a container.
And then AgentCore launch.
So after AgentCore launch,
you will get the Runtime
agents in your console
and then you can also check the status,
AgentCore status to check it.
So this is how quickly you can deploy
through the AgentCore, right?
So someone will ask you,
okay, I do not use Python,
I use Java, for example, right?
You can build your own container, right?
So just to comply to the
AgentCore Runtime protocol,
you can bring your own container
to deploy to the AgentCore Runtime.
And after that I will make the
agent as a tool, similarly.
So I use the Strands as tool generator
and then generate trading strategies
and I specify the arguments.
So please note here the input,
I'm expecting a JSON file.
So you see the name, the buy
condition, sell condition,
which I just mentioned at
the very beginning, right?
So this is the input.
And then here I use the AgentCore Runtime
to invoke the AgentCore Runtime.
So this is how I make the agent as tools.
So after you define the two tools,
market data tool, you define
the strategy generation agents,
you define Runtime tools,
you define the result summary agents
that come to the quant research agent,
which is the orchestrator agent.
It's quite simple.
From Strands, I will import agents,
you give the six prompts, right?
So for a quant trading strategist,
you will like, okay, get
historical market data,
generate the strategy,
run the Strands code,
analyze the results.
So basically that's the prompts means.
I will not focus on the tools
here because this pattern,
remember is the agent as a tool.
So here I can see I've got the four tools,
fetch the market data, generate strategy,
run backtest, and create result summaries.
So, if the there are something
wrong here, the orchestrator,
the quant research agents will
relearn the generated code.
So let's see a quick demo.
So if you look at this,
you will find that I use the
Kiro's CLI to run the command.
So it's perfect for my debugging
because when you write, Kiro
already knows the output
and then it will help
you debug much faster.
Okay. I ask the Kiro CLI to
run the quant agent for me.
And here you will use
the tool execute_bash.
And then you here you
can say the JSON file.
So I use, okay, 10-day period
simple moving average close over 30 day
simple moving average.
First, the strategy will try
to go to the first tools,
which is generate trading strategies.
And here you can see first the agent
will make the JSON input, right?
Remember, I define the
input as a JSON file.
So you can see it's JSON format
and then it perfectly generated
the crossover strategy for me.
So in the Python file you
can see how it process,
how it generate the trading signals.
Okay, it's finished, six seconds.
After I generate the code,
the agent call the
fetch_market_data via the Gateway.
And here you can see the HTTP
request to the Gateway here.
So the symbol is Amazon,
which I defined at the
very beginning and then,
okay, because I defined one year,
so you can see around
200 data points retrieved
from the Gateway.
And the third step it will run
the actual backtest itself.
You can see here you can get a sample data
that I will use in the backtest.
And then because I use
the backtrade framework,
so Cerebro engine is the core component
about backtrade framework.
And then here you can also say I need
to feed the market data into Cerebro
so that you know the market data
and then it will try to
backtest the strategy.
And output, here you can see,
okay, that's the initial value
and then, okay, what's the profit you get
and what's the total return?
And finally, okay, it will try
to create the result summary, okay?
And what it is and how
it needs to be improved.
So here also use AgentCore memory here.
So because I saved the backtest result
in the AgentCore memory
and in the third step,
I will just fetch it from the memory.
So this is how you process it.
And here, for different quants
they may have different intention.
Like here I give the summary,
I give the recommendations,
I give the alerts
and also the key concerns,
how I can improve my trading strategies.
So if you are interested,
so you can scan the live demo here,
to create your own strategy.
Okay, this just for information,
this does not constitute
any investment advice, okay?
So please consult with a
qualified financial analyst.
Okay.
So let's talk about agent as tools.
Now the second one I
want to discuss is Swarm.
The Swarm actually is
fundamental different patterns.
In the agents tool, you can
see the orchestrator agents,
while in the Swarm pattern
there's no single boss, okay?
The agents communicate with each other
and collaborate dynamically
to solve the problem.
The Swarm maintains a shared context
so that all agents can access.
So it's about who is in the Swarm system,
what other agents input and output,
what historical interactions.
Let's use this one example, right?
You got the research
agent, creative agent,
critical agents, some large agents.
So I want to write a blog, all the things.
So here, first I define
the four different agents here, right?
So one to do the research
and one is to create something.
And then the third one is how to challenge
what you already created.
And finally, I will do the summarize
to give the final results.
And then from the shared multi-agents,
I import Swarm class,
and the Swarm class I
give the four agents.
And that defines the max handoff,
max interactions so that
it won't run infinitely.
And also, I do not want the two agents
can make each other the
ping pong, that loop.
So I have the repetitive
handoff detection window
and also the repetitive
handoff unique agents,
which means in the last agent handoff,
at least three agents should be involved.
So let's see how it works.
Yeah, okay, so the task is
please create a blog post,
explain it agentic AI,
and then create summary
for social media blog.
So first it will create a blog
and then a social media post.
Let's see how it works.
First, once the Swarm
receives the request,
it will first call the research agent
because it knows I need to find
what information I can gather, right?
So this a fact, you need research agent.
After research agent found the stuff
and then it will try to call
the creative agent, right?
Because it needs to
create an engaging blog
and it knows, okay, after I create a blog,
I will handoff to the summarizer agent
to create the social media post.
And the interesting happens here.
In the summarize agent,
it'll try to create a post.
However, it found that in
order to create a summary,
I see the general
structure of the blog post
from the creative agent's descriptions,
but I need more details to create
an effective social media summary.
So this is the reasoning
from the summarize agent.
In this way, it won't
hand over to the stuff,
it will hand over back
to the creative agent
so that it will feel the content.
And now the creative agent received it,
it will say, okay, now let me create
a comprehensive blog post and then handoff
to the summarize agent again.
And finally, the summarize agent is able
to create the blog and also the post.
And here I can see, okay, there
are total five interactions.
And also for the Strands Agent framework,
we also have the tools, right?
So from Strands tools I
can import a Swarm tool,
and when I define the agents,
I have import a tool as a Swarm
and then in the results,
use three agents to
analyze or to do the things
and this agent will spin off
three agents to do the task.
So this is use Swarm as a tool.
Now I discuss about agent as a tool,
Swarm patterns, the third one
I will discuss about graph.
In graph pattern, you can
define the agent relationship
as a graph network.
So each agent is a node
and the edge between them
define the relationship,
define the information flow,
how they can communicate with each other.
So the key advantage of the graph pattern
is predictability and
also the control, right?
In this graph, for example,
the economic department
can only communicate
with the market research
and the financial analyst,
and it's not allowed to
communicate with social analyst
or technical analyst.
So this is how you have the predictability
and full control about information flow.
I would like to use example
the agentic fund manager,
developed by our Korean
colleague, Kang Wan Lee, okay?
So Kang Wan develop this
agentic AI fund manager here.
So maybe it's so complicated,
I will use two specific agents here
to demonstrate the graph here.
So first, it'll about
the portfolio architect
and then about fund manager.
So similarly, always I
define agent first, okay?
So this one I will define
how it'll construct the portfolio
to fulfill the customer requirements.
So here you can get a
prompt, define agents,
I know you should be very
familiar with this now.
And then in the graph we
have the nodes, right?
So I will define the portfolio nodes
which will trigger each other
to deploy AgentCore, right?
So it will call the agent with streaming.
And finally, let's talk about
the fund manager itself.
I use this example to
showcase Strands Agents SDK,
it can work with very generic,
other open source or
popular agentic frameworks.
So here you can see I
use the Strands Agent
to work with LangGraph, right?
I know you work with LangChain
and all the other popular frameworks,
for this one, I use a LangChain here
and you can define from LangGraph,
I import the StateGraph,
and the StateGraph, I
define the workflow here.
So I add the nodes of financial,
add nodes of the
portfolio, which I define.
I also add nodes of the risk.
And then after I add
nodes, add the edge, okay?
So from the financial to the portfolio,
from the portfolio to risk,
and the risk is the end node.
So this is how I use the graph
to define the nodes and then the edge,
so you can have a full control.
So if you are interested,
you can have the demo
and also the code repo,
developed by Kang Wan Lee.
Okay, so agent as tool, Swarm, graph,
the last one is workflow.
As a workflow, it's quite
straightforward for us, right?
You can have a very well-defined
sequence of patterns.
Here you can say, okay, I
have the research agents
and then analysis agent, and
then finally the report agent.
So here you can say,
when I define from Strands
tools, I import workflow.
And in the workflow I
define several tasks.
And in the task I define
the dependency here.
So for example, the task ID trend analysis
will depend on the data extraction.
And then the task report generation
will depend on the trend analysis.
So this is how you define the workflow.
You can also have the priority here
so that if you have multiple sub-agents
they can learn parallel and the priority
will determine which runs first.
So we talk about those four
different patterns, right?
So agents as a tool and all the fourth
in this coming five minutes.
So I will give some simple use cases
so that you can apply in your own company
after you leave Las Vegas.
First, agents as tools.
So, for example, customer service chatbot
can be a good example, right?
So when you receive the customer request,
the orchestrator agent can call
your technical account manager,
can call your bidding agents,
can call your summarize agents
and then provide output to your customers.
And then the Swarm patterns, right?
For the Swarm patterns,
so those individual agents
interact locally and then produce complex,
emergent behavior without
centralized control.
So here, for example,
for the multidisciplinary
incident response,
If you have any instance,
you may have different problems, right?
First, you may think it's
like networking issue, right?
And then you pass to network agent
and then the network
agents will check itself
and no, it's not my problem.
It can be the database problem.
And then they pass to the database agents
and the database agent will
check and then solve it, right?
So here you can see those agents,
they dynamically
communicate with each other.
And graph, as I just mentioned,
graph enables complex communication
while maintaining the
well-controlled information flow.
You can define which agent can communicate
with which agent, so
like the data validation
with error pass, right?
So we can control, okay,
first you will have an agent
to determine, okay, which has a problem,
whether there is no errors
and then is passed to different agents.
One can be the data
validation without error.
Another can be the data
agent with error pass, right?
So this is how you clearly
define the network graph, right?
And finally, it's about
the workflow, right?
So the workflow is perfect match.
I mean, if you have a complex
and repeatable process
and you want to encapsulate in a single,
reliable and useful tools, right?
And so, for example, for the
automated data pipelines...
We do have data engineers here?
So you have the data extraction,
you have the ETL, right?
You will do the data transform, right?
And then you will load data
into your data warehouse
or all the things and
then build a pipeline.
So this a perfect match for the workflow.
So the four patterns
about the Strands Agents
that you can leverage.
And now let's quickly
recap what we discussed.
So as Haowen just introduced
about AWS agentic AI portfolio,
I believe you see this diagram
lots of times during our event.
So again, so I would like to welcome you
to re:Invent and hope
you enjoyed the session.
So today we focus on Nova
Acts and the Strands Agents.
And, also we do a quick demo here, right?
So we demo the weather AI application,
the Manim video generation,
and also I and my Hong Kong
colleague, Charlie Chu,
developed agentic backtesting,
and my Korean colleague, Kwang Wan Lee,
developed the agent AI fund manager.
So please feel free to take a picture here
and later you can check the code repo,
check the demo itself.
And finally, we would like
to have your feedback here.
So please open your app
and give us your feedback,
and your feedback is
important for us to improve.
And also, I hope you enjoyed
the last of the event.
Thanks for coming and I thank
you for coming to our session.
Have a great day.
(audience applauding)